<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by Alex Mantzaris (Firaxis Games) -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - Original game objects that are renamed -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
<!-- +++ Asatru +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Religion Details -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_ASATRU</Tag>
		<English>Asatru</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_ASATRU_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Asatruism</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_ASATRU_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Germanic neopaganism, also known as Heathenry, Ásatrú, Odinism, Forn Siðr, Wotanism, Theodism, and other names, is the contemporary revival of historical polytheistic Germanic paganism.[2] Dedicated to the ancient gods and goddesses of the North, the focus of Germanic neopagans varies considerably, from strictly historical polytheistic reconstructionism to syncretist (eclectic), Jungian, occult or mysticist approaches. Germanic neopagan organizations cover a wide spectrum of belief and ideals.[PARAGRAPH:2]Much of Germanic Neopaganism's origins are in 19th century romanticism, as the aboriginal cultures of Northern Europe came to be glorified. In the early 20th century, organised groups emerged in Germany and Austria. In the 1970s, new Germanic Neopagan organisations grew up in Europe and North America, although a broad division in the movement emerged between the folkish movement, who saw it as the indigenous religion of the Nordic peoples, and the universalist movement, who opposed strictly racialist interpretations. As present, established Germanic Pagan communities exist in Europe, North America, South America, and Australasia. A few adherents can even be found in South Africa.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Temple -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_TEMPLE</Tag>
		<English>Asatru Temple</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In Civilization IV, a temple is defined as a building where the faithful come to worship. Christians call their temples "churches," while Muslims call theirs "mosques," and Jews call theirs, simply, "temples." Temples are far more common than cathedrals, but much less large and ornate. Even the smallest village can possess a temple.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Dans Civilization IV, un petit lieu de culte est défini comme un édifice dans lequel les fidèles viennent pratiquer leur religion : "églises" pour les chrétiens, "petites mosquées" pour les musulmans et "petites synagogues" pour les juifs. Ces petits lieux de culte sont bien plus courants que les grands lieux de culte mais sont de taille plus réduite et sont bien moins richement ornés. Même le village le plus petit peut posséder un petit lieu de culte.</French>
		<German>[TAB]In Civilization IV sind Tempel Gebäude, in denen Gläubige beten. Christen nennen ihre Tempel "Kirchen", Moslems "Moscheen". Es gibt deutlich mehr Tempel als Kathedralen. Allerdings sind sie wesentlich kleiner und schlichter. Selbst das kleinste Dorf kann einen Tempel besitzen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]In Civilization IV, il tempio è un edificio all'interno del quale i fedeli si recano a pregare. I Cristiani chiamano i loro templi "chiese", i Musulmani "moschee", gli Ebrei semplicemente "templi". I templi sono più comuni delle cattedrali, ma sono più piccoli e poco fastosi. Anche il villaggio più piccolo ospita un tempio.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]En Civilization IV, un templo se define como un lugar al que los fieles acuden a venerar. Los cristianos llaman a sus templos "iglesias", mientras que para los musulmanes son "mezquitas" y para los judíos, sencillamente, "templos". Son mucho más comunes que las catedrales, pero también mucho más pequeños y humildes. Hasta la más pequeña aldea puede poseer uno.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_TEMPLE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Temples[COLOR_REVERT] increase a city's happiness and culture. They are especially useful for expanding your civilization's borders during the early game.</English>
		<French>Les [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]petites synagogues[COLOR_REVERT] améliorent le bonheur et la culture des villes. Elles sont notamment utiles pour agrandir vos frontières culturelles au début du jeu.</French>
		<German>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Tempel[COLOR_REVERT] steigern die Zufriedenheit und Kultur einer Stadt. Sie eignen sich hervorragend, um Ihre Zivilisation bereits in der Frühphase des Spiels zu vergrößern.</German>
		<Italian>I [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]templi[COLOR_REVERT] aumentano la felicità e la cultura della città. Sono particolarmente indicati per espandere i confini della tua civiltà durante le fasi iniziali della partita.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Los [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Templos[COLOR_REVERT] aumentan la felicidad y cultura de la ciudad. Son especialmente útiles para expandir las fronteras de la civilización al principio de la partida.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Cathedral -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
		<English>Asatru Cathedral</English>
		<French>Cathédrale Asatru</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In Civilization IV, a cathedral is defined as an especially large and ornate religious building where the faithful worship. Only the most prosperous cities can afford to create cathedrals, as they require huge amounts of raw material and years of dedicated labor by skilled craftsmen. For example, the Notre Dame Cathedral in Paris, France, took over two centuries to complete.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Dans Civilization IV, un grand lieu de culte est défini comme un édifice religieux particulièrement grand et richement orné dans lequel les fidèles pratiquent leur religion : "cathédrales" pour les chrétiens, "mosquées" pour les musulmans et "synagogues" pour les juifs. Seules les villes les plus prospères ont les moyens de construire de tels édifices. En effet, ils nécessitent d'énormes quantités de matériaux bruts et des artisans spécialisés doivent y consacrer des années de travail. Ainsi, il a fallu plus de deux siècles pour terminer la cathédrale Notre-Dame à Paris.</French>
		<German>[TAB]In Civilization IV sind Kathedralen große und prächtige Gotteshäuser, in denen Gläubige beten. Nur die reichsten aller Städte können sich den Bau einer Kathedrale leisten, da hierfür große Mengen an Baumaterial und die jahrelange Arbeit erfahrener Handwerker erforderlich sind. Die Kathedrale von Notre Dame in Paris wurde beispielsweise erst nach 200-jähriger Bauzeit fertig gestellt.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]In Civilization IV, viene definito cattedrale un edificio religioso particolarmente grande e sfarzoso adibito a luogo di culto per i fedeli. Solamente le città più prosperose possono permettersi l'edificazione di cattedrali poiché sono necessari un'enorme quantità di materiali e operai esperti. Per esempio, per completare la cattedrale di Notre-Dame de Paris, in Francia, ci sono voluti più di due secoli.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]En Civilization IV, una catedral se define como un edificio religioso especialmente grande y ornamentado en el que se reúnen los fieles para celebrar sus ritos. Solo las ciudades más grandes pueden permitirse el lujo de crear catedrales, puesto que requieren enormes cantidades de materias primas y años de dedicación por parte de trabajadores especializados. Por ejemplo, la catedral de Notre Dame, Francia, tardó dos siglos en completarse.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_CATHEDRAL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Asatru Cathedral[COLOR_REVERT]) greatly increases a city's cultural output. It makes a city's citizens happy (if [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Shinto[COLOR_REVERT] is the state religion).</English>
		<German>Der [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Asatru Kathedrale[COLOR_REVERT]) erhöht den kulturellen Ausstoß einer Stadt deutlich. Ist [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Shinto[COLOR_REVERT] in einer Stadt Staatsreligion, steigt die Zufriedenheit der Bevölkerung.</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Monastry -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_MONASTERY</Tag>
		<English>Asatru Monastery</English>
		<French>Monastère Asatru</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A monastery is a building where monks can retreat from the world and concentrate upon the divine. Usually a monastery will have strict rules of conduct to protect its unworldly members from temptation. In some monasteries, the monks are totally silent; in others no visitors are allowed inside. Monasteries usually have many daily rituals and religious services. [PARAGRAPH:1] Throughout the ages monasteries have often been centers of learning. In remote areas the monks may be the only literate people for miles around. Monks have often been employed as scribes, copying out the words of their religion's sacred scripture. Monasteries frequently have extensive libraries, holding religious, scientific, medical and philosophical texts.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Un monastère est un édifice dans lequel les moines peuvent se retirer du monde et se concentrer sur le divin. Généralement, les règles de conduite y sont strictes afin de protéger ses membres, détachés du monde, de la tentation. Dans certains monastères, les moines sont totalement silencieux ; dans d'autres, les visiteurs ne sont pas autorisés à pénétrer dans leur enceinte. Les monastères ont généralement de nombreux rituels et services religieux quotidiens. [PARAGRAPH:1]A travers les siècles, les monastères ont souvent été des centres d'érudition. Dans les zones retirées, les moines étaient parfois les seules personnes sachant lire et écrire à des kilomètres à la ronde. Ils ont souvent servi de scribes, recopiant les textes sacrés de leur religion. Les monastères ont généralement de grandes bibliothèques possédant des textes religieux, scientifiques, médicaux et philosophiques.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Klöster sind Gebäude, in die sich Mönche zurückziehen, um sich auf Gott zu konzentrieren. In Klöstern gelten strenge Verhaltensregeln, die die Mönche vor Versuchungen bewahren sollen. In einigen Klöstern herrscht ein strenges Redeverbot, in anderen sind keine Besucher gestattet. Die Mönche selbst gehen täglich ihren religiösen Pflichten nach. [PARAGRAPH:1] In der Vergangenheit waren Klöster stets auch Zentren des Wissens. In abgelegenen Gegenden waren die Mönche oft die einzigen gebildeten Menschen, die als Schreiber ihre religiösen Schriften kopierten. Klöster haben nicht selten Bibliotheken, in denen unzählige religiöse, wissenschaftliche, medizinische und philosophische Texte aufbewahrt werden.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il monastero è un edificio nel quale i monaci possono ritirarsi dal mondo e concentrarsi sul Divino. In genere, nel monastero vige un regolamento ferreo per proteggere i membri della comunità dalle tentazioni. In alcuni monasteri, i monaci erano completamente silenziosi e non erano permesse visite dall'esterno per non interrompere i rituali quotidiani e le cerimonie religiose. [PARAGRAPH:1] Nel corso dei secoli, i monasteri sono stati spesso centro di insegnamento: in alcune zone, i monaci erano sovente gli unici in grado di leggere e scrivere nel giro di diversi chilometri. Da sempre, i monaci sono stati utilizzati come scribi per copiare le parole sacre della propria religione; i monasteri ospitavano spesso delle biblioteche che contenevano testi religiosi, scientifici, medici e filosofici.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Un monasterio es un edificio en el que los monjes pueden retirarse del mundo para concentrarse en los asuntos de la divinidad. Normalmente tienen estrictas reglas de comportamiento para proteger a sus miembros de la tentación. En algunos monasterios, los monjes guardan un silencio total, mientras que en otros no se permite el acceso a los visitantes. Lo habitual es que sus miembros tengan que celebrar a diario muchos rituales y servicios religiosos. [PARAGRAPH:1] A lo largo de la historia, los monasterios han sido muchas veces centros de estudio. En las regiones remotas, los monjes podían ser las únicas personas letradas en muchos kilómetros a la redonda. A menudo han sido empleados como escribas, y se han dedicado a copiar los textos sagrados de su religión. Normalmente cuentan con grandes bibliotecas, que contienen textos religiosos, científicos, médicos y filosóficos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_MONASTERY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Monasteries[COLOR_REVERT] allow you to create [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Missionaries[COLOR_REVERT], who can spread the faith in other cities. They also provide culture and a slight boost to research.</English>
		<French>Les [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]monastères[COLOR_REVERT] permettent de former des [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]missionnaires[COLOR_REVERT] qui peuvent propager la foi dans les autres villes. Ils améliorent aussi la culture d'une ville et accélèrent légèrement sa recherche.</French>
		<German>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Klöster[COLOR_REVERT] ermöglichen die Ausbildung von [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Missionaren[COLOR_REVERT]. Diese verkünden in anderen Städten Ihren Glauben, steigern den kulturellen Wert und beschleunigen die Forschung.</German>
		<Italian>I [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]monasteri[COLOR_REVERT] permettono la realizzazione dei [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]missionari[COLOR_REVERT], in grado di diffondere la fede in altre città. Inoltre, forniscono cultura e un piccolo aumento di ricerca.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Los [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Monasterios[COLOR_REVERT] permiten crear [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Misioneros[COLOR_REVERT], que pueden propagar la fe por otras ciudades. También proporcionan cultura y un cierto empuje a la investigación.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Shrine (Odin's Sanctuary) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Asatru Shrine (Odin's Sanctuary)</English>
		<French>Le Sanctuaire d'Odin</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Odin is considered the chief god in Norse paganism. His name is related to óðr, meaning "fury, excitation", besides "mind", or "poetry". His role, like many of the Norse gods, is complex. He is associated with wisdom, war, battle, and death, and also magic, poetry, prophecy, victory, and the hunt.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_SHRINE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]not yet available</English>
		<German>[TABnot yet available</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Thor's Worship Altar -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_THOR_WORSHIP_ALTAR</Tag>
		<English>Asatru Thor's Worship Altar</English>
		<French>Autel de Thor</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_THOR_WORSHIP_ALTAR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Thor is the god of thunder in Norse paganism,. Most surviving stories relating to Germanic mythology either mention Thor or center on Thor's exploits. Thor was a much revered god of the ancient Germanic peoples from at least the earliest surviving written accounts of the indigenous Germanic tribes to over a thousand years later in the late Viking Age. Thor was appealed to for protection on numerous objects found from various Germanic tribes. Miniature replicas of Mjolnir, the weapon of Thor, became a defiant symbol of Norse paganism during the Christianization of Scandinavia. </English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_THOR_WORSHIP_ALTAR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Thor's Altar provides melee units with the Mjolnir promotion[COLOR_REVERT] </English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Wonder (Freya Sanctuary) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_WONDER_FREYA_SANCTUARY</Tag>
		<English>Asatru Wonder (Freya Sanctuary)</English>
		<French>Sanctuaire de Freya</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_WONDER_FREYA_SANCTUARY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Freya is portrayed as a goddess of love, war, and fertility. Blonde, blue-eyed, and beautiful, Freyja is described as the fairest of all goddesses, and people prayed to her for happiness in love. She was also called on to assist childbirths and prayed to for good seasons. </English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ASATRU_WONDER_FREYA_SANCTUARY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Construct [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Freya Sanctuary[COLOR_REVERT] to increase your global population</English>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Buddhism +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Cathedral (Stupa) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BUDDHIST_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
		<English>Buddhist Cathedral (Stupa)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Stupa bouddhiste</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Buddhistische Stupa</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Stupa Buddista:Stupa Buddisti</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Stupa budista:Stupas budistas</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Shrine (The Mahabodhi) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BUDDHIST_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Buddhist Shrine (The Mahabodhi)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Mahabodhi</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Mahabodhi</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Il Mahabodhi</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Mahabodhi</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Christianity +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Shrine (The Church of the Nativity) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHRISTIAN_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Christian Shrine (The Church of the Nativity)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Basilique de la Nativit&#233;</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Geburtskirche</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>La Chiesa della Nativit&#224;</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Iglesia de la Natividad</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Confucianism +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Cathedral (Academy) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONFUCIAN_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
		<English>Confucian Cathedral (Academy)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Acad&#233;mie confucianiste</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Konfuzianische Akademie</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Accademia Confuciana:Accademie Confuciane</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Academia confuciana:Academias confucianas</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Shrine (The Kong Miao) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONFUCIAN_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Confucian Shrine (The Kong Miao)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Kong Miao</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Kong Miao</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Il Kong Miao</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Kong Miao</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Hellenism +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Religion Details -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_HELLENISM</Tag>
		<English>Hellenism</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Hell&#233;nisme</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Hellenismus</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Ellenismo</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Helenismo</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_HELLENISM_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Hellenistic</English>
		<French>Helléniste</French>
		<German>Hellenistisch</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_HELLENISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Hellenic religion, also referred to as Greek mythology, comprises an enormous body of stories about gods, goddesses, and heroes. These stories date back many centuries, preserved in pre-literate Greece through oral tradition. The Hellenic religion was polytheistic in nature, with innumerable local nature deities in addition to the major Olympian gods and goddesses. The Greek gods were human in form but possessed supernatural powers; they were born from other gods but never aged, they were immortal, could travel enormous distances instantly, speak through humans with or without their knowledge, etc. Some gods were the personified aspects of natural forces (for example, Helios was literally the god of the sun) while others had complex personalities and multiple functions associated with them (Apollo is probably the best example). [PARAGRAPH:1]The gods and goddesses were all related to one another as part of one large family, but there were clear generations of gods, and their interactions with each other were sometimes violent. For example, the Olympian gods had reached their place of dominance by casting out an earlier generation of gods and goddesses known as the Titans. This may be a mythical reflection of the struggle between the Greeks and the earlier culture that they displaced when arriving in the Peloponnesus around roughly 1000 BC. [PARAGRAPH:1]In addition to stories about gods, the Hellenic religion was also full of great sagas about the deeds of heroes, many of whom possessed a divine parent. Stories abound about figures such as Heracles, Perseus, Jason, and the characters of the Iliad. These humans frequently interacted with gods and even bested them at times. Many of the heroes were held in great esteem by the Greeks, especially "noble" characters such as Achilles. [PARAGRAPH:1]Although some of the well-educated Greeks had their doubts about the existence of the gods, the vast majority of Greeks did not question the validity of the stories. The Greeks used their religion to explain the doings of the natural world and their own origins; it was a source of pride to trace one's lineage or the founding of one's city to the actions of a god. [PARAGRAPH:1]Archaeology and linguistic analysis suggests that the Hellenic religion was heavily influenced by other religions. For example, the Greek Zeus, Roman Jupiter, Germanic Tyr, and Sanskrit Dyaus are all sky gods that share a common Indo-European origin sometime in the distant past. Other gods were borrowed or influenced from Near Eastern religions; Aphrodite possessed a very similar function to the Semitic goddesses Ishtar and Astarte. During the Hellenic period and afterwards, the Greek religion spread across much of the Mediterranean and Near East, influencing many of the previously existing religions and giving rise to new syncretistic mystery cults. Although the Hellenic religion is no longer followed, it continues to provide inspiration for artists throughout the world.</English>
		<French>[TAB]La religion hell&#233;nique, &#224; laquelle on fait le plus souvent r&#233;f&#233;rence sous l'appellation de mythologie grecque, comprend un grand nombre de l&#233;gendes sur les dieux, d&#233;esses et h&#233;ros. Certaines de ces l&#233;gendes remontent &#224; plusieurs si&#232;cles, ayant &#233;t&#233; transmises par la tradition orale. La religion hell&#233;nique est polyth&#233;iste, avec d'innombrables divinit&#233;s locales de la nature en plus des principaux dieux du panth&#233;on olympien. Les dieux grecs ont forme humaine mais poss&#232;dent des pouvoirs surnaturels, ont &#233;t&#233; engendr&#233;s par d'autres dieux mais ne vieillissent pas, ils sont immortels, peuvent voyager sur de tr&#232;s grandes distances instantan&#233;ment, parler &#224; travers les humains (parfois sans m&#234;me que ceux-ci s'en aper&#231;oivent), etc. Certains dieux sont les personnifications des forces de la nature (H&#233;lios &#233;tant litt&#233;ralement le dieu du soleil) alors que d'autres ont des personnalit&#233;s complexes et sont associ&#233;s &#224; de multiples fonctions (Apollon en &#233;tant le meilleur exemple). [PARAGRAPH:1]Dieux et d&#233;esses sont tous parents d'une m&#234;me grande famille, mais il existe des g&#233;n&#233;rations distinctes de dieux, et leurs interactions sont parfois tr&#232;s violentes. Le fait est que les dieux olympiens n'occupent leur position dominante qu'apr&#232;s avoir chass&#233; une premi&#232;re g&#233;n&#233;ration de dieux appel&#233;s les Titans. Cela refl&#232;te sans doute le chevauchement culturel mythologique existant entre les Grecs et la civilisation pr&#233;c&#233;dente, chass&#233;e &#224; leur arriv&#233;e dans le P&#233;loponn&#232;se aux alentours de 1000 av. J.-C.. [PARAGRAPH:1]Outre de nombreuses l&#233;gendes sur les dieux, la tradition orale hell&#233;nique est riche de grandes sagas relatant les hauts faits de h&#233;ros humains, dont un certain nombre ont une ascendance divine. On pense notamment aux l&#233;gendes d'H&#233;racl&#232;s, de Pers&#233;e, de Jason et des personnages de l'Iliade. Ces mortels entrent souvent en conflit avec des dieux et en triomphent parfois. Nombre d'entre eux, surtout s'ils sont nobles et puissants comme Achille, sont tenus en haute estime par les Grecs. [PARAGRAPH:1] M&#234;me si certains des Grecs &#233;duqu&#233;s entretiennent quelques doutes &#224; propos de la r&#233;alit&#233; dessin&#233;e par la religion hell&#233;nique, la grande majorit&#233; de la population accepte sans r&#233;serve la mythologie comme seule v&#233;rit&#233;. Les Grecs s'appuient sur leur religion pour expliquer les ph&#233;nom&#232;nes naturels et leurs propres origines, et c'est une source de grande fiert&#233; que de pouvoir associer une lign&#233;e ou la fondation d'une cit&#233; aux actions d'un dieu.[PARAGRAPH:1] Les r&#233;sultats des recherches arch&#233;ologiques et linguistiques laissent penser que la religion hell&#233;nique a &#233;t&#233; tr&#232;s influenc&#233;e par d'autres religions. C'est ainsi que le dieu grec Zeus, le dieu romain Jupiter, le dieu germain Tyr et le dieu sanskrit Dyaus sont tous des dieux du ciel, et il est probable qu'ils partagent tous une m&#234;me lointaine origine indo-europ&#233;enne. Les Grecs empruntent librement des dieux &#224; d'autres cultes du Proche-Orient, c'est ainsi qu'Aphrodite a des fonctions tr&#232;s proches de celles des d&#233;esses s&#233;mites Ishtar et Astart&#233;. Au cours de l'&#233;poque hell&#233;nique et par la suite, la religion grecque se r&#233;pand &#224; travers la plus grande partie de la M&#233;diterran&#233;e et du Proche-Orient, influen&#231;ant nombre des cultes d&#233;j&#224; existants et donnant naissance &#224; de nouveaux cultes syncr&#233;tistes. Bien que la religion grecque ne soit plus pratiqu&#233;e de nos jours, ses mythologies continuent d'enflammer les imaginations et d'illuminer les esprits.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die hellenistische Religion der Antike, auch als griechische Mythologie bezeichnet, umfasste einen enormen Fundus an G&#246;tter- und Heldensagen. Diese Geschichten datieren viele Jahrhunderte zur&#252;ck und blieben in der pr&#228;literarischen Zeit durch m&#252;ndliche &#220;berlieferung erhalten. Der hellenistische Glaube war angesichts der vielen G&#246;tter und G&#246;ttinnen des Olymps sowie zahlloser regionaler Naturgottheiten extrem polytheistisch gepr&#228;gt. Die griechischen G&#246;tter wurden in der Regel in menschlicher Form dargestellt, besa&#223;en allerdings &#252;bernat&#252;rliche Kr&#228;fte. Sie wurden von anderen Gottheiten geboren, alterten nicht, waren unsterblich, konnten im Nu enorme Entfernungen &#252;berwinden, sprachen durch die Menschen (mit oder ohne deren Wissen) etc. Einige G&#246;tter verk&#246;rperten Naturgewalten (zum Beispiel war Helios im w&#246;rtlichen Sinne der Gott der Sonne), w&#228;hrend andere komplexe Pers&#246;nlichkeitsstrukturen aufwiesen und zahlreiche Funktionen wahrnahmen (zum Beispiel Apollon). [PARAGRAPH:1]Als Teil einer gro&#223;en Familie waren die G&#246;tter und G&#246;ttinnen alle irgendwie miteinander verwandt, aber es gab eine klare Generationeneinteilung und manchmal bek&#228;mpften sie sich auch gegenseitig. Zum Beispiel sollen die G&#246;tter des Olymps ihre Vorherrschaft durch den Sturz der vorangehenden G&#246;ttergeneration, der so genannten Titanen, gesichert haben. Hierbei k&#246;nnte es sich um eine mythische Darstellung der kulturellen &#220;berschneidung zwischen den Griechen und der fr&#252;heren Population in dieser Region handeln, die sie bei der Ankunft auf dem Peleponnes um 1000 vor Christus vertrieben hatten. [PARAGRAPH:1]Neben den vielen G&#246;ttergeschichten wurde die griechische Religion auch von zahlreichen grandiosen Sagen &#252;ber die Abenteuer verschiedener Helden beeinflusst, von denen viele zumindest ein g&#246;ttliches Elternteil besa&#223;en. Die Erz&#228;hlungen handelten von heldenhaften Pers&#246;nlichkeiten wie Herakles, Perseus, Jason sowie den Charakteren der Ilias und inspirierten viele griechische K&#252;nstler sp&#228;terer Generationen. Diese Helden in Menschengestalt kamen h&#228;ufig mit den G&#246;ttern in Kontakt, &#252;bertrumpften sie bisweilen sogar und wurden von den Griechen meist hoch gesch&#228;tzt, insbesondere so ehrenhafte Pers&#246;nlichkeiten wie zum Beispiel Achilles. [PARAGRAPH:1]Einige der griechischen Gelehrten hatten durchaus Zweifel an dem Wahrheitsgehalt der griechischen Mythologie, dennoch stellte der &#252;berwiegende Teil der Bev&#246;lkerung die Stichhaltigkeit der &#252;berlieferten Legenden nicht in Frage. Die Griechen nutzten ihre Religion, um nat&#252;rliche Vorg&#228;nge und auch ihren eigenen Ursprung zu erkl&#228;ren. Man war stolz darauf, wenn man seine eigene Herkunft oder die Gr&#252;ndung seiner Heimatstadt auf das Einwirken eines Gottes zur&#252;ckf&#252;hren konnte. [PARAGRAPH:1]Arch&#228;ologische und sprachliche Untersuchungen haben ergeben, dass die griechische Religion stark von anderen Religionen beeinflusst war. Zum Beispiel stellen der griechische Gott Zeus, der r&#246;mische Gott Jupiter, der germanische Gott Tyr und der Sanskrit-Gott Dyaus allesamt Himmelsg&#246;tter dar, die irgendwann in der fernen Vergangenheit einen gemeinsamen indo-europ&#228;ischen Ursprung hatten. Andere G&#246;tter wurden von den Religionen im Nahen Osten "ausgeborgt" oder zumindest beeinflusst: Aphrodite besa&#223; frappierend &#228;hnliche Eigenschaften und Funktionen wie die semitischen G&#246;ttinnen Ishtar und Astarte. W&#228;hrend der hellenischen Periode und auch danach kam es zu einer starken Verbreitung der griechischen Mythologie &#252;ber gro&#223;e Teile des Mittelmeerraums und des Nahen Ostens. Sie beeinflusste viele der bereits existierenden Religionen und ebnete den Weg f&#252;r die Entstehung neuer synkretistischer Mysterienkulte. Obwohl die griechische Religion des hellenistischen Zeitalters heute nicht mehr in dieser Form praktiziert wird, lassen sich auch heute noch K&#252;nstler in aller Welt von ihr inspirieren.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]La religione ellenica, nota anche come "mitologia greca", &#232; composta da un'enorme serie di storie di dei, dee ed eroi, tramandate a lungo tempo oralmente nell'era pre-letteraria. La religione ellenica era politeistica e oltre agli dei e alle dee dell'Olimpo comprendeva innumerevoli divinit&#224; naturali locali. Le divinit&#224; greche avevano aspetto umano ma erano dotate di poteri soprannaturali; pur nascendo (da altre divinit&#224;) non invecchiavano ed erano immortali, potevano coprire enormi distanze istantaneamente, parlare attraverso gli uomini con o senza la loro consapevolezza, ecc. Alcune divinit&#224; erano la personificazione di forze naturali (per esempio, Elio era letteralmente il dio del sole), mentre altre avevano personalit&#224; complesse e numerose funzioni (Apollo ne &#232; forse il miglior esempio).  [PARAGRAPH:1]Le divinit&#224; avevano fra loro vincoli di parentela e formavano una grande famiglia, ma potevano distinguersi diverse generazioni, le cui interazioni con le altre avevano spesso esiti violenti. Per fare un esempio, gli dei olimpici avevano raggiunto la loro posizione di dominio estromettendo la precedente generazione dei Titani. Questo fenomeno potrebbe essere un riflesso culturale di ci&#242; che avvenne quando i Greci si sostituirono alla popolazione locale quando giunsero nel Peloponneso intorno al 1000 a.C. [PARAGRAPH:1]Oltre alle storie sugli dei, la mitologia greca &#232; piena di grandi saghe che narrano le gesta di eroi, molti dei quali avevano genitori divini. I miti di Ercole, Perseo, Giasone e le storie dei protagonisti dell'Iliade furono spesso oggetto di rielaborazione da parte degli artisti greci successivi. Si trattava di uomini che interagivano spesso con gli dei, a volte superandoli. Molti di loro erano enormemente stimati dai Greci, soprattutto se "nobili" come Achille.  [PARAGRAPH:1]Anche se i Greci meglio istruiti avevano i loro dubbi sul fondamento della religione ellenica, il popolo non metteva in dubbio la veridicit&#224; delle storie. I Greci usarono la loro religione per spiegare i fenomeni naturali e le proprie origini; era fonte di orgoglio il fatto che la propria ascendenza o la fondazione della propria citt&#224; potessero essere fatte risalire a un atto divino. [PARAGRAPH:1]Le analisi archeologiche e linguistiche suggeriscono che la religione ellenica abbia subito una pesante influenza da parte di altre religioni. Per esempio, il dio greco Zeus, il dio romano Giove, il dio germanico Tyr e il dio sanscrito Dyaus sono tutte divinit&#224; del cielo che condividono un'origine indo-europea risalente a chiss&#224; quando nel passato. Altre divinit&#224; furono prese in prestito o influenzate dalle religioni del Vicinio Oriente: Afrodite aveva una funzione simile a quella delle semitiche Ishtar e Astarte. Nel corso del periodo ellenico e anche dopo, la religione greca si diffuse nel Mediterraneo e nel Vicino Oriente, influenzando a sua volta molte religioni pre-esistenti e facendo nascere nuovi culti mistici sincretici. Anche se oggi si tratta di una religione morta, la mitologia greca ha ispirato gli artisti per migliaia di anni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]La religi&#243;n hel&#233;nica, tambi&#233;n conocida como mitolog&#237;a griega, comprende un cuerpo enorme de narraciones sobre los dioses y h&#233;roes. Estas historias ten&#237;an muchos siglos de antig&#252;edad y, hasta la aparici&#243;n de la escritura en Grecia, se conservaron mediante la tradici&#243;n oral. De naturaleza polite&#237;sta, contaba con un sinf&#237;n de deidades naturales locales, adem&#225;s de los principales dioses y diosas del Olimpo. Los dioses griegos ten&#237;an forma humana, pero pose&#237;an poderes sobrenaturales; eran engendrados por otros dioses, pero nunca envejec&#237;an, no pod&#237;an morir, pod&#237;an cruzar enormes distancias al instante, hablaban a trav&#233;s de los humanos con o sin su consentimiento, etc. Algunos de ellos eran los aspectos personificados de las fuerzas de la naturaleza (Helios, por ejemplo, era literalmente el dios del sol) mientras que otros pose&#237;an personalidades complejas y funciones m&#250;ltiples (seguramente Apolo sea el mejor ejemplo). [PARAGRAPH:1]Todos los dioses pertenec&#237;an a una gran familia, pero hab&#237;a varias generaciones diferenciadas y su interacci&#243;n era en muchas ocasiones violenta. Los dioses del Olimpo, por ejemplo, hab&#237;an alcanzado su posici&#243;n de predominio tras expulsar a una generaci&#243;n anterior de dioses y diosas (los titanes). Esto bien pudiera ser una transposici&#243;n mitol&#243;gica de la lucha entre los griegos y la cultura anterior, a la que desplazaron cuando llegaron al Peloponeso, alrededor del 1000 a. C. [PARAGRAPH:1]Adem&#225;s de las historias de los dioses, la religi&#243;n hel&#233;nica estaba repleta de grandes historias sobre las haza&#241;as de los h&#233;roes, muchos de los cuales estaban emparentados con los dioses. Abundan las narraciones acerca de figuras como H&#233;rcules, Perseo, Jas&#243;n y los personajes de la Il&#237;ada. Estos humanos sol&#237;an relacionarse con los dioses y, a veces, hasta los superaban. Los griegos sent&#237;an gran estima por estos h&#233;roes, especialmente por los personajes "nobles", como por ejemplo Aquiles. [PARAGRAPH:1]Aunque algunos griegos cultivados ten&#237;an sus dudas sobre la existencia de los dioses, la mayor&#237;a no cuestionaba la validez de las historias. Los griegos utilizaban su religi&#243;n para explicar el mundo natural y sus propios or&#237;genes. Desde trazar los or&#237;genes del propio linaje o la fundaci&#243;n de una ciudad hasta los actos de un dios era motivo de gran orgullo. [PARAGRAPH:1]La arqueolog&#237;a y el an&#225;lisis ling&#252;&#237;stico sugieren que la religi&#243;n hel&#233;nica estuvo muy influida por otras religiones. Por poner un ejemplo, el Zeus griego, el J&#250;piter romano, el Tyr germano y el Dyaus s&#225;nscrito son todos dioses del cielo que comparten un origen indoeuropeo com&#250;n en un pasado lejano. Otros dioses proced&#237;an de religiones de Oriente Pr&#243;ximo (o hab&#237;an recibido importantes influencias de ellas): Afrodita pose&#237;a una funci&#243;n muy similar a la de las diosas sem&#237;ticas Ishtar y Astart&#233;. Durante el per&#237;odo helen&#237;stico y despu&#233;s de &#233;l, la religi&#243;n griega se extendi&#243; por gran parte del Mediterr&#225;neo y Oriente Pr&#243;ximo, lo que influy&#243; en muchas de las religiones existentes y origin&#243; nuevos cultos mist&#233;ricos y sincr&#233;ticos. Aunque la religi&#243;n hel&#233;nica ya no cuenta con seguidores, sigue siendo una gran fuente de inspiraci&#243;n para artistas del mundo entero.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Temple -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HELLENIC_TEMPLE</Tag>
		<English>Hellenic Temple</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Temple hell&#233;nique</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Hellenistischer Tempel</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Tempio ellenico:Templi ellenici</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Templo hel&#233;nico:Templos hel&#233;nicos</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_NEW_GREEKWAR_BUILDING_HELLENIC_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In Civilization IV, a temple is defined as a building where the faithful come to worship. Christians call their temples "churches," while Muslims call theirs "mosques," and Jews call theirs, simply, "temples." Temples are far more common than cathedrals, but much less large and ornate. Even the smallest village can possess a temple.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Dans Civilization IV, un petit lieu de culte est d&#233;fini comme un &#233;difice dans lequel les fid&#232;les viennent pratiquer leur religion : "&#233;glises" pour les chr&#233;tiens, "petites mosqu&#233;es" pour les musulmans et "petites synagogues" pour les juifs. Ces petits lieux de culte sont bien plus courants que les grands lieux de culte mais sont de taille plus r&#233;duite et sont bien moins richement orn&#233;s. M&#234;me le village le plus petit peut poss&#233;der un petit lieu de culte.</French>
		<German>[TAB]In Civilization IV sind Tempel Geb&#228;ude, in denen Gl&#228;ubige beten. Christen nennen ihre Tempel "Kirchen", Moslems "Moscheen". Es gibt deutlich mehr Tempel als Kathedralen. Allerdings sind sie wesentlich kleiner und schlichter. Selbst das kleinste Dorf kann einen Tempel besitzen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]In Civilization IV, il tempio &#232; un edificio all'interno del quale i fedeli si recano a pregare. I Cristiani chiamano i loro templi "chiese", i Musulmani "moschee", gli Ebrei semplicemente "templi". I templi sono pi&#249; comuni delle cattedrali, ma sono pi&#249; piccoli e poco fastosi. Anche il villaggio pi&#249; piccolo ospita un tempio.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]En Civilization IV, un templo se define como un lugar al que los fieles acuden a venerar. Los cristianos llaman a sus templos "iglesias", mientras que para los musulmanes son "mezquitas" y para los jud&#237;os, sencillamente, "templos". Son mucho m&#225;s comunes que las catedrales, pero tambi&#233;n mucho m&#225;s peque&#241;os y humildes. Hasta la m&#225;s peque&#241;a aldea puede poseer uno.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Cathedral (Pantheon) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HELLENIC_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
		<English>Hellenic Cathedral (Pantheon)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Grand lieu de culte hell&#233;nique</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Hellenistisches Pantheon</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Cattedrale ellenica:Cattedrali elleniche</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Catedral hel&#233;nica:Catedrales hel&#233;nicas</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HELLENIC_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In Civilization IV, a cathedral is defined as an especially large and ornate religious building where the faithful worship. Only the most prosperous cities can afford to create cathedrals, as they require huge amounts of raw material and years of dedicated labor by skilled craftsmen. For example, the Notre Dame Cathedral in Paris, France, took over two centuries to complete.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Dans Civilization IV, un grand lieu de culte est d&#233;fini comme un &#233;difice religieux particuli&#232;rement grand et richement orn&#233; dans lequel les fid&#232;les pratiquent leur religion : "cath&#233;drales" pour les chr&#233;tiens, "mosqu&#233;es" pour les musulmans et "synagogues" pour les juifs. Seules les villes les plus prosp&#232;res ont les moyens de construire de tels &#233;difices. En effet, ils n&#233;cessitent d'&#233;normes quantit&#233;s de mat&#233;riaux bruts et des artisans sp&#233;cialis&#233;s doivent y consacrer des ann&#233;es de travail. Ainsi, il a fallu plus de deux si&#232;cles pour terminer la cath&#233;drale Notre-Dame &#224; Paris.</French>
		<German>[TAB]In Civilization IV sind Kathedralen gro&#223;e und pr&#228;chtige Gottesh&#228;user, in denen Gl&#228;ubige beten. Nur die reichsten aller St&#228;dte k&#246;nnen sich den Bau einer Kathedrale leisten, da hierf&#252;r gro&#223;e Mengen an Baumaterial und die jahrelange Arbeit erfahrener Handwerker erforderlich sind. Die Kathedrale von Notre Dame in Paris wurde beispielsweise erst nach 200-j&#228;hriger Bauzeit fertig gestellt.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]In Civilization IV, viene definito cattedrale un edificio religioso particolarmente grande e sfarzoso adibito a luogo di culto per i fedeli. Solamente le citt&#224; pi&#249; prosperose possono permettersi l'edificazione di cattedrali poich&#233; sono necessari un'enorme quantit&#224; di materiali e operai esperti. Per esempio, per completare la cattedrale di Notre-Dame de Paris, in Francia, ci sono voluti pi&#249; di due secoli.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]En Civilization IV, una catedral se define como un edificio religioso especialmente grande y ornamentado en el que se re&#250;nen los fieles para celebrar sus ritos. Solo las ciudades m&#225;s grandes pueden permitirse el lujo de crear catedrales, puesto que requieren enormes cantidades de materias primas y a&#241;os de dedicaci&#243;n por parte de trabajadores especializados. Por ejemplo, la catedral de Notre Dame, Francia, tard&#243; dos siglos en completarse.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Monastry (Gymnasia) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HELLENIC_MONASTERY</Tag>
		<English>Hellenic Monastry (Gymnasia)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Monast&#232;re hell&#233;nique</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Hellenistisches Gymnasium</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Monastero ellenico:Monasteri ellenici</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Monasterio hel&#233;nico:Monasterios hel&#233;nicos</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HELLENIC_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A monastery is a building where monks can retreat from the world and concentrate upon the divine. Usually a monastery will have strict rules of conduct to protect its unworldly members from temptation. In some monasteries, the monks are totally silent; in others no visitors are allowed inside. Monasteries usually have many daily rituals and religious services. [PARAGRAPH:1] Throughout the ages monasteries have often been centers of learning. In remote areas the monks may be the only literate people for miles around. Monks have often been employed as scribes, copying out the words of their religion's sacred scripture. Monasteries frequently have extensive libraries, holding religious, scientific, medical and philosophical texts.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Un monast&#232;re est un &#233;difice dans lequel les moines peuvent se retirer du monde et se concentrer sur le divin. G&#233;n&#233;ralement, les r&#232;gles de conduite y sont strictes afin de prot&#233;ger ses membres, d&#233;tach&#233;s du monde, de la tentation. Dans certains monast&#232;res, les moines sont totalement silencieux ; dans d'autres, les visiteurs ne sont pas autoris&#233;s &#224; p&#233;n&#233;trer dans leur enceinte. Les monast&#232;res ont g&#233;n&#233;ralement de nombreux rituels et services religieux quotidiens. [PARAGRAPH:1]A travers les si&#232;cles, les monast&#232;res ont souvent &#233;t&#233; des centres d'&#233;rudition. Dans les zones retir&#233;es, les moines &#233;taient parfois les seules personnes sachant lire et &#233;crire &#224; des kilom&#232;tres &#224; la ronde. Ils ont souvent servi de scribes, recopiant les textes sacr&#233;s de leur religion. Les monast&#232;res ont g&#233;n&#233;ralement de grandes biblioth&#232;ques poss&#233;dant des textes religieux, scientifiques, m&#233;dicaux et philosophiques.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Kl&#246;ster sind Geb&#228;ude, in die sich M&#246;nche zur&#252;ckziehen, um sich auf Gott zu konzentrieren. In Kl&#246;stern gelten strenge Verhaltensregeln, die die M&#246;nche vor Versuchungen bewahren sollen. In einigen Kl&#246;stern herrscht ein strenges Redeverbot, in anderen sind keine Besucher gestattet. Die M&#246;nche selbst gehen t&#228;glich ihren religi&#246;sen Pflichten nach. [PARAGRAPH:1] In der Vergangenheit waren Kl&#246;ster stets auch Zentren des Wissens. In abgelegenen Gegenden waren die M&#246;nche oft die einzigen gebildeten Menschen, die als Schreiber ihre religi&#246;sen Schriften kopierten. Kl&#246;ster haben nicht selten Bibliotheken, in denen unz&#228;hlige religi&#246;se, wissenschaftliche, medizinische und philosophische Texte aufbewahrt werden.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il monastero &#232; un edificio nel quale i monaci possono ritirarsi dal mondo e concentrarsi sul Divino. In genere, nel monastero vige un regolamento ferreo per proteggere i membri della comunit&#224; dalle tentazioni. In alcuni monasteri, i monaci erano completamente silenziosi e non erano permesse visite dall'esterno per non interrompere i rituali quotidiani e le cerimonie religiose. [PARAGRAPH:1] Nel corso dei secoli, i monasteri sono stati spesso centro di insegnamento: in alcune zone, i monaci erano sovente gli unici in grado di leggere e scrivere nel giro di diversi chilometri. Da sempre, i monaci sono stati utilizzati come scribi per copiare le parole sacre della propria religione; i monasteri ospitavano spesso delle biblioteche che contenevano testi religiosi, scientifici, medici e filosofici.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Un monasterio es un edificio en el que los monjes pueden retirarse del mundo para concentrarse en los asuntos de la divinidad. Normalmente tienen estrictas reglas de comportamiento para proteger a sus miembros de la tentaci&#243;n. En algunos monasterios, los monjes guardan un silencio total, mientras que en otros no se permite el acceso a los visitantes. Lo habitual es que sus miembros tengan que celebrar a diario muchos rituales y servicios religiosos. [PARAGRAPH:1] A lo largo de la historia, los monasterios han sido muchas veces centros de estudio. En las regiones remotas, los monjes pod&#237;an ser las &#250;nicas personas letradas en muchos kil&#243;metros a la redonda. A menudo han sido empleados como escribas, y se han dedicado a copiar los textos sagrados de su religi&#243;n. Normalmente cuentan con grandes bibliotecas, que contienen textos religiosos, cient&#237;ficos, m&#233;dicos y filos&#243;ficos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Shrine (Statue of Zeus) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HELLENIC_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Hellenic Shrine (The Statue of Zeus)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Sanctuaire hell&#233;nique</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Zeus-Statue</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Santuario ellenico:Santuari ellenici</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Altar hel&#233;nico:Altares hel&#233;nicos</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HELLENIC_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Many monuments were created to honor Zeus, King of the Greek Gods, yet none could be as impressive as the Statue of Zeus at Olympia. Over forty feet tall, the Statue filled the temple in which it was constructed from floor to ceiling. Created by the master artisan Phidias between 438 and 446BC, the whole statue rested on a wooden frame built upon a cedarwood throne of appropriate size for a forty-foot deity. The frame was then draped in ivory and gold (ivory for skin, gold for clothing) and covered from head to toe in jewels. Before Zeus' feet, a shallow lake of olive oil reflected light into the temple, illuminating the otherwise closed building. Every four years, when the Olympic Games would be held in the town, Olympic competitors would approach the statue and make sacrifices to the King of the Gods with the hope of assuring their victory.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Beaucoup de monuments ont &#233;t&#233; &#233;rig&#233;s pour honorer Zeus, roi des dieux grecs. Cependant, aucun ne saurait &#234;tre aussi impressionnant que la statue de Zeus &#224; Olympie. Mesurant plus de 12 m&#232;tres de haut, la statue atteignait le plafond du temple dans lequel elle a &#233;t&#233; construite. Cr&#233;&#233;e par le ma&#238;tre artisan Phidias entre 438 et 446 av. J.C., la statue repose sur un cadre en bois construit sur un &#233;norme tr&#244;ne en c&#232;dre. Le cadre a ensuite &#233;t&#233; drap&#233; d'or et d'ivoire (ivoire pour la peau, or pour les v&#234;tements) et couvert de bijoux. Aux pieds de Zeus, un lac d'huile d'olive r&#233;fl&#233;chissait la lumi&#232;re, illuminant le temple. Tous les quatre ans, lorsque les jeux olympiques avaient lieu en ville, les concurrents s'approchaient de la statue et faisaient des sacrifices au roi des dieux dans l'espoir qu'il leur assurerait la victoire.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Viele Monumente wurden zu Ehren des griechischen G&#246;tterk&#246;nigs Zeus erschaffen, aber keins war so beeindruckend wie die Zeus-Statue von Olympia. Mit &#252;ber zw&#246;lf Metern f&#252;llte die Statue die gesamte Raumh&#246;he des Tempels, in dem sie errichtet wurde. Sie wurde zwischen 446 und 438 v. Chr. vom Meistersteinmetz Phidias erschaffen und st&#252;tzte sich auf ein h&#246;lzernes Ger&#252;st, das auf einem in seinen Dimensionen der zw&#246;lf Meter hohen Gottheit angemessenen Thron aus Zedernholz fu&#223;te. Das Ger&#252;st wurde mit Elfenbein und Gold verziert (Elfenbein f&#252;r die Haut, Gold f&#252;r das Gewand) und von Kopf bis Fu&#223; mit Juwelen behangen. Vor Zeus' F&#252;&#223;en reflektierte ein seichter See aus Oliven&#246;l das Licht in das Innere des Tempels und erhellte das ansonsten geschlossene Geb&#228;ude. Alle vier Jahre, w&#228;hrend die Olympischen Spiele in der Stadt ausgetragen wurden, n&#228;herten sich die Wettk&#228;mpfer der Statue und brachten dem K&#246;nig der G&#246;tter Opfer dar, in der Hoffnung, er m&#246;ge ihnen daf&#252;r den Sieg schenken.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Furono eretti molti monumenti per onorare Zeus, il signore degli dei greci, ma nessuno &#232; da considerarsi tanto maestoso quanto la Statua di Zeus a Olimpia. La Statua era alta pi&#249; di 12 metri, raggiungendo il soffitto del tempio in cui era stata costruita. Creata dal maestro artigiano Fidia tra il 438 e il 446 a.C., l'intera statua era composta da una struttura di legno costruita su un trono di cedro di dimensioni appropriate per una divinit&#224; alta 12 metri. La struttura era poi coperta di oro e avorio (avorio per la pelle, oro per i vestiti) e coperta dalla testa ai piedi di gioielli. Davanti ai piedi di Zeus un lago poco profondo di olio d'oliva rifletteva la luce nel tempio, illuminando l'edificio altrimenti chiuso. Ogni quattro anni, quando si tenevano in citt&#224; i Giochi Olimpici, i concorrenti si avvicinavano alla statua per fare sacrifici al Re degli Dei, nella speranza che concedesse loro la vittoria.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Hubo muchos monumentos consagrados a Zeus, rey de los dioses griegos, pero ninguno de ellos tan impresionante como la estatua de Olimpia. Con sus casi quince metros de altura, la estatua llenaba el templo en el que estaba construido desde el suelo hasta el techo. Creada por el maestro Fidias entre los a&#241;os 438 y 446 a. C., la estatua descansaba sobre una estructura de madera construida encima de un trono de cedro del tama&#241;o apropiado para una escultura de semejantes dimensiones. La estructura estaba luego revestida de marfil y oro (marfil para la piel, oro para la ropa) y cubierta de joyas de la cabeza a los pies. A los pies de Zeus, un estanque poco profundo de aceite de oliva reflejaba la luz hacia el interior del templo, que no contaba con otros medios de iluminaci&#243;n. Cada cuatro a&#241;os, cuando se celebraban los Juegos Ol&#237;mpicos en el la ciudad, los competidores se acercaban al rey de los dioses y depositaban sus ofrendas a sus pies con la esperanza de que les concediera la victoria.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HELLENIC_SHRINE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Statue of Zeus[COLOR_REVERT] increases war weariness in the cities of those who go to war against its builder. It also increases the chances of a [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Great Artist[COLOR_REVERT] appearing.</English>
		<French>La [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Statue de Zeus[COLOR_REVERT] augmente la lassitude de guerre dans les villes des joueurs en guerre contre son constructeur. Elle augmente aussi les chances d'apparition d'un [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]artiste illustre[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>Die [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Zeus-Statue[COLOR_REVERT] erh&#246;ht die Kriegsm&#252;digkeit in St&#228;dten, die gegen den Erbauer der Statue in den Krieg ziehen. Au&#223;erdem erh&#246;ht sie die Chancen auf den Erhalt eines [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Gro&#223;en K&#252;nstlers[COLOR_REVERT].</German>
		<Italian>La [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Statua di Zeus[COLOR_REVERT] aumenta la stanchezza della guerra in coloro che combattono contro il suo costruttore. Aumenta inoltre le probabilit&#224; che appaia un [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Grande Artista[COLOR_REVERT].</Italian>
		<Spanish>La [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Estatua de Zeus[COLOR_REVERT] aumenta el hast&#237;o b&#233;lico en las ciudades de quienes vayan contra quien la construya. Tambi&#233;n aumenta las posibilidades de que aparezca un [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]gran artista[COLOR_REVERT].</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Wonder (Parthenon) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HELLENIC_WONDER_PARTHENON</Tag>
		<English>Hellenic Wonder (The Parthenon)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Parth&#233;non</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Der Parthenon</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Il Partenone</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>el Parten&#243;n:los Partenones</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HELLENIC_WONDER_PARTHENON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Parthenon was constructed in 433 BC, in Athens, Greece, in honor of Athens' patron goddess, Athena. Measuring 100 feet by 225 feet, the Parthenon is constructed almost totally of marble. The exterior of the Parthenon is ringed with Doric-style columns more than 30 feet in height, and the center part of the temple, called the "cella," is a large open space which once held a statue of Athena. Much of the temple was decorated with beautiful marble statues and friezes celebrating Athena and the glories of Athens. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Parthenon has suffered much from the ravages of time. In the 5th century a Roman Emperor stole the statue of Athena and moved it to Constantinople, where it was subsequently destroyed. In the 13th century the Parthenon was converted to a Catholic church, which involved altering the internal structure and removing (and probably destroying) many statues dedicated to the old gods. In the 15th century Athens was captured by the Ottomans, and the temple was turned into a mosque. In the 17th century the Parthenon was partially destroyed during a war between the Ottomans and Venetians. Finally, in the 19th century, the British ambassador to Greece looted all of the surviving marble friezes from the building, which he subsequently sold to the British museum. [PARAGRAPH:2]Despite the centuries of neglect, mutilation and pillaging, the Parthenon still stands - a remarkably powerful and beautiful symbol of the glories of ancient Greece.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Le Parth&#233;non a &#233;t&#233; construit en 433 av. J.-C. &#224; Ath&#232;nes, en Gr&#232;ce, en l'honneur de la d&#233;esse Ath&#233;na, patronne d'Ath&#232;nes. Mesurant 70 m sur 31 m, le Parth&#233;non est construit pratiquement enti&#232;rement en marbre. A l'ext&#233;rieur, il est entour&#233; de colonnes doriques mesurant plus de 9 m de haut et au centre du temple, appel&#233; "naos", se trouve un vaste espace abritant une statue d'Ath&#233;na. Une grande partie du temple &#233;tait d&#233;cor&#233;e de magnifiques statues de marbre et de frises c&#233;l&#233;brant Ath&#233;na et les gloires d'Ath&#232;nes. [PARAGRAPH:2]Le Parth&#233;non a beaucoup souffert des ravages du temps. Au Ve si&#232;cle, un empereur romain vola la statue d'Ath&#233;na et la transporta &#224; Constantinople, o&#249; elle fut d&#233;truite. Au XIIIe si&#232;cle, le Parth&#233;non fut transform&#233; en une &#233;glise catholique, ce qui entra&#238;na une modification de la structure interne ainsi que la suppression (et sans doute aussi la destruction) de nombreuses statues consacr&#233;es aux anciens dieux. Au XVe si&#232;cle, Ath&#232;nes fut prise par les Ottomans et le temple se trouva transform&#233; en mosqu&#233;e. Au XVIIe si&#232;cle, le Parth&#233;non fut partiellement d&#233;truit lors d'une guerre entre les Ottomans et les V&#233;nitiens. Enfin, au XIXe si&#232;cle, l'ambassadeur britannique en Gr&#232;ce pilla toutes les fresques de marbre subsistantes, dans le b&#226;timent, pour les vendre au British Museum. [PARAGRAPH:2]En d&#233;pit des si&#232;cles de n&#233;gligences, de mutilations et de pillages, le Parth&#233;non subsiste, symbole magnifique et remarquablement fort des gloires de la Gr&#232;ce antique.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Der Parthenon wurde 433 vor Christus in Athen zu Ehren der G&#246;ttin Athene gebaut. Die S&#228;ulen des etwa 30 mal 70 Meter gro&#223;en, im dorischen Stil erbauten Tempels sind &#252;ber 8 Meter hoch. Der zentrale Teil des Tempels (Cella) ist eine gro&#223;e Fl&#228;che, auf der einst eine Athene-Statue stand. Ein Gro&#223;teil des Tempels war mit Marmorstatuen und -fresken verziert, die Athene und den Ruhm Athens symbolisierten. [PARAGRAPH:2]Der Parthenon hat im Laufe der Jahrhunderte sehr gelitten. Im 5. Jahrhundert stahl ein r&#246;mischer Kaiser die Statue der Athene und brachte sie nach Konstantinopel, wo sie schlie&#223;lich zerst&#246;rt wurde. Im 13. Jahrhundert wurde der Parthenon als katholische Kirche geweiht. Dabei wurden die inneren Strukturen ver&#228;ndert und viele heidnische G&#246;tterstatuen zerst&#246;rt. Im 15. Jahrhundert besetzten die Ottomanen Athen und nutzten den Parthenon als Moschee. Im 17. Jahrhundert wurde der Parthenon teilweise zerst&#246;rt. Schlie&#223;lich raubte der britische Botschafter in Griechenland die noch erhaltenen Marmorfresken und verkaufte diese an das British Museum. [PARAGRAPH:2]Trotz der Vernachl&#228;ssigung, Zerst&#246;rung und Pl&#252;nderung steht der Parthenon noch immer ... als m&#228;chtiges Symbol der Bl&#252;tezeit Griechenlands.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il Partenone fu costruito ad Atene, in Grecia, intorno al 433 a. C. in favore di Atena. Alto circa 30 metri e lungo 70, il Partenone &#232; completamente realizzato in marmo. L'esterno del Partenone &#232; ricco di colonne doriche alte pi&#249; di 10 metri e la parte centrale del tempio, chiamata la "cella", &#232; un grande spazio aperto dove una volta di trovava una statua di Atena. Buona parte del tempio &#232; decorato con meravigliose statue di marmo e fregi che celebrano Atena e la gloria di Atene. [PARAGRAPH:2]Il Partenone &#232; stato danneggiato con il passare del tempo: nel V secolo, un Imperatore Romano rub&#242; la statua di Atena e la spost&#242; a Costantinopoli dove venne successivamente distrutta. Nel XIII secolo il Partenone fu convertito a chiesa Cattolica: per questo motivo vennero apportate molte modifiche alla struttura e vennero rimosse (probabilmente distrutte) molte delle statue dedicate alle antiche divinit&#224;. Nel XV secolo, Atene venne conquistata dagli Ottomani e il tempio venne adibito a moschea: nel XVII secolo, il Partenone fu distrutto parzialmente dalla guerra tra Ottomani e Veneziani. Infine, nel XIX secolo, l'ambasciatore Britannico in Grecia saccheggi&#242; tutti i rimanenti fregi di marmo dall'edificio, che vennero successivamente venduti al British Museum. [PARAGRAPH:2]Malgrado secoli di trascuratezza, mutilazioni, saccheggi, il Partenone &#232; ancora al suo posto, un simbolo che ricorda la potenza e la bellezza dell'antica Grecia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]El Parten&#243;n se construy&#243; en el 433 a. C., en Atenas, Grecia, en honor a la diosa patrona de esta ciudad, Atenea. Mide unos 70 x 30 metros y est&#225; construido casi totalmente de m&#225;rmol. El exterior est&#225; rodeado por un peristilo de estilo d&#243;rico de m&#225;s de diez metros de altura y la parte central del templo, llamada "cella", es un espacio abierto en el que anta&#241;o se levant&#243; la estatua de Atenea. Gran parte del templo estaba decorada con preciosos frisos y estatuas de m&#225;rmol en honor de Atenea y las glorias de Atenas. [PARAGRAPH:2]El Parten&#243;n ha sufrido muchos pillajes con el paso del tiempo. En el s. V, un emperador romano rob&#243; la estatua de Atenea y se la llev&#243; a Constantinopla, donde posteriormente fue destruida. En el s. XIII se convirti&#243; en una iglesia cat&#243;lica, lo que supuso alterar su estructura interna y quitar (y probablemente destruir) muchas estatuas dedicadas a los antiguos dioses. En el s. XV, Atenas fue capturada por los otomanos, y el templo se convirti&#243; en una mezquita. En el s. XVII fue parcialmente destruido durante una guerra entre otomanos y venecianos. Finalmente, en el s. XIX, el embajador brit&#225;nico en Grecia saque&#243; todos los frisos de m&#225;rmol que quedaban y posteriormente se los vendi&#243; al British Museum. [PARAGRAPH:2]Pese a siglos de abandono, mutilaci&#243;n y pillaje, el Parten&#243;n a&#250;n se alza como un s&#237;mbolo excepcionalmente poderoso y bello de las glorias de la antigua Grecia.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HELLENIC_WONDER_PARTHENON_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Parthenon[COLOR_REVERT] increases the rate at which your civilization generates [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Great People[COLOR_REVERT], particularly [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Great Artists[COLOR_REVERT]. It also has a high cultural value.</English>
		<French>Le [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Parth&#233;non[COLOR_REVERT] augmente le taux d'apparition des [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]personnages illustres[COLOR_REVERT] dans votre civilisation, notamment des [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]artistes illustres[COLOR_REVERT]. Il a &#233;galement un fort potentiel culturel.</French>
		<German>Der [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Parthenon[COLOR_REVERT] beschleunigt die Bildung [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Gro&#223;er Pers&#246;nlichkeiten[COLOR_REVERT] (vor allem [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Gro&#223;er K&#252;nstler[COLOR_REVERT]). Dar&#252;ber hinaus wirkt er sich positiv auf die Kultur einer Stadt aus.</German>
		<Italian>Il [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Partenone[COLOR_REVERT] aumenta il ritmo di generazione dei [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Grandi Personaggi[COLOR_REVERT] della tua civilt&#224;, in particolare dei [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Grandi Artisti[COLOR_REVERT]. Inoltre, ha un grande valore culturale.</Italian>
		<Spanish>El [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Parten&#243;n[COLOR_REVERT] aumenta el ritmo al que la civilizaci&#243;n genera [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Grandes personajes[COLOR_REVERT], especialmente [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Grandes artistas[COLOR_REVERT]. Tambi&#233;n tiene un gran valor cultural.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Wonder (Phidias Statue Workshop) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HELLENIC_WONDER_PHIDIAS_WORKSHOP</Tag>
		<English>Hellenic Wonder (Phidias Statue Workshop)</English>
		<French>Atelier de sculpture de Phidias</French>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Atelier delle sculture di Fidia</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HELLENIC_WONDER_PHIDIAS_WORKSHOP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Phidias was a Greek sculptor, painter and architect, who lived in the 5th century BC, and is commonly regarded as one of the greatest of all sculptors of Classical Greece: Phidias' Statue of Zeus at Olympia was one of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World. Phidias also designed the statues of the goddess Athena on the Athenian Acropolis, namely the Athena Parthenos inside the Parthenon and the Athena Promachos, a colossal bronze statue of Athena which stood between it and the the Propylaea, a monumental gateway that served as the entrance to the Acropolis in Athens. Phidias was the son of a certain Charmides.</English>
		<Italian>[TAB]Fidia è stato uno scultore, pittore e architetto greco, vissuto nel 5° secolo a.C.; è comunemente considerato uno dei più grandi di tutti gli scultori della Grecia classica: la Statua di Zeus realizzata da Fidia a Olimpia era una delle sette meraviglie del Mondo Antico. Fidia progettò anche le statue della dea Atena sull'Acropoli ateniese, ovvero l'Athena Parthenos dentro il Partenone e l'Athena Promachos, una colossale statua di bronzo di Atena che sorgeva tra di esso e i Propilei, l'ingresso monumentale che faceva da entrata all'Acropoli di Atene. Fidia era figlio di un certo Carmide.</Italian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HELLENIC_WONDER_PHIDIAS_WORKSHOP_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build the Phidias workshop to get a boost to culture in all your cities.</English>
		<Italian>Costruisci l'atelier di Fidia per ottenere un bonus alla cultura in tutte le tue città.</Italian>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Hinduism +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Cathedral (Mandir) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HINDU_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
		<English>Hindu Cathedral (Mandir)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Mandir hindou</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Hinduistischer Mandir</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Mandir Ind&#249;:Mandir Ind&#249;</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Mandir hind&#250;:Mandir hind&#250;es</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Shrine (The Kashi Vishwanath) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HINDU_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Hindu Shrine (The Kashi Vishwanath)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Kashi Vishwanath</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Kashi Vishwanath</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Il Kashi Vishwanath</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Kashi Vishwanath</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Islam +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Cathedral (Mosque) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
		<English>Islamic Cathedral (Mosque)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Mosqu&#233;e</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Islamische Moschee</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Moschea Islamica:Moschee Islamiche</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Mezquita isl&#225;mica:Mezquitas isl&#225;micas</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Shrine (The Masjid al-Haram) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Islamic Shrine (The Masjid al-Haram)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Al-Masjid al-Haraam</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Masjid al-Haram</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Il Masjid al-Haram</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Mezquita al-Haram</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Judaism +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Cathedral (Synagogue) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JEWISH_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
		<English>Jewish Cathedral (Synagogue)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Synagogue</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>J&#252;dische Synagoge</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Sinagoga Giudaica:Sinagoghe Giudaiche</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Sinagoga jud&#237;a:Sinagogas jud&#237;as</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Shrine (The Temple of Solomon) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JEWISH_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Jewish Shrine (The Temple of Solomon)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Temple de Salomon</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Salomons Tempel</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Il Tempio di Salomone</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Templo de Salom&#243;n</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Wonder (Masada) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JEWISH_WONDER_MASADA</Tag>
		<English>Jewish Wonder (Masada)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JEWISH_WONDER_MASADA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build the Masada to improve the production of your priests globally and provide a significant Culture boost</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JEWISH_WONDER_MASADA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Masada is the name for a site of ancient palaces and fortifications in the South District of Israel on top of an isolated rock plateau, or large mesa, on the eastern edge of the Judean Desert overlooking the Dead Sea. Masada became famous after the First Jewish-Roman War (also known as the Great Jewish Revolt) when a siege of the fortress by troops of the Roman Empire led to a mass suicide of the site's Jewish Sicarii fugitives when defeat became imminent. Today, Masada is a very popular tourist destination.[PARAGRAPH:2]The cliffs on the east edge of Masada are about 1,300 feet (400 m) high and the cliffs on the west are about 300 feet (90 m) high; the natural approaches to the cliff top are very difficult. The top of the plateau is flat and rhomboid-shaped, about 1,800 feet (550 m) by 900 feet (275 m). There was a casemate wall around the top of the plateau totaling 4,300 feet (1.3 km) long and 12 feet (3.7 m) thick, with many towers, and the fortress included storehouses, barracks, an armory, the palace, and cisterns that were refilled by rainwater. Three narrow, winding paths led from below up to fortified gates.[PARAGRAPH:2]According to Josephus, a first-century Jewish Roman historian, Herod the Great fortified Masada between 37 and 31 BCE as a refuge for himself in the event of a revolt. In 66 CE, at the beginning of the First Jewish-Roman War against the Roman Empire, a group of Judaic extremist rebels called the Sicarii took Masada from the Roman garrison stationed there.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 72 CE, the Roman governor of Iudaea Lucius Flavius Silva marched against Masada with the Roman legion X Fretensis and laid siege to the fortress. After failed attempts to breach the wall, they built a circumvallation wall and then a rampart against the western face of the plateau, using thousands of tons of stones and beaten earth. The rampart was complete in the spring of 73, after approximately two to three months of siege, allowing the Romans to finally breach the wall of the fortress with a battering ram. When they entered the fortress, however, the Romans discovered that its 936 inhabitants had set all the buildings but the food storerooms ablaze and committed mass suicide rather than face certain capture, defeat, slavery or execution by their enemies.</English>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Kemetism +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Religion Details -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_KEMETISM</Tag>
		<English>Kemetism</English>
		<French>Kémétisme</French>
		<German>Kemetismus</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_KEMETISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The ancient Egyptian religion was not really a religion at all in the way that we would think of it, but an overlapping set of cults and rituals that together shared a common worldview. There was no unifying theology or set of canonical writings to the Egyptian religion. Instead, the religion was based upon a series of ritual interactions between the gods and their followers, the Egyptian priests, which had developed over a long period of time. This religion was very old, and dates back to at least 3000BC but possibly even earlier. Ancient Egyptian religion was a mixture of science, law, and philosophy acting together within the same framework; it would have been impossible for an Egyptian to stand outside of the religion. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]According to Egyptian mythology, before creation there was only the sea. The sun-god Re (or Ra) came from out of an egg, and the other gods were born from him who went on to become the sky, the earth, the land of the dead, etc. The most important myth in the Egyptian religion told the story of the murder and rebirth of Osiris, and the revenge gained by his son Horus on his murderer. The story not only explained the cycle of nature, but also served to highlight the importance of the sacred kingship for Egypt. As the legend suggests, Egyptian religion was polytheistic in nature and had as many as 80 major gods and goddesses. The Egyptian gods were mostly human in form, but some also took the form of animals, and others combined aspects of both, such as a human with the head of a jackal. An unusual feature of the Egyptian religion was that the gods were thought to need food and drink just like humans, which were provided by priests in daily rituals located in the temples of the gods. The statue of the deity, known as an image, would be bathed and fed multiple times daily by the priests in sacred rituals. In return for this care, the gods would watch over and protect the Egyptians from harm. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]State and religion were inextricably bound together in ancient Egypt. The pharaoh was considered to be not only the highest priest in the Egyptian religion, but also a living god on earth. Although it was the priests and not pharaoh who performed most of the religious ceremonies, his power was unquestioned, and massive temples that required enormous amounts of labor were built in order to serve as the final resting places of these rulers. As mentioned earlier, the Egyptian religion was a cult in which the ordinary people were not allowed to participate, beyond taking part in public festivals. There were many small shrines across Egypt that may have been frequented by the people, but the main cult was strictly off-limits and access to the major temples severely curtailed. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]In the last few centuries before the Roman conquest of Egypt, the religion began to be influenced by foreign deities. A number of different variations developed based on Hellenic practices, further complicating the already heterogeneous religion. The traditional Egyptian religion vanished later on in the wake of Christianity and Islam, and is a dead religion today. </English>
		<French>[TAB]L'ancien culte &#233;gyptien n'est pas exactement une religion &#224; proprement parler. C'est plut&#244;t un enchev&#234;trement de croyances et rituels partageant une m&#234;me conception du monde, mais il n'existe pas de th&#233;ologie unificatrice ou d'&#233;critures canoniques : la religion s'appuie sur une s&#233;rie d'interactions rituelles entre les dieux et leurs disciples, les pr&#234;tres &#233;gyptiens, interactions d&#233;velopp&#233;es sur une tr&#232;s longue p&#233;riode. Cette religion est tr&#232;s ancienne, certains de ses principes remontent &#224; au moins 3000 av. J.-C., alors que d'autres sont apparus par la suite. Le culte associe les influences de la science, de la loi et de la philosophie dans un m&#234;me cadre. Il est impossible pour un Egyptien de se soustraire &#224; l'influence de la religion. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Selon la mythologie &#233;gyptienne, avant la cr&#233;ation il n'y avait que la mer. Le dieu soleil Re (or Ra) est sorti d'un oeuf et a engendr&#233; les autres dieux. Ces dieux sont devenus le ciel, la terre, le monde des morts et ainsi de suite. La plus importante l&#233;gende de la mythologie &#233;gyptienne raconte l'histoire du meurtre et de la renaissance d'Osiris, dieu du monde des morts, et la vengeance contre son assassin accomplie par son fils Horus. L'histoire ne permet pas seulement d'expliquer le cycle de la nature, elle sert aussi &#224; mettre en lumi&#232;re l'importance d'une royaut&#233; sacr&#233;e en Egypte. Les Egyptiens ne v&#233;n&#232;rent pas moins de 80 principaux dieux ou d&#233;esses. La plupart des dieux &#233;gyptiens ont forme humaine, mais certains ont l'apparence d'un animal et d'autres combinent les deux formes, tels qu'un humain avec une t&#234;te de faucon. L'un des aspects particuliers de cette religion est la croyance en des dieux anim&#233;s de besoins vitaux et ayant besoin de se nourrir et s'abreuver comme les humains. Boisson et nourriture leur sont servies par les pr&#234;tres &#224; l'occasion de rituels quotidiens dans les temples des dieux. La statue du dieu, appel&#233;e "image", est baign&#233;e et nourrie plusieurs fois par jour par les pr&#234;tres avec des rituels sacr&#233;s. En r&#233;compense de cette attention, les dieux prot&#233;gent les Egyptiens. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]L'&#233;tat et la religion sont &#233;troitement li&#233;s dans l'ancienne Egypte. Le pharaon n'est pas seulement consid&#233;r&#233; comme le premier des pr&#234;tres, mais aussi comme un dieu vivant. M&#234;me si la plupart des c&#233;r&#233;monies religieuses se d&#233;roulent sous la responsabilit&#233; des pr&#234;tres et non du pharaon, l'autorit&#233; de celui-ci n'est pas remise en question et de gigantesques tombeaux requ&#233;rant une force de travail fabuleuse sont &#233;difi&#233;s comme derni&#232;res demeures pour ces rois. La religion &#233;gyptienne est un culte auquel le commun des mortels n'a pas le droit de participer, en dehors des c&#233;l&#233;brations publiques. Certes, l'Egypte compte de nombreux petits sanctuaires qui peuvent &#234;tre fr&#233;quent&#233;s par le peuple, mais le culte central est strictement interdit et l'acc&#232;s aux temples tr&#232;s restreint. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Durant les derniers si&#232;cles avant la conqu&#234;te romaine de l'Egypte, la religion commence &#224; subir l'influence de divinit&#233;s &#233;trang&#232;res. Un certain nombre de variantes se d&#233;veloppent &#224; partir de pratiques hell&#233;niques, compliquant encore un culte d&#233;j&#224; tr&#232;s h&#233;t&#233;rog&#232;ne. Et, comme ce sera le cas pour de nombreux autres cultes anciens, l'&#233;mergence du Christianisme et de l'Islam scelle le sort final de la religion &#233;gyptienne.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Der alt&#228;gyptische Glaube war nach heutigem Verst&#228;ndnis nicht wirklich eine Religion, sondern eine Mischung aus Kulten und Ritualen, kombiniert mit einer gemeinschaftlichen Weltanschauung. Es gab weder eine einheitliche theologische Lehre noch kanonische Schriften zur &#228;gyptischen Religion. Vielmehr basierte sie auf einem vielf&#228;ltigen rituellen Zusammenspiel zwischen den G&#246;ttern und ihren Anh&#228;ngern, den &#228;gyptischen Priestern, das sich &#252;ber einen sehr langen Zeitraum hinweg entwickelt hatte. Diese &#228;gyptische Glaubensform datiert mindestens auf das Jahr 3000 vor Christus zur&#252;ck, wenn nicht sogar noch fr&#252;her. Sie repr&#228;sentierte eine Mischung aus Wissenschaft, Gesetzgebung und Philosophie, die gemeinschaftlich im gleichen Rahmensystem angewandt wurden. F&#252;r einen &#196;gypter w&#228;re es somit unm&#246;glich gewesen, die Religion au&#223;en vor zu lassen. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Gem&#228;&#223; der &#228;gyptischen Mythologie existierte vor der eigentlichen Sch&#246;pfung ausschlie&#223;lich das Meer. Der Sonnengott Ra (auch Re genannt) soll einem Ei entschl&#252;pft sein und die anderen G&#246;tter geboren haben, die dann zu Himmel, Erde, dem Reich der Toten etc. geworden sein sollen. Der wichtigste Mythos der &#228;gyptischen Religion beschreibt den Mord an Osiris, seine Wiedererweckung sowie die Rache, die sein Sohn Horus an seinem M&#246;rder nahm. Diese Geschichte erkl&#228;rte nicht nur den Lauf der Natur, sondern diente auch der Hervorhebung der Bedeutung der k&#246;niglichen Herrschaft f&#252;r &#196;gypten. Laut der &#220;berlieferungen war die &#228;gyptische Religion polytheistisch und an sage und schreibe 80 bedeutenden G&#246;ttern und G&#246;ttinnen orientiert. Diese waren zumeist menschlicher Gestalt, manche nahmen jedoch auch Tiergestalt an und andere erschienen in einer Kombination aus beidem, zum Beispiel mit einem menschlichen K&#246;rper und dem Kopf eines Schakals. Ein ungew&#246;hnliches Merkmal der &#228;gyptischen Religion war die Annahme, dass die G&#246;tter wie die Menschen Nahrung und Getr&#228;nke brauchten, welche die Priester ihnen tagt&#228;glich in den Tempeln darboten: Die Statue der Gottheit, das so genannte Abbild, wurde im Rahmen der von den Priestern abgehaltenen geheiligten Rituale gebadet, gesalbt und mehrfach am Tag verk&#246;stigt, damit die G&#246;tter &#252;ber die &#196;gypter wachen und Schaden von ihnen fernhalten mochten. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Staat und Religion waren in der Antike in &#196;gypten untrennbar miteinander verbunden. Der Pharao wurde nicht nur als Hohepriester der &#228;gyptischen Religion betrachtet, sondern auch als die Personifizierung eines Gottes. Obwohl es die Priester waren, die den gr&#246;&#223;ten Teil der religi&#246;sen Zeremonien abhielten, und nicht der Pharao, war dessen Macht unumstritten. Aus diesem Grund wurde ihm auch in einem ungeheuren Arbeitsaufwand ein massiver Tempel als letzte Ruhest&#228;tte errichtet. Wie bereits erw&#228;hnt, war die &#228;gyptische Religion eher eine Art Kult, an dem die "normale" Bev&#246;lkerung, abgesehen von den &#246;ffentlichen Veranstaltungen, normalerweise nicht teilhaben durfte. Trotzdem gab es in ganz &#196;gypten viele kleine Schreine, die m&#246;glicherweise auch vom gemeinen Volk besucht wurden, doch der Hauptkult war tabu und der Zutritt zu den bedeutenden Tempeln stark eingeschr&#228;nkt. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]In den letzten Jahrhunderten vor der Eroberung &#196;gyptens durch die R&#246;mer wurde die &#228;gyptische Religion zunehmend von fremdl&#228;ndischen Gottheiten beeinflusst. Es entwickelten sich verschiedene Varianten, die vor allem auf den Praktiken der alten Griechen gr&#252;ndeten, wodurch sich die Struktur dieser ohnehin schon heterogenen Glaubensrichtung noch weiter verkomplizierte. Mit dem Aufkommen des Christentums und des Islams verschwand die traditionelle &#228;gyptische Religion sp&#228;ter immer mehr aus dem Blickfeld und ist heute g&#228;nzlich erloschen. </German>
		<Italian>[TAB]L'antica religione egizia in effetti non &#232; una religione come siamo abituati a pensarla, ma piuttosto una sovrapposizione di culti e riti che avevano in comune una certa visione del mondo. Non esistevano scritti canonici o una teologia unificante, ma solo una serie di interazioni ritualistiche tra le divinit&#224; e i loro seguaci, ossia i sacerdoti egizi, sviluppatasi nel corso di un lunghissimo periodo. La religione egizia infatti &#232; molto antica e risale ad almeno al 3000 a.C. e forse anche prima. Essa era un misto di scienza, legge e filosofia operanti all'interno di una stessa cornice: sarebbe stato impossibile per un egizio vivere al di fuori della religione. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Secondo la mitologia egizia, prima della creazione esisteva solo il mare. Il dio-sole, Ra (o Re) nacque da un uovo. Da lui nacquero altre divinit&#224;, che poi diventarono il cielo, la terra, la terra dei morti, ecc. Il mito pi&#249; importante della religione egizia narra la storia della morte e della rinascita di Osiride e la vendetta di suo figlio Horus nei confronti dell'assassino. La storia non solo spiegava il ciclo della natura, ma sottolineava anche l'importanza della dinastia sovrana per l'Egitto. Come pu&#242; capirsi dalla leggenda, la religione egizia era politeistica e comprendeva circa 80 fra dei e dee. Essi avevano per lo pi&#249; un aspetto umano, ma alcuni assumevano la forma di animali o un aspetto misto (es. corpo da uomo con testa di sciacallo). Una caratteristica inusuale della religione egizia era che le divinit&#224; avevano bisogno di cibo e bevande per sopravvivere, cose che erano loro fornite dai sacerdoti in riti che avevano luogo nei templi dedicati alle divinit&#224;. La statua della divinit&#224;, nota come la sua immagine, veniva lavata e unta e "nutrita" pi&#249; volte al giorno. In cambio, la divinit&#224; proteggeva l'Egitto da mali e calamit&#224;. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Stato e religione erano connessi inestricabilmente nell'antico Egitto. Il faraone era non solo il pi&#249; alto sacerdote egizio, ma anche una divinit&#224; vivente in terra. Anche se la maggior parte delle cerimonie era compiuta dai sacerdoti e non dal faraone, il suo potere non era messo in dubbio e per custodire il sonno eterno del sovrano venivano eretti templi che richiedevano enormi quantit&#224; di forza lavoro. Si &#232; gi&#224; detto che la religione egizia era un culto al quale la popolazione ordinaria non aveva il permesso di partecipare, feste pubbliche a parte. Sparsi per l'Egitto vi erano numerosi piccoli santuari frequentati dalla gente, ma l'accesso di questa ai templi e al culto principale era notevolmente ridotto. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Nei secoli precedenti la conquista romana dell'Egitto, la religione egizia cominci&#242; a essere influenzata da culti stranieri. Nacquero diverse varianti per via dell'influenza della religione ellenica, col risultato di complicare una religione gi&#224; abbastanza eterogenea. La religione egizia tradizionale spar&#236; pi&#249; tardi con l'avvento del cristianesimo e dell'islam e oggi &#232; una religione morta. </Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]La religi&#243;n del antiguo Egipto no era realmente una religi&#243;n en el sentido en que nosotros lo entendemos hoy d&#237;a, sino una combinaci&#243;n de cultos y rituales que compart&#237;an una visi&#243;n del mundo. No exist&#237;a un cuerpo teol&#243;gico unificador ni unas escrituras can&#243;nicas. Se basaba en una serie de interacciones entre los dioses y sus adoradores, los sacerdotes egipcios, desarrolladas a lo largo de mucho tiempo. La religi&#243;n era muy antigua. Se remonta como m&#237;nimo hasta el 3000 a. C., y es posible que a&#250;n m&#225;s. Estaba formada por una mezcla de ciencia, derecho y filosof&#237;a que actuaban bajo una misma estructura; un egipcio nunca habr&#237;a podido escapar a su religi&#243;n. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Seg&#250;n la mitolog&#237;a egipcia, antes de la creaci&#243;n solo exist&#237;a el mar. El dios del sol (Ra) naci&#243; de un huevo y los dem&#225;s dioses, engendrados por &#233;l, se convirtieron en el cielo, la tierra, el pa&#237;s de los muertos, etc. El mito m&#225;s importante de la religi&#243;n egipcia cuenta la historia del asesinato y renacimiento de Osiris y de la venganza cobrada por Horus, su hijo. Adem&#225;s de explicar el ciclo de la naturaleza, esta historia serv&#237;a para recalcar el car&#225;cter divino de la realeza en Egipto.  Seg&#250;n indican las leyendas, la religi&#243;n egipcia era de naturaleza polite&#237;sta y contaba con un total de ochenta dioses y diosas principales. En su mayor parte, los dioses ten&#237;an forma humana, pero algunos de ellos adoptaban forma de animales y otros una combinaci&#243;n de ambas, como por ejemplo un cuerpo humano con cabeza de chacal. Una caracter&#237;stica poco habitual de la religi&#243;n egipcia era que sus practicantes pensaban que los dioses necesitaban comida y bebida, igual que si fueran seres humanos, y los sacerdotes se encargaban de cubrir estas necesidades en rituales diarios realizados en los templos. La estatua de la deidad, conocida como imagen, era ba&#241;ada y alimentada muchas veces a lo largo del d&#237;a. A cambio de este cuidado, los dioses vigilaban y proteg&#237;an a los egipcios. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Estado y religi&#243;n estaban unidos indisolublemente en el antiguo Egipto. Se consideraba que el fara&#243;n no era tan solo el sumo sacerdote de la religi&#243;n egipcia, sino adem&#225;s un dios que caminaba entre los mortales. Aunque eran los sacerdotes, y no el fara&#243;n, los que realizaban la mayor parte de las ceremonias religiosas, el poder de &#233;ste era incuestionable y se levantaban enormes templos (que requer&#237;an el trabajo de gran cantidad de hombres) como &#250;ltima morada para &#233;l. Como ya hemos dicho, la religi&#243;n egipcia era un tipo de culto del que el pueblo no participaba m&#225;s all&#225; de ciertos rituales p&#250;blicos. Exist&#237;an muchos peque&#241;os santuarios por todo Egipto y es muy posible que el pueblo acudiera a ellos, pero la parte principal del culto estaba estrictamente prohibida y el acceso a los templos principales, severamente restringido. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]En los siglos que precedieron a la conquista de Egipto por parte de los romanos, la religi&#243;n empez&#243; a recibir influencias extranjeras. Se desarrollaron diferentes variedades basadas en las pr&#225;cticas helen&#237;sticas, lo que contribuy&#243; a complicar a&#250;n m&#225;s una religi&#243;n ya de por s&#237; heterog&#233;nea. M&#225;s adelante, con el ascenso de cristianismo e islamismo, la religi&#243;n desaparecer&#237;a y en nuestros d&#237;as ya no existe. </Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Temple -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_TEMPLE</Tag>
		<English>Kemetic Temple of Amun</English>
		<French>Temple d'Amon</French>
		<German>Amun-Tempel</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In Civilization IV, a temple is defined as a building where the faithful come to worship. Christians call their temples "churches," while Muslims call theirs "mosques," and Jews call theirs, simply, "temples." Temples are far more common than cathedrals, but much less large and ornate. Even the smallest village can possess a temple.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_TEMPLE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Cathedral -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
		<English>Kemetic Cathedral of Mut</English>
		<French>Temple de Mut</French>
		<German>Mut-Tempel</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In Civilization IV, a cathedral is defined as an especially large and ornate religious building where the faithful worship. Only the most prosperous cities can afford to create pantheons, as they require huge amounts of raw material and years of dedicated labor by skilled craftsmen.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_CATHEDRAL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Monastry -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_MONASTERY</Tag>
		<English>Kemetic Monastry of Chons</English>
		<French>Temple de Chons</French>
		<German>Chons-Tempel</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Chons is an ancient lunar deity, from before formal structure was given to a pantheon. His name reflects the fact that the Moon (referred to as Iah in Egyptian) travels across the night sky, for it means The Wanderer, and also had the titles Embracer, Pathfinder, and Defender, as he was thought to watch over night travelers. As the god of light in the night, Chons was invoked to protect against wild animals, increase male virility, and to aid with healing. It was said that when Chons caused the crescent moon to shine, women conceived, cattle became fertile, and all nostrils and every throat was filled with fresh air. can also be understood to mean king's placenta, and consequently in early times, he was considered to slay the king's (i.e. the pharaoh's) enemies, and extract their innards for the king's use, metaphorically creating something resembling a placenta for the king. This bloodthirsty aspect leads him to be referred to, in such as the Pyramid texts, as the (one who) lives on hearts. He also became associated with more literal placentas, becoming seen as a deification of the royal placenta, and so a god involved with childbirth.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_MONASTERY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Shrine (Karnak)  -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Kemetic Shrine (Karnak Temple Complex)</English>
		<French>Le Complexe de Temples de Karnak</French>
		<German>Der Tempelkomplex von Karnak</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Karnak temple complex, universally known only as Karnak, describes a vast conglomeration of temples, chapels, pylons and other buildings. [PARAGRAPH:1]By the Eleventh Dynasty, the Theban kings had become rulers of all Egypt, and the tribal god of the region (Amun) consequently increased in power and wealth, gradually being merged with the sun god Re, to become Amun-Re. The White Chapel of Senusret I and the Middle Kingdom court are the earliest remains of buildings within the temple area. [PARAGRAPH:1]Major construction work took place during the Eighteenth dynasty. Thutmose I erected an enclosure wall connecting the Fourth and Fifth pylons, which comprise the earliest part of the temple still standing in situ. They contain fourteen papyrus columns and the two obelisks of Hatshepsut, which were later hidden from view by walls set up by Thutmose III. Under Hatshepsut and Thutmose III, another enclosure wall fortified with towers was erected, and the nearby Sacred Lake was either constructed or enlarged. During the reign of Thutmose III, the main temple itself was extended by 50% with the addition of a building called the Akh-menu ("the most glorious of monuments"), now know as the Festival Hall of Thutmose III, which is seemingly decorated to echo a huge tent shrine, complete with awnings and tent poles. In this temple, the Karnak king list, shows Thutmose III with some of the earlier kings that built parts of the temple complex. After a brief period of interruption during the Amarna period, when the Egyptian capital was moved to Akhetaten, construction resumed at Karnak under Tutankhamun and Horemheb. The Ninth pylon was erected along the southern axis using material known as talatat from the now demolished Akhetaten. Construction of the Hypostyle Hall may have also began during the eighteenth dynasty, though most building was undertaken under Seti I and Ramesses II. Merenptah commemorated his victories over the Sea Peoples on the walls of the Cachette Court, the start of the processional route to the Luxor Temple. This Great Inscription (which has now lost about a third of its content) shows the king's campaigns and eventual return with booty and prisoners. Next to this enscription is the Victory Stela, which is largely a copy of the more famous Israel Stela, which was found on the West Bank funerary complex of Merenptah. Merenptah's son Seti II added 2 small obelisks in front of the Second Pylon, and a triple bark-shrine to the north of the processional avenue in the same area. This was constructed of sandstone, with a chapel to Amun flanked by those of Mut and Khonsu.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_SHRINE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Wonder (Isis) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_ISIS</Tag>
		<English>Kemetic Wonder (Temple of Isis)</English>
		<French>Temple d'Isis</French>
		<German>Isis-Tempel</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_ISIS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Isis Is the wife and sister of Osiris and the mother of Horus (Heru). Isis was worshipped as the archetypal wife and mother. Her name literally means "she of throne", that is, "Queen of the throne", which was portrayed by the emblem worn on her head, that of a throne. However, the hieroglyph of her name originally meant "she of flesh", i.e. mortal, and she may simply have represented deified, historical queens. She is also known as the goddess of magic and healing and the goddess from who all Beginnings arose, and was also known as the Lady of bread, of beer and of green fields. Ancient Egyptians believed that the Nile flooded every year because of her tears of sorrow for her dead husband, Osiris. He was killed by her other evil brother, Set, god of chaos and destruction. Set sliced Osiris into bits and flung them into the Nile River, letting the animals eat the remains of his body. However, all the pieces survived, except for his phallus.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_ISIS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build this to increase the health of your cities</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Wonder (Osiris) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_OSIRIS</Tag>
		<English>Kemetic Wonder (Temple of Osiris)</English>
		<French>Temple d'Osiris</French>
		<German>Osiris-Tempel</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_OSIRIS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Osiris is the Egyptian god of life, death, and fertility. Osiris was not only the redeemer and merciful judge of the dead in the afterlife, but also the underworld agency that granted all life, including sprouting vegetation and the fertile flooding of the Nile River. The Kings of Egypt were associated with Osiris in death as Osiris rose from the dead they would, in union with him, inherit eternal life through a process of imitative magic. By the New Kingdom all people, not just pharaohs, were believed to be associated with Osiris at death if they incurred the costs of the assimilation rituals.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_OSIRIS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build this to increase the growth of your cities</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Wonder (Ptah) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_PTAH</Tag>
		<English>Kemetic Wonder (Temple of Ptah)</English>
		<French>Temple de Ptah</French>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Tempio di Ptah</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_PTAH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Ptah was the ancient Egyptian god of scribes ,craftsmen and architects. In art, he is shown as a bearded mummified man, often wearing a skull cap, holding a djed. He was believed to be married to Sekhmet.</English>
		<Italian>[TAB]Ptah era l'antico dio egizio degli scribi, degli artigiani e degli architetti. Nell'arte veniva rappresentato come un uomo mummificato barbuto, spesso indossando un berretto cranico, brandendo un djed. Si riteneva che fosse sposato con Sekhmet.</Italian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_PTAH_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build the Temple of Ptah to increase the production of your cities craftsmen.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Wonder (Set) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_SET</Tag>
		<English>Kemetic Wonder (Temple of Set)</English>
		<French>Temple de Set</French>
		<German>Seth-Tempel</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_SET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Set (also spelled Seth, Sutekh or Seteh) is an ancient god, who was originally the god of the desert, storms, and chaos. Set was viewed as immensely powerful, and was regarded consequently as the chief god. Set carried the epithet, "His Majesty", shared only with Ra. Another common epithet was, of great of strength, and in one of the Pyramid Texts it states that the king's strength is that of Set. As chief god, he was patron of Upper Egypt (in the South- upstream), where he was worshiped, most notably at Ombos. Set was regarded as a fierce warrior. It was he who protected Ra on the solar barque, slaying the chaos serpent, Apep each day to allow the sun to rise. Combined with an association with the destructive and irresistible power of storms and the desert, Set became the patron deity of soldiers, who often wore Set amulets, hoping to acquire similar destructive force, or Set's infinite protection.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_SET_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build this when you embark on wars as it reduces war weariness and increases GG point generation</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Wonder (Thoth) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_THOTH</Tag>
		<English>Kemetic Wonder (Temple of Thoth)</English>
		<French>Temple de Toth</French>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Tempio di Toth</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_THOTH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Thoth, was considered one of the more important deities of the Egyptian pantheon, often depicted with the head of an Ibis.He was considered the heart and tongue of Ra as well as the means by which Ra's will was translated into speech. In the Egyptian mythology, he has played many vital and prominent roles, including being one of the two deities (the other being Ma'at) who stood on either side of Ra's boat. He has further been involved in arbitration, magic, writing, science,and the judging of the dead.</English>
		<Italian>[TAB]Toth era considerato una delle più importanti divinità del pantheon egizio, spesso raffigurato con la testa di un Ibis. Era considerato il cuore e la lingua di Ra, così come il mezzo con cui la volontà di Ra veniva trasformata in parole. Nella mitologia egizia, ha giocato molti ruoli vitali e importanti, tra cui l'essere una delle due divinità (l'altra era Ma'at) che stavano ai lati della barca di Ra. E' stato inoltre coinvolto negli arbitrati, nella magia, nella scrittura, nella scienza, e nel giudizio dei morti.</Italian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KEMETIC_WONDER_TEMPLE_OF_THOTH_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build the Temple of Thoth to get a boost to research in all your cities.</English>
		<Italian>Costruisci il tempio di Toth per ottenere un bonus alla ricerca in tutte le tue città.</Italian>
	</TEXT>

<!-- ++++ Nagualism +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Religion Details -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_NAGUALISM</Tag>
		<English>Nagualism</English>
		<French>Nagualisme</French>
		<German>Nagualismus</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_NAGUALISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Maya, Zapotec, Mixtec, and Aztec religions all had a concept of a vital force that separated living from nonliving matter. For the Maya this was expressed in the concept of "ik," or wind, breath, or life. For the Zapotecs it was "pee" or wind, breath, or spirit. For the Mixtec it was "yni" or "ini" or spirit, heart, or heat. For the Aztec it was "tona" or vital energy, or heat. As animists, the line drawn as to what was alive, was different from the Judeo-Christian tradition. They attributed life to many things which the Spaniards, for example, did not. The idea of human sacrifice was one of the more notable shared concepts of these religions which were concerned with keeping the cosmos in balance through human action. </English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Temple (Quetzalcoatl) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_TEMPLE</Tag>
		<English>Nagualistic Temple (Temple of Quetzalcoatl)</English>
		<French>Temple de Quetzalcoatl</French>
		<German>Quetzalcoatl-Tempel</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In Civilization IV, a temple is defined as a building where the faithful come to worship. Christians call their temples "churches," while Muslims call theirs "mosques," and Jews call theirs, simply, "temples." Temples are far more common than cathedrals, but much less large and ornate. Even the smallest village can possess a temple.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_TEMPLE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Temples[COLOR_REVERT] increase a city's happiness and culture. They are especially useful for expanding your civilization's borders during the early game.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Cathedral (Temple of Tlaloc) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
		<English>Nagualistic Cathedral (Temple of Tlaloc)</English>
		<French>Temple de Tlaloc</French>
		<German>Tlaloc-Tempel</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_CATHEDRAL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In Civilization IV, a religious pyramid is defined as an especially large and ornate religious building where the faithful worship. Only the most prosperous cities can afford to create pyramids, as they require huge amounts of raw material and years of dedicated labor by skilled craftsmen.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Monastry (Calmacec) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_MONASTERY</Tag>
		<English>Nagualistic Monastry (Calmacec)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_MONASTERY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Shrine (Teotihuacan) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Nagualistic Shrine (Teotihuacan)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Aztecs believed Teotihuacan was where the Sun had been created and that the city was built by the gods.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_SHRINE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Wonder (Pyramid of the Magician) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_WONDER_MAGICIAN_PYRAMID</Tag>
		<English>Nagualistic Wonder (Pyramid of the Magician)</English>
		<French>Pyramide du Mage</French>
		<German>Pyramide des Magiers</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_WONDER_MAGICIAN_PYRAMID_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Pyramid of the Magician is a Mesoamerican step pyramid located in the ancient, Pre-Columbian city of Uxmal, Mexico. The structure is also referred to as the Pyramid of the Dwarf, Casa el Adivino, and the Pyramid of the Soothsayer. The pyramid is the tallest and most recognizable structure in Uxmal.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NAGUALISTIC_WONDER_MAGICIAN_PYRAMID_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Taoism +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Cathedral (Pagoda) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAOIST_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
		<English>Taoist Cathedral (Pagoda)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Pagode tao&#239;ste</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Taoistische Pagode</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Pagoda Taoista:Pagode Taoiste</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Pagoda tao&#237;sta:Pagodas tao&#237;stas</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Shrine (The Dai Miao) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAOIST_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Taoist Shrine (The Dai Miao)</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Daimiao</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Dai Miao</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Il Dai Miao</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Dai Miao</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Zoroastrianism +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Religion Details -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_ZOROASTRIANISM</Tag>
		<English>Zoroastrianism</English>
		<French>Zoroastrisme</French>
		<German>Zoroastrismus</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_ZOROASTRIANISM_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Zoroastrian</English>
		<French>Zoroastrien</French>
		<German>Zoroastrismusn</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_ZOROASTRIANISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Zoroastrianism was founded by Zarathushtra (Zoroaster) in Persia which followed an aboriginal polytheistic religion at the time. He preached what may have been the first monotheism with a single supreme god, Ahura Mazda. Zoroastrians belief in the dualism of good and evil as either a cosmic one between Ahura Mazda and an evil spirit of violence and death, Angra Mainyu, or as an ethical dualism within the human consciousness. The Zoroastrian holy book is called the Avesta which includes the teachings of Zarathushtra written in a series of five hymns called the Gathas. They are abstract sacred poetry directed towards the worship of the One God, understanding of righteousness and cosmic order, promotion of social justice, and individual choice between good and evil. The rest of the Avesta was written at a later date and deals with rituals, practice of worship, and other traditions of the faith.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Bien que le zoroastrisme soit peu connu de nos jours, c'est l'une des religions qui a le plus influenc&#233; l'histoire du monde. Zarathushtra, ou Zoroastre en Occident, est le proph&#232;te de cette ancienne religion de l'empire perse. Le zoroastrisme pr&#233;sente certains &#233;l&#233;ments du monoth&#233;isme, mais est &#233;galement une religion dualiste. L'univers aurait &#233;t&#233; cr&#233; par un &#234;tre de lumi&#232;re supr&#234;me du nom d'Ahura Mazda, oppos&#233; &#224; une cr&#233;ature des t&#233;n&#232;bres du nom d'Angra Mainyu. Le symbole le plus important de la foi zoroastrienne est le feu, car il repr&#233;sente la lumi&#232;re et la chaleur d'Ahura Mazda, mais &#233;galement la puret&#233;. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Les &#233;rudits ne s'accordent pas pr&#233;cis&#233;ment sur l'&#233;poque &#224; laquelle v&#233;cut Zoroastre, mais la situent entre l'an 1000 av. J.-C. et l'an 600 av. J.-C.. Les dates exactes de sa naissance et de sa mort restent un myst&#232;re, mais le zoroastrisme existe d&#233;j&#224; lorsque Cyrus II &#233;rige l'empire perse au cours du VIe si&#232;cle av. J.-C.. Selon la l&#233;gende zoroastrienne, Zoroastre se d&#233;marque comme un &#234;tre particulier d&#232;s sa naissance, et des esprits mal&#233;fiques tentent &#224; plusieurs reprises de le tuer au cours de son enfance. A l'&#226;ge de 20 ans, Zoroastre se retire dans une grotte et y passe les sept ann&#233;es qui suivent &#224; m&#233;diter. Une fois qu'il ressent que sa d&#233;votion envers Ahura Mazda a atteint son apog&#233;e, Zoroastre d&#233;cide de partir r&#233;pandre la bonne parole, sans grand succ&#232;s au d&#233;part. Son tout premier fid&#232;le est converti lorsqu'il parvient par miracle &#224; gu&#233;rir le cheval du roi Vishtaspa, qui apporte alors le soutien dont Zoroastre a tant besoin pour pr&#234;cher sa religion qui s'&#233;tend ensuite rapidement. Avant que les Grecs ne rencontrent les Perses et commencent &#224; &#233;crire sur ce peuple, le zoroastrisme s'est r&#233;pandu dans tout l'empire perse et dans une grande partie du Proche-Orient. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Les zoroastriens pensent que le monde est fondamentalement un endroit bienfaisant cr&#233; par Ahura Mazda pour les hommes, mais qu'il s'agit &#233;galement d'un champ de bataille qui voit s'affronter les forces du bien et du mal. Les zoroastriens ne croient pas en la pr&#233;destination et accordent beaucoup d'importance aux choix que chaque individu doit faire afin de repousser les tentations et les corruptions d'Angra Mainyu. Les bonnes actions comme les mauvaises seront r&#233;compens&#233;es apr&#232;s la mort, et les &#234;tres malfaisants seront jug&#233;s et envoy&#233;s en enfer, m&#234;me si &#224; la fin des temps, ils seront purifi&#233;s pour rejoindre Ahura Mazda. Les zoroastriens ne reconnaissent aucun autre dieu qu'Ahura Mazda, mais ce dernier est repr&#233;sent&#233; de diff&#233;rentes fa&#231;ons, souvent d&#233;peint sous une forme ang&#233;lique, et porte des noms tels que Vohu Manah (la Bonne pens&#233;e) et Asha (la V&#233;rit&#233;). Le livre saint du zoroastrisme est l'Avesta. Il r&#233;unit toutes les traditions orales transcrites pour la premi&#232;re fois sous la dynastie perse des Sassanides. On pense qu'une petite partie de l'Avesta, un ensemble de po&#232;mes connus comme les Gathas, a &#233;t&#233; r&#233;dig&#233;e par Zoroastre en personne. Les temples zoroastriens sont con&#231;us de mani&#232;re &#224; pr&#233;server le feu sacr&#233;, symbole de la lumi&#232;re et de l'&#233;clat d'Ahura Mazda. Les zoroastriens accordent &#233;galement une grande importance &#224; la propret&#233;. C'est pourquoi ils doivent suivre plusieurs rites de purification &#224; chaque p&#233;ch&#233; commis. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Le zoroastrisme est historiquement la religion de l'empire perse, bien qu'elle ne soit pas officiellement encourag&#233;e par les empereurs perses avant la dynastie des Sassanides au IIIe si&#232;cle de notre &#232;re. Cette religion croise le juda&#239;sme au cours de la captivit&#233;[NEWLINE]babylonienne au VIe si&#232;cle av. J.-C.. Plusieurs &#233;l&#233;ments laissent &#224; penser que les deux religions se sont influenc&#233;es mutuellement (concepts du monoth&#233;isme, du paradis et de l'enfer, de l'eschatologie...). On pense &#233;galement, mais sans certitude, que les trois hommes sages de la naissance du Christ &#233;taient des mages zoroastriens (pr&#234;tres). Au VIIe si&#232;cle, lorsque les Arabes envahissent et d&#233;truisent l'empire perse, le zoroastrisme devient une religion pers&#233;cut&#233;e et dispara&#238;t progressivement. Un petit nombre de zoroastriens fuient en Inde, o&#249; ils cr&#233;ent une nouvelle communaut&#233; connue sous le nom de Parsis. La population des zoroastriens est aujourd'hui estim&#233;e entre 2 et 3 millions de personnes, principalement en Inde, au Pakistan et en Iran, mais est &#233;galement pr&#233;sente dans les principaux centres urbains anglophones de la plan&#232;te.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Auch wenn bis heute nur wenig &#252;ber den Zarathustrismus bekannt ist, z&#228;hlt er doch zu den einflussreichsten Religionen der Weltgeschichte. Von dem Propheten Zarathustra (im griechischen Sprachraum Zoroaster genannt) begr&#252;ndet, wurde diese Glaubensrichtung in der Antike im Persischen Reich praktiziert. Der Zarathustrismus beinhaltet zwar einige monotheistische Elemente, ist aber im Wesentlichen eine dualistische Religion, denn sie besagt, dass das Universum von Ahura Masda, dem Gott des Lichts, erschaffen wurde, dem ein Gott der Finsternis namens Angra Mainyu gegen&#252;bersteht. Das wichtigste Symbol des zarathustrischen Glaubens ist das Feuer, welches das Licht und den gl&#228;nzenden Schein des Ahura Masda repr&#228;sentiert und f&#252;r Reinheit steht. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Wann genau Zarathustra gelebt hat, ist unter Historikern umstritten, man schr&#228;nkt den Zeitraum allerdings von etwa 1000 bis 600 vor Christus ein. Unabh&#228;ngig von seinen exakten Geburts- und Todesdaten ist jedoch belegt, dass der Zarathustrismus bereits bei der Gr&#252;ndung des Persischen Reiches durch Kyros II. im 6. Jahrhundert vor Christus existierte. &#220;berlieferungen zufolge soll Zarathustra schon von Geburt an ein besonderer Mensch gewesen sein, der in seiner Kindheit zahlreiche Anschl&#228;ge auf sein Leben &#252;berstanden haben soll, die b&#246;se Geister auf in ver&#252;bten. Im Alter von etwa 20 Jahren zog sich Zarathustra in die Einsamkeit zur&#252;ck und verbrachte die darauf folgenden sieben Jahre in Meditation. Als er schlie&#223;lich vollkommene Hingebung zu Ahura Masda versp&#252;rte, machte er sich auf den Weg, um seine &#220;berzeugungen unter das Volk zu bringen, zun&#228;chst jedoch erfolglos. Erst nachdem er auf wundersame Weise das Pferd des K&#246;nigs Vistaspa geheilt hatte, der sich daraufhin h&#246;chstpers&#246;nlich zu Zarathustras Lehren bekannte, wuchs seine Anh&#228;ngerschaft und seine Religion wurde zunehmend popul&#228;rer. Zu der Zeit, als die Griechen erstmals auf die Perser stie&#223;en und schriftliche Aufzeichnungen &#252;ber sie verfassten, war der Zarathustrismus bereits im ganzen Persischen Reich und auch in gro&#223;en Teilen des Nahen Ostens etabliert. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Die Anh&#228;nger des Zarathustrismus vertreten die Auffassung, dass die Welt im Grunde ein guter Ort ist, den Ahura Masda f&#252;r die Menschen erschaffen hat, aber auch eine Art Schlachtfeld f&#252;r die Kr&#228;fte des Guten und des B&#246;sen. Sie glauben nicht an die Vorbestimmung, sondern sind &#252;berzeugt, dass jeder Einzelne eine Wahl treffen muss, um der Versuchung und Manipulation durch Angra Mainyu zu entgehen. Gute und b&#246;se Taten werden nach dem Tod gleicherma&#223;en bewertet, wobei alles &#220;bel verurteilt und zur H&#246;lle geschickt wird, doch am Ende der Zeit wird auch das B&#246;se gel&#228;utert werden und sich wieder Ahura Masda zuwenden. Der Zarathustrismus erkennt keinen anderen Gott an als Ahura Masda, der verschiedene Erscheinungsformen annehmen kann, h&#228;ufig die von engels&#228;hnlichen Wesen mit Namen wie Vohu Manah (guter Gedanke) und Asha (Wahrheit). Das Awesta, das Heilige Buch des zarathustrischen Glaubens, enth&#228;lt die urspr&#252;nglich m&#252;ndlichen &#220;berlieferungen, die w&#228;hrend der Sassaniden-Periode in Persien schriftlich niedergelegt wurden. Ein kleiner Teil des Awestas, eine Reihe von Hymnen bzw. Liedern, die so genannten Gathas, sollen von Zarathustra selbst verfasst worden sein. Der Hauptzweck der zarathustrischen Tempel ist die Bewahrung des heiligen Feuers, welches das Licht und den Glanz des Ahura Masda symbolisiert. Auch die Reinheit spielt im zarathustrischen Glauben eine sehr wichtige Rolle. So m&#252;ssen die Gl&#228;ubigen verschiedene Reinigungsrituale durchlaufen, wenn sie ges&#252;ndigt haben. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Aus historischer Sicht war der Zarathustrismus die Hauptreligion im Persischen Reich, offiziell wurde sie jedoch erst w&#228;hrend der Sassaniden-Periode im 3. Jahrhundert nach Christus von den persischen Kaisern gef&#246;rdert. Ein erstes Aufeinandertreffen des Zarathustrismus und des j&#252;dischen Glaubens fand w&#228;hrend der babylonischen Besatzungszeit im 6. Jahrhundert vor Christus statt und vieles weist darauf hin, dass sich die beiden Religionen in der Folge gegenseitig beeinflussten (&#228;hnliche monotheistische Pr&#228;gung, Himmel und H&#246;lle, Eschatologie etc.). Es gibt kaum einen Zweifel daran, dass auch die drei Weisen, die bei der Geburt Jesu Christi anwesend waren, zarathustrische Magi (Priester) gewesen sind. Nach der Verw&#252;stung und Zerst&#246;rung des Persischen Reiches durch die Araber im 7. Jahrhundert nach Christus wurden die Glaubensanh&#228;nger des Zarathustrismus verfolgt und so nahm die Popularit&#228;t dieser Religion immer mehr ab. Einige Gl&#228;ubige fl&#252;chteten nach Indien, wo sie eine neue Gemeinde gr&#252;ndeten und sich fortan Parsen nannten. Auch heute gibt es noch etwa 2-3 Millionen Menschen, die den Zarathustrismus praktizieren, vorwiegend in Indien, Pakistan, im Iran sowie vereinzelt auch in den Gro&#223;st&#228;dten der englischsprachigen Welt. </German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Anche se oggi &#232; poco noto, lo zoroastrismo &#232; stato una delle religioni pi&#249; influenti della storia. Esso fu la religione dell'antico Impero persiano e fu predicato dal profeta Zaratustra, noto in occidente come Zoroastro. Lo zoroastrismo contiene elementi di monoteismo ma &#232; in realt&#224; un culto dualistico: l'universo fu creato da un supremo essere di luce, Ahura Mazda, a cui si oppone l'essere supremo dell'oscurit&#224;, Angra Mainyu. Il simbolo pi&#249; importante della fede zoroastriana &#232; il fuoco, che simboleggia la luce e il calore di Ahura Mazda nonch&#233; la purezza. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Gli studiosi non sono d'accordo sull'esatta collocazione temporale di Zoroastro. Le date variano dal 1000 a.C. al 600 a.C. Anche se il periodo di vita del suo profeta &#232; incerto, lo zoroastrismo certamente esisteva gi&#224; quando Ciro fond&#242; l'Impero persiano nel VI secolo a.C. Secondo la tradizione zoroastriana, Zoroastro sarebbe stato riconosciuto come persona speciale sin dalla nascita e gli spiriti maligni avrebbero tentato pi&#249; volte di ucciderlo. All'et&#224; di venti anni, Zoroastro si ritir&#242; in una caverna e trascorse i sette anni successivi in meditazione. Dopo aver raggiunto la devozione pi&#249; completa per Ahura Mazda, Zoroastro vag&#242; per diffondere la fede, ma con scarsi successi iniziali: ottenne le prime conversioni alla sua fede solo quando riusc&#236; a guarire il cavallo del re Vishtaspa: da allora, il re support&#242; la religione e questa si diffuse rapidamente. Quando gli intellettuali Greci conobbero i Persiani e cominciarono a scrivere opere su di loro, lo zoroastrismo era ormai diffuso in tutta la Persia e il Vicino Oriente. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Lo zoroastrismo ritiene che il mondo sia sostanzialmente un bel posto creato per gli uomini da Ahura Mazda, ma anche che sia diventato il campo di battaglia tra le forze del bene e quelle del male. Gli zoroastriani non credono nella predestinazione e molta enfasi &#232; posta sulle scelte di ciascuno, che dovrebbero tendere a evitare la corruzione da parte di Angra Mainyu. Alle azioni in terra corrisponder&#224; un premio o una punizione nell'aldil&#224;: i malvagi saranno spediti all'inferno, anche se poi, alla fine dei tempi, tutti verranno purificati e si riuniranno ad Ahura Mazda. Gli zoroastriani non riconoscono altro dio al di fuori di Ahura Mazda, che per&#242; si manifesta in forme diverse, spesso angeliche, che assumono nomi quali Vohu Manah (Buon pensiero) e Asha (Verit&#224;). Il libro sacro del zoroastrismo &#232; l'Avesta, una raccolta delle tradizioni orali poi scritte al tempo della dinastia dei Sassanidi. Una piccola parte dell'Avesta, una serie di inni noti come Gatha, pare sia stata composta da Zoroastro in persona. I templi zoroastriani hanno la funzione di preservare il fuoco sacro, simbolo della luce e dello splendore di Ahura Mazda. Anche la pulizia &#232; importante e vi erano infatti diversi riti di purificazione da compiere dopo che si aveva peccato. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Lo zoroastrismo &#232; storicamente la religione della Persia, anche se gli imperatori persiani non lo promossero ufficialmente fino al III secolo d.C., durante la dinastia dei Sassanidi. Esso venne a contatto con il giudaismo durante la cattivit&#224; babilonese del VI secolo a.C. e sembrano esserci le prove che le due religioni si siano influenzate reciprocamente (condivisione dei concetti di monoteismo, di paradiso e inferno, dell'escatologia, ecc.). Pare quasi certo anzi che i tre saggi presenti alla nascita di Cristo, fossero magi (sacerdoti) zoroastriani. Con la conquista da parte degli Arabi dell'Impero persiano nel VII secolo d.C., gli zoroastriani vennero perseguitati e la religione scomparve. Alcuni fedeli fuggirono in India, dove fondarono una nuova comunit&#224; nota come Parsis. Oggi vi sono al mondo circa 2-3 milioni di praticanti del zoroastrismo, concentrati per lo pi&#249; in India, Pakistan e Iran, ma sparsi anche nelle principali citt&#224; del mondo di lingua inglese. </Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Aunque no es muy conocido en nuestros d&#237;as, el zoroastrismo ha sido una de las religiones m&#225;s influyentes de la historia del mundo. Era la religi&#243;n del imperio persa, formulada por Zaratustra, conocido en el oeste como Zoroastro. El zoroastrismo tiene elementos monote&#237;stas, pero tambi&#233;n es una fe dualista: el universo es obra de un ser supremo de luz llamado Ahura Mazda, que est&#225; enfrentado a una criatura de oscuridad primigenia conocida como Angra Mainyu. El s&#237;mbolo m&#225;s importante de la fe zoroastrista es el fuego, que simboliza la luz y el calor de Ahura Mazda y sirve como s&#237;mbolo de pureza. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Los estudiosos debaten cu&#225;ndo vivi&#243; Zoroastro, con fechas que oscilan entre el a&#241;o 1000 a. C. y el 600 a. C. Las fechas exactas de su nacimiento y su muerte se desconocen, pero en cualquier caso, el zoroastrismo exist&#237;a ya cuando Ciro II fund&#243; el imperio persa, en el siglo VI a. C. Seg&#250;n la tradici&#243;n zoroastrista, Zoroastro fue reconocido desde su nacimiento como un individuo especial, por lo que los esp&#237;ritus malignos intentaron asesinarlo varias veces siendo a&#250;n un ni&#241;o. Al cumplir los veinte a&#241;os, Zoroastro se retir&#243; a una cueva, donde pas&#243; los siete a&#241;os siguientes meditando. Cuando sinti&#243; que hab&#237;a alcanzado una devoci&#243;n completa hacia Ahura Mazda, Zoroastro parti&#243; a difundir su palabra por el mundo, tarea en la que inicialmente no le acompa&#241;&#243; el &#233;xito. No consigui&#243; sus primeros conversos hasta despu&#233;s de curar de manera milagrosa al caballo del rey Vishtaspa, pero despu&#233;s de este suceso su religi&#243;n conoci&#243; una r&#225;pida difusi&#243;n.  Cuando los griegos se encontraron con los persas por vez primera y empezaron a escribir sobre ellos, el zoroastrismo se hab&#237;a difundido por el imperio persa y ocupaba la mayor parte de Oriente Pr&#243;ximo. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Los zoroastristas creen que el mundo es fundamentalmente un lugar bueno creado para los humanos por Ahura Mazda, pero que al mismo tiempo es el campo de batalla de una lucha entre el bien y el mal. No creen en la predestinaci&#243;n y ponen mucho &#233;nfasis en la elecci&#243;n que deben hacer los individuos para no verse tentados y corrompidos por Angra Mainyu. Las acciones, buenas y malas, recibir&#225;n su recompensa tras la muerte y los malvados ser&#225;n juzgados y enviados al Infierno, aunque al final de los tiempos hasta los perversos ser&#225;n purificados y se reunir&#225;n con Ahura Mazda. Los zoroastristas no reconocen a ning&#250;n otro dios que Ahura Mazda, pero &#233;ste se manifiesta a trav&#233;s de diferentes emanaciones, que a menudo adoptan forma de &#225;ngel y tienen nombres diferentes, como Vohu Manah (Buen Pensamiento) y Asha (Verdad). El libro sagrado de los zoroastristas, llamado Avesta, es una compilaci&#243;n de tradiciones orales que se puso por escrito en tiempos de la Persia sas&#225;nida. Se cree que una peque&#241;a secci&#243;n del Avesta, una serie de himnos conocida como "gathas", es obra del propio Zoroastro. La funci&#243;n fundamental de los templos zoroastristas es la preservaci&#243;n del fuego sagrado, s&#237;mbolo de la luz y la radiaci&#243;n de Ahura Mazda. La limpieza es tambi&#233;n muy importante, y existen varios rituales de purificaci&#243;n que se deben seguir cuando se ha pecado. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Hist&#243;ricamente, el zoroastrismo fue la religi&#243;n del imperio persa, aunque no fue reconocido como tal por los emperadores hasta el per&#237;odo sas&#225;nida (siglo III d. C.). Entr&#243; en contacto con el juda&#237;smo durante el cautiverio en Babilonia (siglo VI a. C.) y existen numerosas evidencias que sugieren que ambas religiones se influenciaron mutuamente (conceptos similares del monote&#237;smo, el Cielo y el Infierno, la escatolog&#237;a, etc.). Adem&#225;s, hoy en d&#237;a se acepta que los tres reyes magos de la historia de Cristo eran magos (sacerdotes) zoroastristas. Cuando, en el siglo VII d. C., los &#225;rabes conquistaron y destruyeron el imperio persa, el zoroastrismo se convirti&#243; en una religi&#243;n perseguida y experiment&#243; un lento declive. Un peque&#241;o n&#250;mero de sus seguidores huy&#243; a la India y form&#243; una comunidad nueva, cuyos miembros ser&#237;an conocidos como "parsis". En la actualidad existen entre dos y tres millones de practicantes del zoroastrismo, concentrados principalmente en la India, Paquist&#225;n e Ir&#225;n, pero tambi&#233;n con cierta presencia en los principales centros urbanos del mundo anglosaj&#243;n. </Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Temple -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_TEMPLE</Tag>
		<English>Zoroastrian Temple (Fire Temple)</English>
		<French>Temple de Feu Zoroastrien</French>
		<German>Zoroastrischer Feuertempel</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In Civilization IV, a temple is defined as a building where the faithful come to worship. Christians call their temples "churches," while Muslims call theirs "mosques," and Jews call theirs, simply, "temples." Temples are far more common than cathedrals, but much less large and ornate. Even the smallest village can possess a temple.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_TEMPLE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Temples[COLOR_REVERT] increase a city's happiness and culture. They are especially useful for expanding your civilization's borders during the early game.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Cathedral (Pantheon) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
		<English>Zoroastrian Cathedral (Pantheon)</English>
		<French>Panthéon Zoroastrien</French>
		<German>Zoroastrisches Pantheon</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In Civilization IV, a pantheon is defined as an especially large and ornate religious building where the faithful worship. Only the most prosperous cities can afford to create pantheons, as they require huge amounts of raw material and years of dedicated labor by skilled craftsmen.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_CATHEDRAL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Zoroastrian Pantheon[COLOR_REVERT] greatly increases a city's cultural output. It makes a city's citizens happy (if [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Zoroastrianism[COLOR_REVERT] is the state religion).</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Monastry -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_MONASTERY</Tag>
		<English>Zoroastrian Monastry</English>
		<French>Mausolée Zoroastrien</French>
		<German>Zoroastrischer Schrein</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A Zoroastrian Shrine is a site where pilgrims can travel and concentrate upon the divine. </English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_MONASTERY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Shrines[COLOR_REVERT] provide culture and a slight boost to research.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Shrine (Pir-e Sabz) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Zoroastrian Shrine (Pir-e Sabz)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Pir-e-Sabz is the holiest and most visited of the Zoroastrian mountain shrines. Shrine legends tell of a conquering Arab army that had pursued Nikbanoo, the daughter of the Sassanian Emperor Yazdgird III, to this region. Fearing capture, she prayed to Ahura Mazda to protect her from the enemy. In the nick of time the mountain miraculously opened up and gave her protection. This legendary site, where a holy spring issues from the towering cliff, is also called Chak-Chak, which means 'drop-drop' in Persian. Growing beside the source of the holy spring is an immense and ancient tree which legends says used to be Nikbanoo's cane, and the waters of the spring are believed to be tears of grief shed by the mountain for Lady Nikbanoo. The shrine enclosure, a man-made cave, is floored with marble and its walls are darkened by soot from the fires kept eternally burning in the sanctuary. Each year from June 14 to 18, many thousands of Zoroastrians from Iran, India and other countries flock to the temple of Pir-e Sabz. One of the pilgrim trails to Chak-Chak is a dirt road starting near the village of Elabad, north of Yazd. It is a time-honored tradition for pilgrims to stop the moment they see the sight of the shrine and continue the rest of their journey by foot. Several roofed pavilions have been constructed on the cliffs below the shrine and throughout the day and night these are tightly packed with pilgrims.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_SHRINE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Wonder (Apadana Palace) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_WONDER_APADANA_PALACE</Tag>
		<English>Zoroastrian Wonder (Apadana Palace)</English>
		<French>Palais Apadana</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_WONDER_APADANA_PALACE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Darius the Great built the greatest and most glorious palace at Persepolis in the western side. This palace was called the Apadana.  The King of Kings used it for official audiences. The work began in 515 BC. His son Xerxes I completed it 30 years later. The palace had a grand hall in the shape of a square, each side 60 m long with seventy-two columns, thirteen of which still stand on the enormous platform. Each column is 19 m high with a square Taurus and plinth. The columns carried the weight of the vast and heavy ceiling. The tops of the columns were made from animal sculptures such as two headed bulls, lions and eagles. The columns were joined to each other with the help of oak and cedar  beams, which were brought from Lebanon. The walls were covered with a layer of mud and stucco to a depth of 5 cm, which was used for bonding, and then covered with the greenish stucco which is found throughout the palaces. At the western, northern and eastern sides of the palace there was a rectangular veranda which had twelve columns in two rows of six. At the south of the grand hall a series of rooms were built for storage. Two grand Persepolitan stairways were built, symmetrical to each other and connected to the stone foundations. To protect the roof from erosion, vertical drains were built through the brick walls. In the four corners of Apadana, facing outwards, four towers were built.[PARAGRAPH:2]The walls were tiled and decorated with pictures of lions, bulls, and flowers. Darius ordered his name and the details of his empire to be written in gold and silver on plates, which were placed in covered stone boxes in the foundations under the Four Corners of the palace. Two Persepolitan style symmetrical stairways were built on the northern and eastern sides of Apadana to compensate for a difference in level. Two other stairways stood in the middle of the building. The external front views of the palace were embossed with pictures of the Immortals, the Kings' elite guards. The northern stairway was completed during Darius' reign, but the other stairway was completed much later.</English>
		<French>Darius Ie (le Grand) a construit le plus Grand et glorieux Palais de la Perse. Le roi l'a fait bâtir durant les premières années de son règne. Le palais s'inspire de ceux de la période néo-babylonienne en ce qui concerne l'organisation des salles dans la Maison du Roi, avec sa succession de cours intérieures alignées, et le plan des salles. Mais il présente aussi des originalités, comme les salles carrées soutenues par quatre colonnes qui seront reprises ensuite à Persépolis. Du point de vue des matériaux, on voit le mélange de la technique mésopotamienne, donc susienne (briques crues, cuites, émaillées), et de celle des montagnards perses (bois et pierre). L'Apadana, salle d'audience royale, a été construit au nord du palais. Il s'agit d'un grand édifice (12 000 m²), de base carrée (109 mètres de côté) ; elle s'organise autour d'une salle centrale carrée (58 mètres de côté), dont le plafond est supporté par six rangées de six colonnes, qui ont une base carrée, et devaient s'élever à 19 mètres. Ces colonnes étaient couronnées d'un chapiteau à protomé de taureau, où s'encastraient les poutres du plafond. Les côtés ouest, nord et est de l'Apadana permettaient d'accéder par des portes à double battants à trois portiques (avec chacun deux rangées de six colonnes). Quatre tours avaient été bâties aux angles de l'édifice.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_WONDER_APADANA_PALACE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Apadana Palace[COLOR_REVERT] reduces maintenance in nearby cities and gives the Order of Ormazd promotion to units produced in city.  This allows empire expansion by both improving your economy and military.</English>
		<French>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Les Palais Apadana[COLOR_REVERT] réduit l'entretien des Villes à proximité et confère la promotion 'Ordre de Ormazd' aux unités entraînées dans la Ville. Cela permet ainsi une expansion de l'Empire, à la fois point de vue économique et militaire.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Wonder (Hammurabi Stele of Laws) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_WONDER_HAMMURABI_STELE_LAWS</Tag>
		<English>Zoroastrian Wonder (Hammurabi Stele of Laws)</English>
		<French>Stèle des Lois d'Hammurabi</French>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Codice di Hammurabi</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_WONDER_HAMMURABI_STELE_LAWS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Code of Hammurabi is a well-preserved ancient law code, created ca. 1760 BC (middle chronology) in ancient Babylon. It was enacted by the sixth Babylonian king, Hammurabi.Only one example of the Code survives today, inscribed on a seven foot, four inch tall basalt stone slab or stele. Originally, several stelae would have been displayed in temples around the empire.</English>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il Codice di Hammurabi è un antico codice di leggi ben conservato, creato intorno al 1760 a.C. nell'antica Babilonia; fu redatto dal sesto re di Babilonia, Hammurabi. Attualmente esiste un solo esemplare del Codice, inciso in una stele di basalto alta all'incirca sette piedi; in origine esistevano invece molte steli, posizionate nei templi di tutto l'impero.</Italian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_WONDER_HAMMURABI_STELE_LAWS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build the Hammurabi stele of laws to get a free Courthouse in all your cities.</English>
		<Italian>Costruisci il Codice di Hammurabi per ottenere un palazzo di giustizia gratuito in tutte le tue città.</Italian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Wonder (Nimrud Palace) -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_WONDER_NIMRUD_PALACE</Tag>
		<English>Zoroastrian Wonder (Nimrud Palace)</English>
		<French>Palais de Nimrud</French>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Palazzo di Nimrud</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_WONDER_NIMRUD_PALACE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The site of Nimrud is located on the Tigris River southeast of Mosul in the north of modern day Iraq. Today the city lies some kilometers east of the Tigris, but in antiquity the river flowed along the northwest side of the acropolis. The site was occupied intermittently from the 6th millennium BC to at least the Hellenistic period, but the most significant period of occupation occurred during the Late Assyrian period, when Assurnasirpal II (883-859 BC) built Nimrud as the capital of his empire. The city remained the chief royal residence and administrative capital of the Assyrian empire until the reign of Sargon II (721-705 BC), though Esarhaddon (680-669 BC) later rebuilt much of the citadel. The Northwest Palace was probably completed between 865 and 869 BC. Its inauguration was celebrated with a large banquet, a description of which is preserved in an inscription on a large stone slab found in the palace. The text describes the building of the city of Kalhu, the settlement of peoples from all over the kingdom in the city, the irrigation of orchards and gardens in the city, the dedication of temples, and the hunting and capture of exotic animals. Finally, the inscription describes the lavish dedicatory celebration, which was attended by 69,574 invitees from all over Assyria. According to Assurnasirpal, they were provided with an enormous amount of food, including 1,500 ducks, 500 geese, 10,000 turtle doves, 10,000 loaves of bread, 10,000 jugs of beer, 10,000 skins of wine, and quantities of nuts, sheep, spices, and vegetables. The text concludes with Assurnasirpal expressing satisfaction in the event: "For ten days I gave them food, I gave them drink, I had them bathe, and I had them anointed. (Thus) did I honor them (and) send them back to their lands in peace and joy" (Grayson 1991: 293).</English>
		<Italian>Il sito di Nimrud si trova sul fiume Tigri a sud est di Mosul, nel nord dell'odierno Iraq. Oggi la città si trova alcuni chilometri a est del Tigri, ma nell'antichità il fiume scorreva lungo il lato nord-ovest dell'acropoli. Il sito è stato abitato in modo discontinuo dal 6° millennio a.C. almeno fino al periodo ellenistico, ma il periodo più significativo di occupazione si è verificato durante il tardo periodo assiro, quando Assurnasirpal II (883-859 a.C.) scelse Nimrud come capitale del suo impero. La città rimase la residenza reale principale e capitale amministrativa dell'impero assiro fino al regno di Sargon II (721-705 a.C.), anche se Esarhaddon (680-669 a.C.) ricostruì gran parte della citadella. Il palazzo fu probabilmente completato tra l'865 e l'869 a.C. La sua inaugurazione è stata celebrata con un grande banchetto, la cui descrizione è conservata in un'iscrizione su una grande lastra di pietra trovata nel palazzo. Il testo descrive la costruzione della città di Kalhu, l'insediamento di popoli di tutto il regno in città, l'irrigazione di orti e giardini in città, la dedizione dei templi, la caccia e la cattura di animali esotici. Infine, l'iscrizione descrive la sontuosa cerimonia d'inaugurazione, a cui parteciparono 69.574 invitati da tutta l'Assiria. Secondo Assurnasirpal, vennero saziati da una quantità enorme di cibo, tra cui 1.500 anatre, 500 oche, 10000 tortore, 10.000 pagnotte di pane, 10.000 boccali di birra, 10.000 pelli di vino e grandi quantità di noci, pecore, spezie e verdure. Il testo si conclude con Assurnasirpal che esprime soddisfazione per la manifestazione: "Per dieci giorni ho dato loro da mangiare, ho dato loro da bere, li ho fatti lavari e li ho unti. (Così) ho fatto loro onore (e) li ho rimandati alle loro terre nella pace e nella gioia "(Grayson 1991: 293).</Italian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZOROASTRIAN_WONDER_NIMRUD_PALACE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build the Nimrud Palace to improve the military production of your city.</English>
		<Italian>Costruisci il Palazzo di Nimrud per inrementare la produzione militare della tua città.</Italian>
	</TEXT>

</Civ4GameText>
