<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Game Text - New -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT> <!-- Accelerator Research Complex -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ACCELERATOR</Tag>
		<English>Accelerator Research Complex</English>
		<French>Accélérateur</French>
		<German>Teilchenbeschleuniger</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ACCELERATOR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A particle accelerator is a device that uses electric fields to propel electrically-charged particles to high speeds and to contain them. An ordinary CRT television set is a simple form of accelerator. There are two basic types: linear accelerators and circular accelerators. [PARAGRAPH:2]In a linear accelerator (linac), particles are accelerated in a straight line with a target of interest at one end. Linacs are very widely used - every cathode ray tube contains one. They are also used to provide an initial low-energy kick to particles before they are injected into circular accelerators. The longest linac in the world is the Stanford Linear Accelerator, SLAC, which is 3 km (2 miles) long. SLAC is an electron-positron collider. [PARAGRAPH:2]Linear accelerators are also widely used in medicine, for radiotherapy and radiosurgery. Medical grade LINACs accelerate electrons using a klystron and a complex bending magnet arrangement which produces a beam of 6-30 million electron-volt (MeV) energy. The electrons can be used directly or they can be collided with a target to produce a beam of X-rays. The reliability, flexibility and accuracy of the radiation beam produced has largely supplanted the older use of Cobalt-60 therapy as a treatment tool.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the circular accelerator, particles move in a circle until they reach sufficient energy. The particle track is typically bent into a circle using electromagnets. The advantage of circular accelerators over linear accelerators (linacs) is that the ring topology allows continuous acceleration, as the particle can transit indefinitely. Another advantage is that a circular accelerator is relatively smaller than a linear accelerator of comparable power (i.e. a linac would have to be extremely long to have the equivalent power of a circular accelerator).[PARAGRAPH:2]The earliest circular accelerators were cyclotrons, invented in 1929 by Ernest O. Lawrence at the University of California, Berkeley. Cyclotrons have a single pair of hollow 'D'-shaped plates to accelerate the particles and a single large dipole magnet to bend their path into a circular orbit. It is a characteristic property of charged particles in a uniform and constant magnetic field B that they orbit with a constant period, at a frequency called the cyclotron frequency, so long as their speed is small compared to the speed of light c. This means that the accelerating D's of a cyclotron can be driven at a constant frequency by a radio frequency (RF) accelerating power source, as the beam spirals outwards continuously. The particles are injected in the centre of the magnet and are extracted at the outer edge at their maximum energy.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ACCELERATOR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases science, commerce and spaceship production.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Agora -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AGORA</Tag>
		<English>Agora</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Agora</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Agora</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AGORA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Agora was an open "place of assembly" in ancient Greek city-states. Early in Greek history (900s - 700s BCE), free-born male land-owners who were citizens would gather in the agora for military duty or to hear statements of the ruling king or council. Later in Greek history, the agora served as a marketplace where merchants kept stalls or shops to sell their goods under colonnades.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AGORA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Alchemists Lab -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ALCHEMISTS_LAB</Tag>
		<English>Alchemist's Lab</English>
		<French>Atelier d'Alchimiste</French>
		<German>Alchemistenlabor</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ALCHEMISTS_LAB_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ALCHEMISTS_LAB_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>An early research facility, grants a science bonus to your city.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Apothecary Shop -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_APOTHECARY_SHOP</Tag>
		<English>Apothecary Shop</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_APOTHECARY_SHOP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In colonial times, the apothecary was more than simply a druggist. An apothecary often provided medical treatment, prescribed medicine, trained apprentices, performed surgery and served as man-midwives. Records kept by 18th-century Williamsburg's apothecaries show they practiced as doctor and even made house calls to treat patients.  Williamsburg apothecaries also sold cooking spices, candles, salad oil, anchovies, toothbrushes, and tobacco, making them true precursors of today's drugstores.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_APOTHECARY_SHOP_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[SPACE]The Apothecary shop provides health to your city and heals units a small amount.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Arena -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARENA</Tag>
		<English>Arena</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Arêne</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARENA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]An arena is an enclosed area, often circular or oval-shaped, designed to showcase theater, musical performances, or sporting events. It is composed of a large open space surrounded on most or all sides by tiered seating for spectators. The key feature of an arena is that the event space is the lowest point, allowing for maximum visibility. Usually, an arena is designed to accommodate a fairly large number of spectators. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Latin word arena means "sand", which was useful as the primary surface where gladiators battled, to absorb the blood. In Spanish, the word carries both meanings. A bullfight is held in an arena (or plaza de toros, literally "circus/square of bulls") and its floor is also covered with arena.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARENA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Arenas entertain the people, providing happiness to your city. Arenas are required to build the Circus Maximus world Wonder or the Statue of Champion national Wonder.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Armaments Industry -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARMAMENTS_INDUSTRY</Tag>
		<English>Armaments Industry</English>
		<French>Usine d'Armement</French>
		<German>Rüstungsindustrie</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARMAMENTS_INDUSTRY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases production of military units at the expense of a high maintenace cost.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARMAMENTS_INDUSTRY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The arms industry is a global industry  and business  which manufactures and sells weapons and military technology and equipment. Arms producing companies, also referred to as defence companies or military industry, produce arms mainly for the armed forces of states. Products include guns, ammunition, missiles, military aircraft, military vehicles, ships, electronic systems, and more. The arms industry also conducts significant research and development.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Armourer -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARMOURER</Tag>
		<English>Armourer</English>
		<French>Armurier</French>
		<German>Waffenschmied</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARMOURER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]An armourer was in former times a smith who specialized in manufacturing and repairing arms and armour. In modern usage, the word may also designate a member of a modern military or police force who maintains and repairs small arms, and weapons systems, with some duties resembling those of a civilian gunsmith.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARMOURER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Armourer allows your city to construct military units faster but also addeds unhealthiness in the city.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Arsenal -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARSENAL</Tag>
		<English>Arsenal</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARSENAL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases production of military units at the expense of a high maintenace cost.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARSENAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>An arsenal is an establishment for the construction, repair, storage and issue of weapons and ammunition. The word is of Arabic origin, being a corruption of dar as-sina'ah, "house of manufacturing" or "manufacture".A first-class arsenal, which can furnish the material and equipment of a large army, embraces a gun factory, carriage factory, laboratory and small-arms ammunition factory, small-arms factory, harness, saddlery and tent factories, and a powder factory; in addition it must possess great store-houses. In a second-class arsenal the factories would be replaced by workshops. The situation of an arsenal should be governed by strategic considerations. If of the first class, it should be situated at the base of operations and supply, secure from attack, not too near a frontier, and placed so as to draw in readily the resources of the country.</English>
		<French>An arsenal is an establishment for the construction, repair, storage and issue of weapons and ammunition. The word is of Arabic origin, being a corruption of dar as-sina'ah, "house of manufacturing" or "manufacture".A first-class arsenal, which can furnish the material and equipment of a large army, embraces a gun factory, carriage factory, laboratory and small-arms ammunition factory, small-arms factory, harness, saddlery and tent factories, and a powder factory; in addition it must possess great store-houses. In a second-class arsenal the factories would be replaced by workshops. The situation of an arsenal should be governed by strategic considerations. If of the first class, it should be situated at the base of operations and supply, secure from attack, not too near a frontier, and placed so as to draw in readily the resources of the country.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Bath House -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BATH_HOUSE</Tag>
		<English>Bath House</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Maison des Bains</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Badeanstalt</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BATH_HOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Public baths originated from a communal need for cleanliness. Often the term public is misleading to some people, as they will have restrictions based upon who can use the facility - elite members of the culture, men only, religious only. As societies advance, public baths often disappear as private washing stations become possible, or they become incorporated into the social system and now are 'meeting places'. [PARAGRAPH:2]The first Roman public thermae of 19 BC had a rotunda 25 meters across, circled by small rooms, set in a park with artificial river and pool. By AD 300 the Baths of Diocletian would cover 1.5 million square feet (140,000 square meters), its soaring granite and porphry sheltering 3,000 bathers a day. Roman baths became "something like a cross between an aquacentre and a theme park," with pools, game rooms, gardens, even libraries and theatres. One of the most famous public bath sites is Aquae Sulis in Bath, England.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BATH_HOUSE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Bath Houses provide health and culture to cities. It also increases the rate at which its city produces [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Great People[COLOR_REVERT]</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Bazaar -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BAZAAR</Tag>
		<English>Bazaar</English>
		<French>Bazar</French>
		<German>Bazar</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BAZAAR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]As cities grew and prospered, trade between the farmers, artisans, and craftsmen who lived in the vicinity contributed to the economic health of the city. It soon became apparent that the best way for conducting trade within the city was to have a central location, or marketplace, where the people offering goods and services, or seeking them, could meet and conduct business. As a city's marketplace grew larger and more active, the economic vitality of the city grew as well.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Lorsque les villes se sont agrandies et ont prosp&#233;r&#233;, le commerce entre les fermiers et les artisans des environs a contribu&#233; &#224; la bonne sant&#233; &#233;conomique de la ville. Rapidement, il est apparu que le meilleur moyen d'attirer le commerce dans la ville consistait &#224; cr&#233;er un emplacement central, une place du march&#233;, o&#249; la population pouvait &#233;changer ses biens et services, se rencontrer et faire des affaires. Lorsque la place du march&#233; d'un village s'agrandissait et devenait plus active, la vitalit&#233; &#233;conomique de la ville augmentait &#233;galement.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Je mehr eine Stadt sich vergr&#246;&#223;erte, desto mehr trug der Handel zwischen Bauern, Kunsthandwerkern und Handwerkern, die im Stadtgebiet oder der n&#228;heren Umgebung ans&#228;ssig waren, zum st&#228;dtischen Wohlstand bei. Schnell erkannte man, dass es sinnvoll war, einen zentralen Ort - einen Marktplatz - f&#252;r Handelsaktivit&#228;ten bereitzustellen. Hier konnten sich alle B&#252;rger einfinden, die Waren und Dienstleistungen anboten oder suchten, um ihre Gesch&#228;fte zu t&#228;tigen. Je mehr ein Marktplatz genutzt wurde, desto st&#228;rker wurde auch die wirtschaftliche Situation der Stadt.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Quando le citt&#224; crescevano e prosperavano, il commercio fra gli agricoltori, gli artigiani e gli artisti che vivevano nelle vicinanze contribuiva al benessere economico della citt&#224;. Divenne presto chiaro che il modo migliore per condurre questi scambi nella citt&#224; era di avere un'area centrale, il mercato, in cui la gente che offriva beni e servizi, oppure li cercava, potesse incontrarsi per condurre i suoi affari. Quando il mercato diventava pi&#249; grande e pi&#249; attraente in una citt&#224;, anche la vitalit&#224; di quest'ultima ne risentiva positivamente.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]A medida que las ciudades crec&#237;an y prosperaban, el comercio entre los agricultores y artesanos que viv&#237;an en sus inmediaciones contribu&#237;a a su salud econ&#243;mica. Pronto se hizo evidente que la mejor manera de llevar a cabo el intercambio en la ciudad era con un lugar central o mercado en el que pudiera reunirse la gente que ofrec&#237;a mercanc&#237;as o servicios y la que iba en busca de los mismos. A medida que el mercado de la ciudad crec&#237;a y su actividad se intensificaba, la vitalidad econ&#243;mica tambi&#233;n aumentaba.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BAZAAR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Bazaar increases a city's commerce a small amount.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Biological Warfare Lab -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BIOLOGICAL_WARFARE_LAB</Tag>
		<English>Biological Warfare Lab</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Laboratoire de guerre biologique</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Labor f&#252;r Biologische Kriegsf&#252;hrung</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Laboratorio per la guerra biologica:Laboratori per la guerra biologica</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Laboratorio de guerra biológica:Laboratorios de guerra biológica</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BIOLOGICAL_WARFARE_LAB_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Bio-war labs are designed to create and mass-produce bio-weapons. In addition, they also work to create antidotes to the enemy's bio-weapons (as well as to their own). Thus these buildings are considered to be integral to a city's defenses. Despite this, and even though these Bio-war labs are equipped with sophisticated and layered defenses against containment breaches, such facilities are often quite unpopular with their neighbors. </English>
		<French>[TAB]Les laboratoires de guerre biologique sont con&#231;us pour cr&#233;er et produire des armes biologiques. En outre, ils travaillent aussi &#224; la mise au point d'antidotes, afin de lutter contre les effets des agents biologiques ennemis (ou alli&#233;s). Ces b&#226;timents font donc partie int&#233;grante du dispositif de d&#233;fense d'une ville. Toutefois, malgr&#233; la fiabilit&#233; de leur syst&#232;me de protection, ces installations restent tr&#232;s impopulaires aupr&#232;s des populations riveraines.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Labors f&#252;r biologische Kriegsf&#252;hrung dienen der Entwicklung und Massenproduktion von biologischen Waffen. Au&#223;erdem werden hier auch Gegenmittel f&#252;r feindliche (und eigene) biologische Waffen hergestellt. Dementsprechend sind diese Geb&#228;ude integraler Bestandteil der st&#228;dtischen Verteidigung. Obwohl die Labors durch hoch entwickelte Abschirmsysteme gleich mehrfach gesch&#252;tzt sind, zeigen sich benachbarte Nationen in aller Regel nicht allzu begeistert von ihrer Existenz. </German>
		<Italian>[TAB]I laboratori per la guerra biologica sono progettati per creare e produrre in massa armi biologiche. Inoltre lavorano per creare antidoti per le armi biologiche del nemico (oltre che per le proprie). Per questo gli edifici vengono considerati parte integrante delle difese di una citt&#224;. Nonostante ci&#242;, e anche se sono equipaggiati con misure di sicurezza per impedire contaminazioni, questi impianti non sono mai molto ben visti nel vicinato.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Los laboratorios de guerra biol&#243;gica se han pensado para crear armas biol&#243;gicas a gran escala. Adem&#225;s, tambi&#233;n trabajan en la creaci&#243;n de ant&#237;dotos contra las bioarmas enemigas (as&#237; como contra las propias). Por ello, dichos edificios se consideran esenciales para la defensa de una ciudad. A pesar de eso y, aunque dichos laboratorios biob&#233;licos est&#233;n equipados con sofisticadas capas protectoras contra filtraciones, los vecinos no acostumbran a recibir bien a estas instalaciones.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BIOLOGICAL_WARFARE_LAB_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Biological Warfare Labs[COLOR_REVERT] allow construction of [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Biological Warfare Missiles[COLOR_REVERT]. They allow you to turn 1 [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Citizen[COLOR_REVERT] into a [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Scientist[COLOR_REVERT]. Bio-Labs decrease [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Happiness[COLOR_REVERT] and [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Healthiness[COLOR_REVERT] by 1 each.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Boatyard -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BOATYARD</Tag>
		<English>Boatyard</English>
		<French>Hangar à Bâteaux</French>
		<German>Bootslager</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BOATYARD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A boatyard is where small watercraft are stored when not in use.</English>
		<French>Le Hangar à Bâteaux est l'endroit pour les embarcations navales sont stockées lorsqu'elles ne sont pas utilisées.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BOATYARD_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build in cities with Fishing Boats nearby.</English>
		<French>Construit dans les Villes près de bâteaux de pêche.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Brightsmiths Hut -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BRIGHTSMITHS_HUT</Tag>
		<English>Brightsmith's Hut</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BRIGHTSMITHS_HUT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The brightsmith is a metalworker that works with the lighter metals such as gold and silver.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BRIGHTSMITHS_HUT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Makes use of unrefined metals resources, providing Commerce</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Brothel -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BROTHEL</Tag>
		<English>Brothel</English>
		<French>Bordel</French>
		<German>Bordell</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BROTHEL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A brothel is an establishment specifically dedicated to prostitution, providing the prostitutes a place to meet and to have sex with the clients. In some places, brothels are legal, and in many countries, places such as massage parlor are allowed to function as brothels, with varying degrees of regulation and repression. [PARAGRAPH:2]Brothels have been known for most of recorded history. Early incidences include temple prostitution in many Mediterranean and Middle Eastern countries. By the time of the ancient Grecian and Roman civilizations, brothels were established and sometimes licensed institutions, with the latter first being recorded in Athens in 594 BC. Public sources of the time applauded the installation of said brothel by Solon, as this was deemed to reduce the disruptions caused by sexually unfulfilled transients (sailors, workers), as well as bringing money into the public purse. This first official brothel was soon followed by many others, and also influenced the creation of special schools in which various classes of prostitutes (from slavegirls to future courtesans) were trained for their profession.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BROTHEL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Brothels provides a small happiness bonus to your city and increases espionage.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Cannon Forge -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CANNON_FORGE</Tag>
		<English>Cannon Forge</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Forge de Canons</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Kanonenschmiede</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CANNON_FORGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CANNON_FORGE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[SPACE].</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Capital Administration -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAPITAL_ADMINISTRATION</Tag>
		<English>Capital Administration</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Administration de la Capitale</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Capital Verwaltung</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAPITAL_ADMINISTRATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Casino -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CASINO</Tag>
		<English>Casino</English>
		<French>Casino</French>
		<German>Kasino</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CASINO_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The term "Casino" is of Italian origin, the root word being "Casa" (house) and originally meant a small country villa, summerhouse or pavilion. The word changed to refer to a building built for pleasure, usually on the grounds of a larger Italian villa or palazzo. Such buildings were used to host civic town functions - including dancing, music listening and gambling.[PARAGRAPH:2]The precise origin of gambling is unknown. The Chinese recorded the first official account of the practice in 2300 B.C., but it is generally believed that activity of gambling, in some way or another, has been seen in almost every society in history. From the Ancient Greeks and Romans to Napoleon's France and Elizabethan England, much of history is filled with stories of entertainment based on the games of chance.  One of the first known casinos was the Casinò di Venezia, established in Venice Italy around 1638, and is still in operation.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CASINO_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Casino increases city's wealth.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Central Bank -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CENTRAL_BANK</Tag>
		<English>Central Bank</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Banque Centrale</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Zentralbank</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CENTRAL_BANK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A central bank, reserve bank, or monetary authority is the entity responsible for the monetary policy of a country or of a group of member states. It is a bank that can lend money to other banks in times of need. Its primary responsibility is to maintain the stability of the national currency and money supply, but more active duties include controlling subsidized-loan interest rates, and acting as a lender of last resort to the banking sector during times of financial crisis (private banks often being integral to the national financial system). It may also have supervisory powers, to ensure that banks and other financial institutions do not behave recklessly or fraudulently.[PARAGRAPH:2]Most richer countries today have an "independent" central bank, that is, one which operates under rules designed to prevent political interference. Examples include the European Central Bank (ECB) and the Federal Reserve System in the United States. Some central banks are publicly owned, and others are privately owned. For example, the United States Federal Reserve is a quasi-public corporation.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CENTRAL_BANK_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Central Bank national wonder boosts city's commerce significantly</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Ceremonial Altar -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CEREMONIAL_ALTAR</Tag>
		<English>Ceremonial Altar</English>
		<French>Autel de cérémonie</French>
		<German>Zeremonienaltar</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CEREMONIAL_ALTAR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A Ceremonial altar is structure upon which sacrifices or other offerings are made for religious purposes, or some other sacred place where ceremonies take place. </English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CEREMONIAL_ALTAR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Ceremonial Altars provides happiness to your city and requires no religion.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Chemist -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHEMIST</Tag>
		<English>Chemist</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Pharmacie</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Apotheke</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHEMIST_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A chemist (commonly drugstore in North America; retail pharmacy in industry terminology; or Apothecary, historically) is the place where most pharmacists practice the profession of pharmacy. It is the community pharmacy where the dichotomy of the profession exists-health professionals who are also retailers. [PARAGRAPH:2]Community pharmacies usually consist of a retail storefront with a dispensary where medications are stored and dispensed. The dispensary is subject to pharmacy legislation; with requirements for storage conditions, compulsory texts, equipment, etc., specified in legislation. Where it was once the case that pharmacists stayed within the dispensary compounding/dispensing medications; there has been an increasing trend towards the use of trained pharmacy technicians while the pharmacist spends more time communicating with patients.[PARAGRAPH:2]All pharmacies are required to have a pharmacist on-duty at all times when open. In many jurisdictions, it is also a requirement that the owner of a pharmacy must be a registered pharmacist (R.Ph.). This latter requirement has been revoked in many jurisdictions, such that many retailers (including supermarkets and mass merchandisers) now include a pharmacy as a department of their store.[PARAGRAPH:2]Likewise, many pharmacies are now rather grocery store-like in their design. In addition to medicines and prescriptions, many now sell a diverse arrangement of additional household items such as cosmetics, shampoo, office supplies, confectionary, and snack foods.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHEMIST_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Cinema -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CINEMA</Tag>
		<English>Cinema</English>
		<French>Cinéma</French>
		<German>Kino</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CINEMA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Most cinemas are commercial operations catering to the general public, who attend by purchasing a ticket. The film is projected onto a large projection screen at the front of the auditorium. Some cinemas are now equipped for digital cinema projection, removing the need to create and transport a physical film print.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CINEMA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Movies can make people happy and some might even become celebrities.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Circus Maximus -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CIRCUS_MAXIMUS</Tag>
		<English>Circus Maximus</English>
		<French>Cirque Maxime</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CIRCUS_MAXIMUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Circus Maximus (Latin for largest arena) is an ancient arena and mass entertainment venue located in Rome.[NEWLINE] [PARAGRAPH:1]Situated in the valley between the Aventine and Palatine hills, the location was first utilised for public games and entertainment by the Etruscan kings of Rome. Certainly, the first games of the Ludi Romani (Roman Games) were staged at the location by Tarquinius Priscus, the first Etruscan ruler of Rome. Somewhat later, the Circus was the site of public games and festivals influenced by the Greeks in the 2nd century BC. Meeting the demands of the Roman citizenry for mass public entertainment on a lavish scale, Julius Caesar expanded the Circus around 50 BC, after which the track measured approximately 600 metres in length, 225 metres in breadth and could accommodate an estimated 150,000 seated spectators (many more, perhaps an equal number again, could view the games by standing, crowding and lining the adjoining hills). In 81 AD, the Senate built a triple arch honoring Titus by the closed East end (not to be confused with the Arch of Titus over the Via Sacra on the opposite side of the Palatinum). The emperor Domitian connected his new palace on the Palatine to the Circus in order that he could more easily view the races. The emperor Trajan later added another 5000 seats and expanded the emperor's seating in order to increase his public visibility during the games. [NEWLINE] [PARAGRAPH:1]The most important event at the Circus was chariot racing. The track could hold 12 chariots, and the two sides of the track were separated by a raised median termed the spina. Statues of various gods were set up on the spina, and Augustus erected an Egyptian obelisk on it as well. At either end of the spina was a turning post, the meta, around which chariots made dangerous turns at speed. One end of the track extended further back than the other, to allow the chariots to line up to begin the race. Here there were starting gates, or carceres, which staggered the chariots so that each travelled the same distance to the first turn. [PARAGRAPH:1] From : Wikipedia</English>
		<French>[TAB]À Rome, le Circus maximus (en latin : Cirque le plus grand) ou Cirque Maxime (ou simplement Grand Cirque), dédié aux courses de chars, reste à ce jour la plus vaste enceinte sportive que le monde ait connu.[NEWLINE] [PARAGRAPH:1] Source : Wikipedia</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CIRCUS_MAXIMUS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Circus Maximus increases happiness in all cities on the same continent and provides bonus XP for melee and mounted units constructed in the city.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- City Council -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CITY_COUNCIL</Tag>
		<English>City Council</English>
		<French>Conseil Municipal</French>
		<German>Stadtrat</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CITY_COUNCIL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT> <!-- Cloning Laboratory -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CLONING_LABORATORY</Tag>
		<English>Cloning Laboratory</English>
		<French>Laboratoire de Clonage</French>
		<German>Klonlabor</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CLONING_LABORATORY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CLONING_LABORATORY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Cloning Laboratory increases science output in the city and permits training of Automatons and Clones. Causes unhappiness in the city.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Commercial Port -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COMMERCIAL_PORT</Tag>
		<English>Commercial Port</English>
		<French>Port Commercial</French>
		<German>Handelshafen</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COMMERCIAL_PORT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COMMERCIAL_PORT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Commercial Ports increase coastal cities' trade routes and commerce and happiness. They are required to build International Ports.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Communication Tower -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COMMUNICATION_TOWER</Tag>
		<English>Communication Tower</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Tour de Communication</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Sendeturm</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COMMUNICATION_TOWER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COMMUNICATION_TOWER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Computer Network -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COMPUTER_NETWORK</Tag>
		<English>Computer Network</English>
		<French>Réseau Informatique</French>
		<German>Computernetzwerk</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COMPUTER_NETWORK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A computer network allows computers to communicate with many other and to share resources and information. The Advanced Research Projects Agency (ARPA) funded the design of the "Advanced Research Projects Agency Network" (ARPANET) for the United States Department of Defense. It was the first operational computer network in the world. Development of the network began in 1969, based on designs begun in the 1960s.[PARAGRAPH:2]Computer networks can be classified according to the hardware and software technology that is used to interconnect the individual devices in the network, such as Optical fiber, Ethernet, Wireless LAN, HomePNA, Power line communication or G.hn. Ethernet uses physical wiring to connect devices. Frequently deployed devices include hubs, switches, bridges and/or routers.[PARAGRAPH:2]Networks are often classified as Local Area Network (LAN), Wide Area Network (WAN), Metropolitan Area Network (MAN), Personal Area Network (PAN), Virtual Private Network (VPN), Campus Area Network (CAN), Storage Area Network (SAN), etc. depending on their scale, scope and purpose. Usage, trust levels and access rights often differ between these types of network - for example, LANs tend to be designed for internal use by an organization's internal systems and employees in individual physical locations (such as a building), while WANs may connect physically separate parts of an organization to each other and may include connections to third parties.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COMPUTER_NETWORK_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Computer Network increases city's wealth and science output but causes some unhealthiness. Required building in the city for many other advanced buildings.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Construction Firm -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONSTRUCTION_FIRM</Tag>
		<English>Construction Firm</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Entreprise de Construction</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Bauunternehmer</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONSTRUCTION_FIRM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In the fields of architecture and civil engineering, construction is a process that consists of the building or assembling of infrastructure. Far from being a single activity, large scale construction is a feat of multitasking. Normally the job is managed by the project manager and supervised by the construction manager, design engineer, construction engineer or project architect.  For the successful execution of a project, effective planning is essential. Those involved with the design and execution of the infrastructure in question must consider the environmental impact of the job, the successful scheduling, budgeting, site safety, availability of materials, logistics, inconvenience to the public caused by construction delays, preparing tender documents, etc.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONSTRUCTION_FIRM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases Production for Buildings.</English>
		<French>Augmente la vitesse de Construction des Bâtiments.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Container Port -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONTAINER_PORT</Tag>
		<English>Container Port</English>
		<French>Grand Port de Container</French>
		<German>Containerhafen</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONTAINER_PORT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONTAINER_PORT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Container ports significantly increase coastal cities' commerce but at the cost of increased polution.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Doctor's Office -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DOCTORS_OFFICE</Tag>
		<English>Doctor's Office</English>
		<French>Cabinet de médecin</French>
		<German>Gesundheitsamt</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DOCTORS_OFFICE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DOCTORS_OFFICE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Doctor's Office provides health to the city and helps units recover health.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Einsteins Laboratory -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_EINSTEIN_LAB</Tag>
		<English>Einsteins Laboratory</English>
		<French>Laboratoire d'Einstein</French>
		<German>Einsteins Labor</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_EINSTEIN_LAB_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Albert Einstein (14 March 1879 - 18 April 1955) was a theoretical physicist. He is best known for his theories of special relativity and general relativity. Einstein received the 1921 Nobel Prize in Physics "for his services to Theoretical Physics, and especially for his discovery of the law of the photoelectric effect."[PARAGRAPH:2]Einstein's many contributions to physics included the special and general theories of relativity, the founding of relativistic cosmology, the first post-Newtonian expansion, explaining the perihelion advance of Mercury, prediction of the deflection of light by gravity and gravitational lensing, the first fluctuation dissipation theorem which explained the Brownian movement of molecules, the photon theory and wave-particle duality, the quantum theory of atomic motion in solids, the zero-point energy concept, the semiclassical version of the Schr&#246;dinger equation, and the quantum theory of a monatomic gas which predicted Bose-Einstein condensation.[PARAGRAPH:2]Einstein published more than 300 scientific works and more than 150 non-scientific works.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_EINSTEIN_LAB_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases science output of city and gives +2 free scientists.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Elder Council -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ELDER_COUNCIL</Tag>
		<English>Elder Council</English>
		<French>Conseil des Anciens</French>
		<German>&#196;ltestenrat</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ELDER_COUNCIL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Oral tradition, oral culture and oral lore are messages or testimony transmitted orally from one generation to another.  The messages or testimony are verbally transmitted in speech or song and may take the form, for example, of folktales, sayings, ballads, songs, or chants. In this way, it is possible for a society to transmit oral history, oral literature, oral law and other knowledges across generations without a writing system.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ELDER_COUNCIL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Early science building.</English>
		<French>Bâtiment Primitif de Science</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Financial Nexus -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FINANCIAL_NEXUS</Tag>
		<English>Financial Nexus</English>
		<French>Nexus Financier</French>
		<German>Finanznexus</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FINANCIAL_NEXUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FINANCIAL_NEXUS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Financial Nexus[COLOR_REVERT] increases your total [ICON_GOLD] by 50%, and provides 2% interest on your [ICON_GOLD] reserves every turn.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Fish Market -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISH_MARKET</Tag>
		<English>Fish Market</English>
		<French>Marché aux poissons</French>
		<German>Fischmarkt</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISH_MARKET_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Fish Markets grant a health bonus and allow faster growth. they also increase the commerce gain.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISH_MARKET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Fish Market[COLOR_REVERT] is a marketplace used for marketing fish products. It can be dedicated to wholesale trade between fishermen and fish merchants, or to the sale of seafood to individual consumers, or to both. Retail fish markets, a type of wet market, often sell street food as well.[PARAGRAPH:1]Because seafood is quick to spoil, fish markets are historically most often found in seaside towns. Once ice or other simple cooling  methods became available, some were also established in large inland cities that had good trade routes to the coast.[PARAGRAPH:1]Since refrigeration and rapid transport became available in the 19th and 20th century, fish markets can technically be established at any place. However, because modern trade logistics in general has shifted away from marketplaces and towards retail outlets, such as supermarkets, most seafood worldwide is now sold to consumers through these venues, like most other foodstuffs.[PARAGRAPH:1]Consequently, most major fish markets now mainly deal with wholesale trade, and the existing major fish retail markets continue to operate as much for traditional reasons as for commercial ones. Both types of fish markets are often tourist attractions as well.</English>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT> <!-- Fish Traps -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISHTRAPS</Tag>
		<English>Fish Traps</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Pièges à Poissons</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Fischreusen</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISHTRAPS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Fish are an important part of diets for many cultures, since fish can be easily salted and dried and are rich in protein.  Fish traps allow fish migrating in rivers or coastal areas to be easily caught.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISHTRAPS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The ability to catch fish in rivers and the coastline increases Food</English>
		<French>La possibilité de piéger des poissons augmente la Nourriture</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Fisherman's Hut -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISHERMANS_HUT</Tag>
		<English>Fisherman's Hut</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Cabane du Pêcheur</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Fischerh&#252;tte</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISHERMANS_HUT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB] A fishmonger (fishwife for women practitioners - "wife" in this case used in its archaic meaning of "woman") is someone who sells fish and seafood. In some countries modern supermarkets are replacing fishmongers who operate in shops or markets.  Fishmongers are trained at selecting and purchasing, handling, gutting, boning, filleting, displaying, merchandising and selling their product. In many places fishmongers, like butchers, are a dying breed. With the advent of many modern ways of distributing and packaging food, supermarkets often opt for less expensive alternatives to these trained, highly skilled professionals.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISHERMAN_HUTS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Can be built only in coastal city</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Peut être construit uniquement dans une Ville côtière</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Kann nur in K&#252;stenst&#228;dten gebaut werden</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISHERMAN_HUTS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Fisherman's Hut increases city's food production if city has access to Fish, Crab and Whale resources.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Foundry -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FOUNDRY</Tag>
		<English>Foundry</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Fonderie</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Gie&#223;erei</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FOUNDRY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A foundry is a factory that produces metal castings from either ferrous or non-ferrous alloys. Metals are turned into parts by melting the metal into a liquid, pouring the metal in a mold, and then removing the mold material or casting. The most common metal alloys processed are aluminum and cast iron. However, other metals, such as steel, magnesium, copper, tin, and zinc, can be processed.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FOUNDRY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Furrier -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FURRIER</Tag>
		<English>Furrier</English>
		<French>Fourreur</French>
		<German>K&#252;rschner</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FURRIER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Originally, Russia exported a majority in raw furs of the pelts of martens, beavers, wolves, foxes, squirrels and hares. Between the 16th and 18th centuries, Russians tamed Siberia, a region rich in many mammal species, such as Arctic fox, lynx, sable, sea otter and stoat (ermine). In the search for the prized sea otter (pelts first used in China), and, later the northern fur seal, the Russian Empire expanded into North America, notably Alaska. Between the 17th and second half of the 19th century, Russia was the largest supplier of fur in the world. The fur trade played a vital role in the development of Siberia, the Russian Far East and the Russian colonization of the Americas. To this day sable is a regional symbol of Ural Sverdlovsk oblast and Siberian Novosibirsk, Tyumen and Irkutsk oblasts of Russia.  The European discovery of North America, with its vast forests and wild-life, particularly the beaver, led to the continent's becoming a major supplier in the 17th century of fur pelts for the fur-felt hat and fur trimming and garment trades of Europe. Fur was a major source of warmth in clothing, critical prior to the organisation of coal distribution.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FURRIER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Adds gold and commerce with Fur; Resource requirement.</English>
		<French>Ajoute de l'Or et du commerce avec la ressource Fourrure (nécessaire)</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Gambling Hall -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GAMBLING_HALL</Tag>
		<English>Gambling Hall</English>
		<French>Hall de Jeux</French>
		<German>Gl&#252;cksspielsaal</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GAMBLING_HALL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Gambling is the wagering of money or something of material value on an event with an uncertain outcome with the primary intent of winning additional money and/or material goods. Typically, the outcome of the wager is evident within a short period.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GAMBLING_HALL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Cheap gold building, but angers citizens</English>
		<French>Bâtiment générant de l'Or, mais rend certains citoyens mécontents</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Great Academy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_ACADEMY</Tag>
		<English>Great Academy</English>
		<French>Grande Académie</French>
		<German>Große Akademie</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Guild Hall -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GUILDHALL</Tag>
		<English>Guild Hall</English>
		<French>Maison des Corporations</French>
		<German>Gildehalle</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GUILDHALL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A Guildhall is a building used by guilds for meetings. The town authorities were represented in the guild meetings and thus had a means of controlling the handicraft activities. This was important since towns very often depended on a good reputation for export of a narrow range of products, on which not only the guild's, but the town's, reputation depended.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GUILDHALL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases production in city but the downside is slightly higher maintenance costs.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Harbour -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HARBOUR</Tag>
		<English>Harbour</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Port</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Hafen</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Porto:Porti</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Puerto:Puertos</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HARBOUR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Just because a city is built in a coastal region doesn't guarantee that the city is readily accessible by ship. In order for a port city to establish a steady trade, fishing, or other shipping industry, the city must have a harbour. A harbour is a protected body of water that opens into an ocean or lake that shelters ships from waves and high winds. Although some coastal cities are established in areas where a natural harbour exists, most seaports are forced either to improve the existing natural harbour, or to build a man-made harbour to shelter ships and provide channels deep enough to accommodate large vessels.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Le fait de construire une ville dans une r&#233;gion c&#244;ti&#232;re ne lui garantit pas d'&#234;tre facilement accessible par bateau. Pour qu'une cit&#233; portuaire puisse &#233;tablir des industries de commerce, de p&#234;che et de transport maritime de fa&#231;on durable, elle doit avoir un port. Un port est une structure emprisonnant de l'eau mais ouvert sur l'oc&#233;an ou sur un lac et qui abrite les bateaux des vagues et des vents violents. Certaines villes portuaires sont construites dans des ports naturels mais la majorit&#233; des ports maritimes ne le sont pas. Dans ce cas, ces infrastructures permettent d'am&#233;liorer un port naturel existant ou de cr&#233;er un port artificiel pour abriter les navires et offrir des chenaux suffisamment profonds pour accueillir de grands bateaux.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Nur weil eine Stadt an der K&#252;ste liegt, bedeutet das nicht, dass sie f&#252;r Schiffe leicht zug&#228;nglich ist. Vielmehr muss eine solche K&#252;stenstadt einen Hafen unterhalten, damit sie sich aktiv am Seehandel, der Fischereiindustrie und anderen maritimen Unternehmungen beteiligen kann. Ein Hafen ist eine gesch&#252;tzte Wasserfl&#228;che, die sich zum Meer oder einem anderen offenen Gew&#228;sser hin &#246;ffnet und die vor Anker liegenden Schiffe vor Wellen und starken Windb&#246;en sch&#252;tzt. Auch wenn einige K&#252;stenst&#228;dte einen nat&#252;rlichen Hafen besitzen, so sind sie meist doch gezwungen, diesen entweder auszubauen oder zus&#228;tzlich einen k&#252;nstlichen Hafen anzulegen, um die einlaufenden Schiffe beherbergen und auch gro&#223;en Schiffen mit mehr Tiefgang Zugang gew&#228;hren zu k&#246;nnen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Solo perch&#233; una citt&#224; sorge sulla costa, non &#232; detto che sia facilmente accessibile alle navi e alle imbarcazioni. Affinch&#233; una citt&#224; di mare possa intraprendere solide attivit&#224; di commercio, pesca, o altre industrie navali, essa deve avere una baia. Questo &#232; uno specchio d'acqua che d&#224; sul mare o su un lago, protetta in modo da offrire ai natanti un riparo dalle onde e dai venti forti. Anche se molte citt&#224; sono sorte in luoghi gi&#224; dotati di una baia naturale, la maggior parte delle comunit&#224; portuali sono costrette o a migliorare quella esistente o a realizzarne una artificiale per assicurare una sufficiente navigabilit&#224; e accessibilit&#224; anche alle navi di maggiori dimensioni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]El hecho de que una ciudad est&#233; construida en una regi&#243;n costera no garantiza que se pueda acceder a ella por barco. Para que una ciudad portuaria pueda establecer una ruta de comercio estable, pescar o establecer cualquier tipo de industria naval, debe tener un puerto. Un puerto es una masa de agua protegida que se abre hacia el oc&#233;ano o un lago y protege a las naves del oleaje y los vientos. Aunque algunas ciudades costeras se encuentran en zonas en las que existe un puerto natural, la mayor&#237;a de los puertos marinos se ven obligados, bien a mejorar el puerto natural ya existente, bien a construir un puerto artificial para proteger a los barcos y proporcionar canales suficientemente profundos para albergar a buques de gran calado.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HARBOUR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Harbour[COLOR_REVERT] increases that city's income from trade routes. It increases a city's health from access to [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Clam[COLOR_REVERT], [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Crab[COLOR_REVERT], and [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Fish[COLOR_REVERT] resources.</English>
		<French>Les [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]ports[COLOR_REVERT] augmentent les revenus g&#233;n&#233;r&#233;s par les routes commerciales des villes. Ils am&#233;liorent la sant&#233; des citoyens dans les villes qui peuvent p&#234;cher des [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]coquillages[COLOR_REVERT], du [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]crabe[COLOR_REVERT] et du [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]poisson[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>Ein [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Hafen[COLOR_REVERT] erh&#246;ht das Handelseinkommen einer Stadt und erschlie&#223;t die Ressourcen [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Muscheln[COLOR_REVERT], [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Krabben[COLOR_REVERT] und [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Fisch[COLOR_REVERT]. Diese wirken sich wiederum positiv auf die Gesundheit Ihrer Bev&#246;lkerung aus.</German>
		<Italian>Il [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]porto[COLOR_REVERT] aumenta il guadagno della citt&#224; da parte delle rotte commerciali. Inoltre, con l'accesso a [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Molluschi[COLOR_REVERT], [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Crostacei[COLOR_REVERT] e [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Pesci[COLOR_REVERT], aumenta la salute della citt&#224;.</Italian>
		<Spanish>El [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Puerto[COLOR_REVERT] aumenta los ingresos por rutas comerciales de la ciudad. Tambi&#233;n incrementa su salud por acceder a los recursos de las [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Almejas[COLOR_REVERT], los [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Cangrejos[COLOR_REVERT] y el [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Pescado[COLOR_REVERT].</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Healer's Hut -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HEALERS_HUT</Tag>
		<English>Healer's Hut</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Hutte du Guérisseur</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Medizinmann</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HEALERS_HUT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HEALERS_HUT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Healer's Hut provides health to your city and heals units a small amount.</English>
		<French>Les Guérisseurs améliore la Santé de la population, et soigne également les unités.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- High Walls -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HIGH_WALLS</Tag>
		<English>High Walls</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Hauts Remparts</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Lange Mauern</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Lunghe mura</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Muralla alta:Murallas altas</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HIGH_WALLS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>At the onset of the Peloponnesian War, Athens possessed a formidable defensive structure known as the "Long Walls." Completed in 457 BC, the Long Walls connected Athens with its port city of Piraeus and ensured that the city could not be cut off from supplies unless it was defeated at sea. Lacking effective siege technology the Spartans were unable to breach these walls; they did not achieve final victory until they destroyed the Athenian navy in 404 BC, cutting off Athen's supplies and starving the city into submission.[PARAGRAPH:1]The city of Thebes possessed an ancient and powerful set of fortifications known as the "Cadmea." During 457-447 BC Thebes was engaged in a bitter struggle with its traditional foe Athens. Though the powerful Athenian army overran the Theban countryside, it was never able to breach Thebes's potent defenses and engage the enemy army directly.[PARAGRAPH:1]In this scenario, high walls take much longer to construct than ordinary city walls, but once built they are very difficult for an enemy force to occupy and grant a huge defensive bonus to any units stationed inside.</English>
		<French>[TAB]D&#232;s le d&#233;but de la guerre du P&#233;loponn&#232;se, Ath&#232;nes dispose d'une formidable structure d&#233;fensive, les Longs Murs achev&#233;s en 457 av. J.-C. qui relient Ath&#232;nes au port du Pir&#233;e, pr&#233;venant toute rupture des voies d'approvisionnement tant que les Ath&#233;niens peuvent maintenir leur contr&#244;le maritime. Manquant d'engins de si&#232;ge, les Spartiates ne parviennent pas &#224; percer ces murailles et n'obtiennent la victoire finale qu'en 404 av. J.-C. apr&#232;s avoir an&#233;anti la flotte ath&#233;nienne et coup&#233; leurs lignes de ravitaillement, affamant la cit&#233; et la for&#231;ant &#224; se rendre.[PARAGRAPH:1]La cit&#233; de Th&#232;bes est prot&#233;g&#233;e par un puissant r&#233;seau de fortifications formant la citadelle de la Cadm&#233;e. De 457 &#224; 447 av. J.-C., Th&#232;bes est engag&#233;e dans une &#226;pre lutte contre son ennemi jur&#233; ath&#233;nien. La puissance arm&#233;e d'Ath&#232;nes &#233;crase les forces th&#233;baines en-dehors de la cit&#233;, mais se montre incapable de briser les derni&#232;res d&#233;fenses de Th&#232;bes et d'engager le combat contre son arm&#233;e.[PARAGRAPH:1]Dans ce sc&#233;nario, les Longs Murs prennent bien plus de temps &#224; &#233;difier que des murailles ordinaires, mais une fois construits, ils sont tr&#232;s difficiles &#224; prendre et accordent par cons&#233;quent un &#233;norme bonus d&#233;fensif &#224; toutes les unit&#233;s en position &#224; l'int&#233;rieur.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Bereits beim Ausbruch des Peleponnesischen Krieges verf&#252;gte die Stadt Athen &#252;ber eindrucksvolle Defensivbauwerke, die so genannten "Langen Mauern". Im Jahr 457 vor Christus fertig gestellt, verbanden sie die Stadt Athen mit der Hafenstadt Pir&#228;us. Dadurch konnte die Versorgung der Athener nur dann tats&#228;chlich gef&#228;hrdet werden, wenn die Stadt von der Seeseite her angegriffen und bezwungen w&#252;rde. Da die Spartaner nicht &#252;ber geeignete Belagerungstechniken verf&#252;gten, gelang es ihnen zun&#228;chst nicht, die Mauern zu durchbrechen. Erst nach der Vernichtung der attischen Seestreitkr&#228;fte im Jahr 404 vor Christus, wodurch die Stadtbev&#246;lkerung von der Versorgung abgeschnitten und die Stadt angesichts der nun herrschenden Hungersnot zur Aufgabe gezwungen war, trugen sie den endg&#252;ltigen Sieg davon. [PARAGRAPH:1]Mit der so genannten "Kadmeia" besa&#223; die Stadt Theben eine sehr alte und solide Festungsanlage. Als die Thebianer in den Jahren 457 bis 447 vor Christus einen erbitterten Krieg gegen ihre traditionellen attischen Erzfeinde f&#252;hrten, &#252;berrannten die m&#228;chtigen Streitkr&#228;fte Athens zwar die au&#223;erhalb der Stadt liegenden Landstriche, es gelang ihnen jedoch nicht, die robusten st&#228;dtischen Verteidigungsanlagen zu &#252;berwinden und die gegnerischen Truppen direkt anzugreifen.[PARAGRAPH:1]In diesem Szenario erfordern die Langen Mauern eine wesentlich l&#228;ngere Bauzeit als die herk&#246;mmlichen Stadtmauern - andererseits k&#246;nnen sie auch nur sehr schwer von feindlichen Truppen &#252;berwunden werden und bieten allen innerhalb der Mauern stationierten Einheiten einen sehr hohen Defensivbonus.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]All'inizio della Guerra del Peloponneso, Atene possedeva una formidabile struttura difensiva nota come le "Lunghe mura". Completate nel 457 a.C., esse collegavano Atene con il Pireo (la sua frazione portuale), impedendo che alla citt&#224; fosse tagliata la linea di rifornimento (a meno che non venisse sconfitta per mare). Privi di vere armi d'assedio, gli Spartani furono incapaci di scavare una breccia in queste mura e la loro vittoria fu rinviata finch&#233; non riuscirono a distruggere la flotta ateniese nel 404: Atene non poteva pi&#249; ricevere rifornimenti e la citt&#224;, affamata, dovette cedere.[PARAGRAPH:1]La citt&#224; di Tebe possedeva un antico e possente sistema di fortificazioni noto come "Cadmea". Tra il 457 e il 447 a.C. Tebe fu impegnata in un aspro scontro con la rivale Atene. Anche se il potente esercito ateniese imperversava nelle campagne tebane, non fu mai in grado di aprire una breccia nelle potenti difese della citt&#224; e affrontare apertamente l'avversario.[PARAGRAPH:1]In questo scenario, per costruire le Lunghe mura occorre pi&#249; tempo rispetto alle normali mura cittadine ma, una volta erette, esse sono molto difficili da superare per il nemico poich&#233; offrono un enorme bonus difensivo a tutte le unit&#224; stazionate al loto interno.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Al inicio de la guerra del Peloponeso, Atenas ten&#237;a una formidable estructura defensiva llamada "las murallas largas". Completadas en el 457 a. C., conectaban Atenas con su enclave portuario del Pireo y aseguraban que la ciudad no se quedara sin suministros a menos que la derrotaran por mar. Al carecer de la tecnolog&#237;a de asedio necesaria, los espartanos fueron incapaces de romperlas y no consiguieron la victoria definitiva hasta que destruyeron la armada ateniense en el 404 a. C., lo que dej&#243; sin vituallas a Atenas y la rindi&#243; por hambre.[PARAGRAPH:1]La ciudad de Tebas contaba con un conjunto de fortificaciones formidable llamado "Cadmea". Entre el 457 y el 447 a. C., Tebas se enzarz&#243; en una lucha encarnizada contra Atenas, su enemiga tradicional. Aunque el poderoso ej&#233;rcito ateniense arras&#243; el campo tebano, nunca pudo hacer brecha en las recias defensas de Tebas y enfrentarse directamente al ej&#233;rcito enemigo.[PARAGRAPH:1]En este escenario, las murallas altas tardan mucho m&#225;s en construirse que las murallas corrientes de la ciudad; no obstante, una vez construidas, es muy dif&#237;cil que una fuerza enemiga las ocupe. Adem&#225;s, conceden unas bonificaciones defensivas a todas las unidades destacadas all&#237;.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Hypermarket -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HYPERMARKET</Tag>
		<English>Hypermarket</English>
		<French>Hypermarché</French>
		<German>Hypermarkt</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HYPERMARKET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In commerce, a hypermarket is a superstore which combines a supermarket and a department store. The result is a very large retail facility which carries an enormous range of products under one roof, including full lines of groceries and general merchandise. In theory, hypermarkets allow customers to satisfy all their routine weekly shopping needs in one trip.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HYPERMARKET_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Info Net -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INFO_NET</Tag>
		<English>Info Net</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INFO_NET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INFO_NET_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Info Net increases city's science output.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Investment Bank -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INVESTMENT_BANK</Tag>
		<English>Investment Bank</English>
		<French>Banque d'Investissements</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INVESTMENT_BANK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]An investment bank is a financial institution that assists corporations and governments in raising capital by underwriting and acting as the agent in the issuance of securities. An investment bank also assists companies involved in mergers and acquisitions, derivatives, etc. Further it provides ancillary services such as market making and the trading of derivatives, fixed income instruments, foreign exchange, commodity, and equity securities.[PARAGRAPH:1]To provide investment banking services in the United States an advisor must be a licensed broker-dealer. Until 1999, the United States maintained a separation between investment banking and commercial banks. Other industrialized countries, including G7 countries, have not maintained this separation historically. Trading securities for cash or securities (i.e., facilitating transactions, market-making), or the promotion of securities (i.e., underwriting, research, etc.) was referred to as the "sell side".[PARAGRAPH:1]Dealing with the pension funds, mutual funds, hedge funds, and the investing public who consumed the products and services of the sell-side in order to maximize their return on investment constitutes the "buy side". Many firms have buy and sell side components.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Jumplane Portal -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JUMPLANE_PORTAL</Tag>
		<English>Jumplane Portal</English>
		<French>Portail de Saut</French>
		<German>Jumplaneportal</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JUMPLANE_PORTAL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Jumplane Portals boost your commerce income - especially from trade routes.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JUMPLANE_PORTAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT> <!-- Lepinski Vir -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEPENSKI_VIR</Tag>
		<English>Lepenski Vir</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEPENSKI_VIR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT]Lepenski Vir[COLOR_REVERT] is an important Mesolithic archaeological site located in Serbia in the central Balkan peninsula. It consists of one large settlement with around ten satellite villages. The evidence suggests the first human presence in the locality around 7000 BC with the culture reaching its peak between 5300 BC and 4800 BC. Numerous piscine sculptures and peculiar architecture are testimony to a rich social and religious life led by the inhabitants and the high cultural level of these early Europeans.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]This is clearly evident in the layout of the Lepenski Vir Ia-e settlement. The village is well planned. All houses are built according to one complex geometric pattern. These remains of houses constitute the distinct Lepenski Vir architecture, one of the important achievements of this culture. The main layout of the village is clearly visible. The dead were buried outside the village in an elaborate cemetery. The only exceptions were apparently a few notable elders who were buried behind the fireplaces in houses, according to a religious ritual.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]The complex social structure was dominated by a religious cult which probably served as a binding force for the community and a means of coordination of activity for its members. Numerous sacral objects that were discovered in this layer support this theory. The most remarkable examples are piscine sculptures, unique to the Lepenski Vir culture, which represent one of the first examples of monumental sacral art on European soil.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEPENSKI_VIR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build the [COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT]Lepenski Vir[COLOR_REVERT] to get a free [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Sacrificial Altar[COLOR_REVERT] in every city.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Library -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LIBRARY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Libraries[COLOR_REVERT] boost your cities' research and provide culture. They are required to build [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Universities[COLOR_REVERT], the [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Great Library[COLOR_REVERT] wonder, and the [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]National Epic[COLOR_REVERT] national wonder.</English>
		<French>Les [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]biblioth&#232;ques[COLOR_REVERT] am&#233;liorent la recherche et produisent de la culture. Elles sont n&#233;cessaires pour construire des [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]universit&#233;s[COLOR_REVERT], la [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Grande biblioth&#232;que[COLOR_REVERT], et l'[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Epop&#233;e nationale[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Bibliotheken[COLOR_REVERT] erh&#246;hen den kulturellen Wert einer Stadt und beschleunigen die Forschung sp&#252;rbar. Dar&#252;ber hinaus sind sie die Voraussetzung f&#252;r den Bau von [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Universit&#228;ten[COLOR_REVERT], eines Weltwunders ([COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Gro&#223;e Bibliothek[COLOR_REVERT]) und der Nationalen Wunder [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Nationalepos[COLOR_REVERT].</German>
		<Italian>Le [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]biblioteche[COLOR_REVERT] aumentano la ricerca e la cultura delle citt&#224;. Sono necessarie per la realizzazione di [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]universit&#224;[COLOR_REVERT], della Meraviglia [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Grande Biblioteca[COLOR_REVERT] e delle Meraviglia Nazionali [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Poema Patriottico[COLOR_REVERT].</Italian>
		<Spanish>Las [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Bibliotecas[COLOR_REVERT] impulsan la investigaci&#243;n de las ciudades y proporcionan cultura. Son necesarias para construir [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Universidades[COLOR_REVERT], la maravilla de la [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Gran Biblioteca[COLOR_REVERT] y las maravilla nacionales de la [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Epopeya nacional[COLOR_REVERT].</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Manor -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANOR</Tag>
		<English>Manor</English>
		<French>Manoir</French>
		<German>Landgut</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANOR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A manor house or fortified manor-house is a country house, which has historically formed the administrative centre of a manor, the lowest unit of territorial organisation in the feudal system. The term is sometimes applied to relatively small country houses which belonged to gentry families, as well as to grand stately homes, particularly as a technical term for minor late medieval fortified country houses intended more for show than for defence. [PARAGRAPH:2]In general terms, the manor house was the dwelling house, or "capital messuage", of a feudal lord of a manor, which he occupied only on occasional visits if he held many manors. As such it was the place in which sessions of his "court baron", or manor court, were held. Sometimes a steward or seneschal was appointed by the seigniorial lord to oversee and manage his different manorial properties. The day-to-day administration was delegated to a bailiff, or reeve. [PARAGRAPH:2]Although not typically built with strong fortifications as castles were, many manor houses were partly fortified: they were enclosed within walls or ditches that often included the farm buildings as well. Many of them were equipped with small gatehouses and watchtowers. The primary feature of the manor house was its Great Hall, to which subsidiary apartments were added as the lessening of feudal warfare permitted more peaceful domestic life. [PARAGRAPH:2]By the beginning of the 16th century, manor houses as well as small castles began to acquire the character and amenities of the residences of country gentlemen. This late 16th century transformation produced many of the smaller Renaissance châteaux of France and the numerous country mansions of the Elizabethan and Jacobean styles in England.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANOR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Manufactory -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANUFACTORY</Tag>
		<English>Manufactory</English>
		<French>Manufacture</French>
		<German>Manufaktur</German>
		<Italian>Manifattura</Italian>
		<Spanish>Manufactura</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANUFACTORY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANUFACTORY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Manufacturing Plant -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANUFACTURING_PLANT</Tag>
		<English>Manufacturing Plant</English>
		<French>Complexe Industriel</French>
		<German>Industrieanlage</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANUFACTURING_PLANT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Manufacturing plant is an industrial building where workers manufacture goods or supervise machines processing one product into another. Most modern factories have large warehouses or warehouse-like facilities that contain heavy equipment used for assembly line production. Typically, factories gather and concentrate resources: workers, capital and plant.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANUFACTURING_PLANT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Manufacturing Plants increase cities' production by 65% with power.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Marina -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MARINA</Tag>
		<English>Marina</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Marina</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Marina</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MARINA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A marina is a sheltered harbor where boats and yachts are kept in the water and where services geared to the needs of recreational boating are found.  The marina may have re-fueling, washing and repair facilities, ship chandlers, stores and restaurants. Slipways are used to get a trailered boat into the water. Marinas may offer a boat hoist well, a type of traveling crane, instead of a more space-wasteful slipway, operated by service center personnel. Marinas may offer out-of-water-storage, which is useful out of season and important in latitudes susceptible to freezing waters.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MARINA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build Marinas to increase your cities specialists.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Masons Guild -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MASONS_GUILD</Tag>
		<English>Mason Guild</English>
		<French>Maison des Francs-Maçons</French>
		<German>Maurergilde</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MASONS_GUILD_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Masons Guild[COLOR_REVERT] to increase the production of your city, especially cathedrals.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MASONS_GUILD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Metropolitan Administration -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_METROPOLITAN_ADMINISTRATION</Tag>
		<English>Metropolitan Administration</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Cité Administrative</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Metropolis Verwaltung</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_METROPOLITAN_ADMINISTRATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Modern Granary -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MODERN_GRANARY</Tag>
		<English>Modern Granary</English>
		<French>Silot à Grain</French>
		<German>Moderner Kornspeicher</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MODERN_GRANARY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Modern Granaries[COLOR_REVERT] store food to help increase a city's growth rate. They add additional health if your civ has access to [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Corn[COLOR_REVERT], [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Wheat[COLOR_REVERT], [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Rice[COLOR_REVERT], and [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Potato[COLOR_REVERT].</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Modern Steelworks -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MODERN_STEELWORKS</Tag>
		<English>Modern Steelworks</English>
		<French>Aciérie Moderne</French>
		<German>Modernes Stahlwerk</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MODERN_STEELWORKS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MODERN_STEELWORKS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Moneylender -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MONEYLENDER</Tag>
		<English>Moneylender</English>
		<French>Prêteur</French>
		<German>Geldverleiher</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MONEYLENDER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Munitions Factory -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MUNITIONS_FACTORY</Tag>
		<English>Munitions Factory</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Usine de Munitions</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Munitionsfabrik</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MUNITIONS_FACTORY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A munitions factory specialises in filling various munitions, such as bombs, shells, cartridges, screening smokes, etc. In the UK, in both World Wars, the majority of the employees were women. Munitions factories had a large number of buildings. Buildings were needed on the various Groups for filling of munitions. Explosives magazines were required by each Group to store the incoming explosive materials and to store the outgoing filled shells or gun cartridges, usually packed in ammunition boxes. Storage buildings were also needed on each Group to store the incoming empty shells, or cartridges, and the empty ammunition boxes.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MUNITIONS_FACTORY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Munitions Factory manufactures [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ammunition[COLOR_REVERT] from Sulphur and other metal resources.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Nanofactory -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NANOFACTORY</Tag>
		<English>Nanofactory</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Usine de Nano-Composants</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Nanofabrik</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NANOFACTORY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A nanofactory is a system in which nanomachines (resembling molecular assemblers, or industrial robot arms) would combine reactive molecules via mechanosynthesis to build larger atomically precise parts. These, in turn, would be assembled by positioning mechanisms of assorted sizes to build macroscopic (visible) but still atomically-precise products.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NANOFACTORY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Nanofactory increases city's production.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- National Courier System -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_COURIER_SYSTEM</Tag>
		<English>National Courier System</English>
		<French>La Poste nationale</French>
		<German>Nationales Kuriersystem</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_COURIER_SYSTEM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_COURIER_SYSTEM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>With National Courier System the important military messages and news spread faster throughout your empire. This decreases the effects of anarchy periods and more great people appear among your citizens.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- National Slave Auction -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION</Tag>
		<English>National Slave Auction</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The national Slave Auction is a centralized slave sale and distribution center that provides an empire with the means to provide cheap labor to all cities of the empire.  Slaves were moved to areas requiring labor which guaranteed that they would never consume resourses without providing a benefit to their owners.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]National Slave Auction[COLOR_REVERT] provides a free Slave Market in all of your cities and a +1 happiness bonus in the founding city.  It increases it's city's odds of generating a Great Merchant.</English>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION_PYTHON</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_SELECTED_TEXT]The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]National Slave Auction[COLOR_SELECTED_TEXT] increases slavery infrastrucre nationwide[COLOR_REVERT]!</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- National TV Station -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_TV_STATION</Tag>
		<English>National TV-Station</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Station de Télévision Nationale</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Nationale TV-Station</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_TV_STATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A television station is a type of broadcast station that broadcasts both audio and video to television receivers in a particular area. Traditionally, TV stations made their broadcasts by sending specially-encoded radio signals over the air, called terrestrial television. Individual television stations are usually granted licenses by a government agency to use a particular section of the radio spectrum (a channel) through which they send their signals. Some stations use LPTV broadcast translators to retransmit to further areas. Many television stations are now in the process of converting from analogue (NTSC, PAL, or SECAM) to digital TV (ATSC, DVB, or ISDB).</English>
	</TEXT>
 	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_TV_STATION_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Network Node -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NETWORK_NODE</Tag>
		<English>Network Node</English>
		<French>Relais de Réseau</French>
		<German>Netzwerkknoten</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NETWORK_NODE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NETWORK_NODE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Pont du Gard -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PONT_DU_GARD_AQUEDUCT</Tag>
		<English>Pont du Gard</English>
		<French>Pont du Gard</French>
		<German>Pont du Gard</German>
		<Italian>Pont du Gard</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pont du Gard</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PONT_DU_GARD_AQUEDUCT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Pont du Gard is an aqueduct in the South of France constructed by the Roman Empire, and located in Vers-Pont-du-Gard near Remoulins, in the Gard département. Built on three levels, the Pont is 49 m high, and the longest level is 275 m (300 yards) long. On its first level, it carries a road and at the top of the third level, a water conduit, which is 1.8 metres (6 ft) high and 1.2 meters (4 ft) wide and has a gradient of 0.4 percent.[PARAGRAPH:2]It has long been thought that the Pont du Gard was built by Augustus' son-in-law and aide, Marcus Vipsanius Agrippa, around the year 19 BC. Newer excavations, however, suggest the construction may have taken place in the middle of the first century A.D, consequently, opinion is now somewhat divided on the matter. Designed to carry the water across the small Gardon river valley, it was part of a nearly 50 km (31 mi) aqueduct that brought water from the Fontaines d'Eure springs near Uzès to the Castellum in the Roman city of Nemausus (Nîmes). The full aqueduct had a gradient of 34 cm/km (1/3000), descending only 17 m vertically in its entire length and delivering 20,000 cubic meters (5 million gallons) of water daily. [PARAGRAPH:2]It was constructed entirely without the use of mortar. The aqueduct's stones - some of which weigh up to 6 tons - were precisely cut to fit perfectly together eliminating the need for mortar. The masonry was lifted into place by block and tackle with a massive human-powered treadmill providing the power for the winch. A complex scaffold was erected to support the aqueduct as it was being built. The face of the aqueduct still bears the mark of its construction, in the form of protruding scaffolding supports and ridges on the piers which supported the semicircular wooden frames on which the arches were constructed. It is believed to have taken about three years to build, employing between 800 and 1,000 workers.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PONT_DU_GARD_AQUEDUCT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Pont du Gard grants +2 health in all cities on the same continent.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Port -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PORT</Tag>
		<English>Port</English>
		<French>Grand Port</French>
		<German>Seehafen</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PORT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Just because a city is built in a coastal region doesn't guarantee that the city is readily accessible by ship. In order for a port city to establish a steady trade, fishing, or other shipping industry, the city must have a harbor. A harbor is a protected body of water that opens into an ocean or lake that shelters ships from waves and high winds. Although some coastal cities are established in areas where a natural harbor exists, most seaports are forced either to improve the existing natural harbor, or to build a man-made harbor to shelter ships and provide channels deep enough to accommodate large vessels.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Le fait de construire une ville dans une r&#233;gion c&#244;ti&#232;re ne lui garantit pas d'&#234;tre facilement accessible par bateau. Pour qu'une cit&#233; portuaire puisse &#233;tablir des industries de commerce, de p&#234;che et de transport maritime de fa&#231;on durable, elle doit avoir un port. Un port est une structure emprisonnant de l'eau mais ouvert sur l'oc&#233;an ou sur un lac et qui abrite les bateaux des vagues et des vents violents. Certaines villes portuaires sont construites dans des ports naturels mais la majorit&#233; des ports maritimes ne le sont pas. Dans ce cas, ces infrastructures permettent d'am&#233;liorer un port naturel existant ou de cr&#233;er un port artificiel pour abriter les navires et offrir des chenaux suffisamment profonds pour accueillir de grands bateaux.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Nur weil eine Stadt an der K&#252;ste liegt, bedeutet das nicht, dass sie f&#252;r Schiffe leicht zug&#228;nglich ist. Vielmehr muss eine solche K&#252;stenstadt einen Hafen unterhalten, damit sie sich aktiv am Seehandel, der Fischereiindustrie und anderen maritimen Unternehmungen beteiligen kann. Ein Hafen ist eine gesch&#252;tzte Wasserfl&#228;che, die sich zum Meer oder einem anderen offenen Gew&#228;sser hin &#246;ffnet und die vor Anker liegenden Schiffe vor Wellen und starken Windb&#246;en sch&#252;tzt. Auch wenn einige K&#252;stenst&#228;dte einen nat&#252;rlichen Hafen besitzen, so sind sie meist doch gezwungen, diesen entweder auszubauen oder zus&#228;tzlich einen k&#252;nstlichen Hafen anzulegen, um die einlaufenden Schiffe beherbergen und auch gro&#223;en Schiffen mit mehr Tiefgang Zugang gew&#228;hren zu k&#246;nnen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Solo perch&#233; una citt&#224; sorge sulla costa, non &#232; detto che sia facilmente accessibile alle navi e alle imbarcazioni. Affinch&#233; una citt&#224; di mare possa intraprendere solide attivit&#224; di commercio, pesca, o altre industrie navali, essa deve avere una baia. Questo &#232; uno specchio d'acqua che d&#224; sul mare o su un lago, protetta in modo da offrire ai natanti un riparo dalle onde e dai venti forti. Anche se molte citt&#224; sono sorte in luoghi gi&#224; dotati di una baia naturale, la maggior parte delle comunit&#224; portuali sono costrette o a migliorare quella esistente o a realizzarne una artificiale per assicurare una sufficiente navigabilit&#224; e accessibilit&#224; anche alle navi di maggiori dimensioni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]El hecho de que una ciudad est&#233; construida en una regi&#243;n costera no garantiza que se pueda acceder a ella por barco. Para que una ciudad portuaria pueda establecer una ruta de comercio estable, pescar o establecer cualquier tipo de industria naval, debe tener un puerto. Un puerto es una masa de agua protegida que se abre hacia el oc&#233;ano o un lago y protege a las naves del oleaje y los vientos. Aunque algunas ciudades costeras se encuentran en zonas en las que existe un puerto natural, la mayor&#237;a de los puertos marinos se ven obligados, bien a mejorar el puerto natural ya existente, bien a construir un puerto artificial para proteger a los barcos y proporcionar canales suficientemente profundos para albergar a buques de gran calado.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PORT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Port[COLOR_REVERT] increases that city's income from trade routes. It increases a city's health from access to [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Clam[COLOR_REVERT], and [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Crab[COLOR_REVERT] resources.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Postal Service -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_POSTAL_SERVICE</Tag>
		<English>Postal Service</English>
		<French>Bureau de Poste</French>
		<German>Postamt</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_POSTAL_SERVICE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Poultry Farm -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_POULTRY_FARM</Tag>
		<English>Poultry Farm</English>
		<Spanish>Granja Av&#237;cola</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POULTRY_FARM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Poultry Farm[COLOR_REVERT] rears chickens and other poultry for the purpose of providing food.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_POULTRY_FARM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Poultry Farm[COLOR_REVERT] to increase your cities' growth.</English>
		<Spanish>Construye una [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Granja Av&#237;cola[COLOR_REVERT] para incrementar el crecimiento de tus ciudades.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Quantum Lab -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_QUANTUM_LAB</Tag>
		<English>Quantum Lab</English>
		<French>Laboratoire Quantique</French>
		<German>Quantenlabor</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_QUANTUM_LAB_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_QUANTUM_LAB_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[SPACE]Quantum Lab gives +2 free scientists to city where it's built and the city is more likely to generate Great Scientists.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Ranch -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RANCH</Tag>
		<English>Ranch</English>
		<Spanish>Rancho</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RANCH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Ranch[COLOR_REVERT] is an area of landscape, including various structures, given primarily to the practice of ranching, the practice of raising grazing livestock such as cattle or sheep for meat or wool. The word most often applies to livestock-raising operations in the western United States and Canada, though there are ranches in other areas. People who own or operate a ranch are called stockgrowers or ranchers. Ranching is also a method used to raise less common livestock such as elk, American Bison or even ostrich and emu.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RANCH_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Ranch[COLOR_REVERT] to increase your cities' growth.</English>
		<Spanish>Construye un [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Rancho[COLOR_REVERT] para incrementar el crecimiento de tus ciudades.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Research Institute -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RESEARCH_INSTITUTE</Tag>
		<English>Research Institute </English>
		<French>Institut de Recherche</French>
		<German>Forschungsinstitut </German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RESEARCH_INSTITUTE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Research Institutes increse research and space ship construction at the cost of the cities productivity. They are prerequiste for more specialised research facilities.</English>
		<French>Research Institutes increse research and space ship construction at the cost of the cities productivity. They are prerequiste for more specialised research facilities.</French>
		<German>Forschungsinstitute verbessern die Forschung und Raumschiffkonstruktion einer Stadt auf Kosten ihrer Produktivität. Es sind Voraussetzung für den Bau spezialisierter Forschungseinrichtungen.</German>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT> <!-- Research Institute: Russian Nautschno-Issledowatelski Institute -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RUSSIAN_NII</Tag>
		<English>Nautschno-Issledowatelski Institute</English>
		<French>Institut Nautschno-issledowatelski</French>
		<German>Nautschno-Issledowatelski Institut</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RUSSIAN_NII_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Russian version of the Research Institute strongly increse research and space ship constructionat the cost of the cities productivity. They are prerequiste for more specialised research facilities.</English>
		<French>Russian version of the Research Institute strongly increse research and space ship constructionat the cost of the cities productivity. They are prerequiste for more specialised research facilities.</French>
		<German>Die Russische Variante des Forschungsinstitute verbessert die Forschung und Raumschiffkonstruktion wesentlicher stärker. Es sind Voraussetzung für den Bau spezialisierter Forschungseinrichtungen.</German>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT> <!-- School of Scribes -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SCHOOL_OF_SCRIBES</Tag>
		<English>School of Scribes</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Ecole des Scribes</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Schreiberschule</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SCHOOL_OF_SCRIBES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The School of Scribes is a place where people learn to read and write hieroglyphic and hieratic scripts.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SCHOOL_OF_SCRIBES_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases city's science output and generates some culture as well. Required before you can build Plato's Academy.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Shopping District -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHOPPING_DISTRICT</Tag>
		<English>Shopping District</English>
		<French>Centre Commercial</French>
		<German>Shoppingmeile</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHOPPING_DISTRICT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHOPPING_DISTRICT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Shopping District increases yield from trade routes.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Shrine -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Shrine</English>
		<French>Autel Sacré</French>
		<German>Schrein</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHRINE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Commerce boost with resources, however, this building becomes obsolete fast.  This building requires Folklore civic.</English>
		<French>Bonus de Commerce provenant des ressources. Cependant, le batiment est très vite obsolète. Requiert la Doctrine 'Folklore'.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Idolatry is usually defined as worship of any cult image, idea, or object, as opposed to the worship of a monotheistic God. It is considered a major sin in the Abrahamic religions whereas in religions where such activity is not considered as sin, the term "idolatry" itself is absent. Which images, ideas, and objects, constitute idolatry, and which constitute reasonable worship, is a matter of contention with some religious authorities and groups using the term to describe certain other religions apart from their own.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Siege Weapons Workshop -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SIEGE_WORKSHOP</Tag>
		<English>Siege Weapons Workshop</English>
		<French>Atelier d'Armes de Siège</French>
		<German>Werkstatt f&#252;r Belagerungswaffen</German>
		<Spanish>Taller de Armas de Ascedio</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SIEGE_WORKSHOP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Siege Weapon[COLOR_REVERT] is a device that is designed to break or circumvent city walls and other fortifications in siege warfare. [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Siege Weapons Workshops[COLOR_REVERT] are places where engineers developed Siege Weapons.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SIEGE_WORKSHOP_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Siege Weapons Workshop[COLOR_REVERT] to construct [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Catapults[COLOR_REVERT] and [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Trebuchets[COLOR_REVERT].</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Slave Market -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET</Tag>
		<English>Slave Market</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Slave Market is the local slave auction block in a city where slaves are displayed prior to sale.  Nearly all ancient civilizations were built on slave labour and slavery existed even in modern times despite attempts to stamp it out.  The slave market was a source of cheap labor and civic pride, as defeated rivals and captured enemies were often displayed for the amusement of the city's citizens prior to begining their labours to build up the very civilizations they opposed.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Slave Market[COLOR_REVERT] provides a 25% production bonus and a +1 happiness bonus in any city it is built in. Allows for the purchase of slaves. Doubles Production for leaders with Organized or Industrius traits.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- State School -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STATE_SCHOOL</Tag>
		<English>State School</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Ecole publique</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Schule</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STATE_SCHOOL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In most of the world, excluding England and Wales and some Commonwealth countries, a public school is an educational institution that is funded with tax revenue and most commonly administered by a local government or government agency. In England and Wales, the equivalent term would be state school.[PARAGRAPH:2]In most of the United Kingdom and in some Commonwealth countries, a public school is a traditional privately operated secondary school that is funded by the payment of tuition fees. These schools, wherever located, often follow a British educational tradition. Originally, many were single-sex boarding schools, but many are now co-educational with both boarders and day-pupils. This usage is synonymous with preparatory school in the USA, although in British English preparatory school has a different meaning. Whether a particular independent school is or is not a public school is not clearly defined, although there are some which indisputably are, and others which clearly are not. While this usage of the term public school is common in most of the United Kingdom, it can be ambiguous in Scotland, where it often refers to a publicly funded school.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STATE_SCHOOL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases city's science and culture output in city. Extra happiness from science and culture every 20%</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Steel Mill -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STEEL_MILL</Tag>
		<English>Steel Mill</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Aciérie</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Stahlm&#252;hle</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STEEL_MILL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A steel mill is an industrial plant for the manufacture of steel. [PARAGRAPH:2]Steel is an alloy of iron and carbon. It is produced in a two-stage process. First, iron ore is reduced or smelted with coke and limestone in a blast furnace, producing molten iron which is either cast into pig iron or carried to the next stage as molten iron. In the second stage, known as steelmaking, impurities such as sulfur, phosphorus, and excess carbon are removed and alloying elements such as manganese, nickel, chromium and vanadium added to produce the exact steel required.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STEEL_MILL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Steel Mill increases city's production and converts Iron and Coal to Steel resource. It replaces also Forge.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Stonemasons Workshop -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STONEMASONS_WORKSHOP</Tag>
		<English>Stonemasons Workshop</English>
		<French>Ateliers de Maçonnerie</French>
		<German>Steimetz</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STONEMASONS_WORKSHOP_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Stonemasons Workshop[COLOR_REVERT] to increase the production of your city.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STONEMASONS_WORKSHOP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Supercollider -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SUPERCOLLIDER</Tag>
		<English>Supercollider</English>
		<French>Supercollider</French>
		<German>Superbeschleuniger</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SUPERCOLLIDER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Large Hadron Collider (LHC) is the world's largest and highest-energy particle accelerator, intended to collide opposing particle beams, of either protons at an energy of 7 TeV per particle, or lead nuclei at an energy of 574 TeV per nucleus. The Large Hadron Collider was built by the European Organization for Nuclear Research (CERN) with the intention of testing various predictions of high-energy physics, including the existence of the hypothesized Higgs boson and of the large family of new particles predicted by supersymmetry. It lies in a tunnel 27 kilometres (17 mi) in circumference, as much as 175 metres (570 ft) beneath the Franco-Swiss border near Geneva, Switzerland. It is funded by and built in collaboration with over 10,000 scientists and engineers from over 100 countries as well as hundreds of universities and laboratories.[PARAGRAPH:2]On 10 September 2008, the proton beams were successfully circulated in the main ring of the LHC for the first time. On 19 September 2008, the operations were halted due to a serious fault between two superconducting bending magnets. Due to the time required to repair the resulting damage and to add additional safety features, the LHC is scheduled to be operational in mid-November 2009.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SUPERCOLLIDER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Supercollider is a very powerful accelerator which allows scientists to study quarks. Gives boost to city's science and spaceship production.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Tailor Shop -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAILOR_SHOP</Tag>
		<English>Tailor Shop</English>
		<French>Atelier du Tailleur</French>
		<German>Schneidergesch&#228;ft</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAILOR_SHOP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A tailor is a person who makes, repairs, or alters clothing professionally, especially suits and men's clothing.  Although the term dates to the thirteenth century, tailor took on its modern sense in the late eighteenth century, and now refers to makers of men's and women's suits, coats, trousers, and similar garments, usually of wool, linen, or silk.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAILOR_SHOP_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Makes use of "clothing" resources, providing Commerce and Happiness</English>
		<French>Procure une ressource 'Vêtement', fournissant commerce et bonheur</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Telephone Network -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TELEPHONE_NETWORK</Tag>
		<English>Telephone Network</English>
		<French>Réseau téléphonique</French>
		<German>Telefonnetz</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TELEPHONE_NETWORK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The first telephones had no network but were in private use, wired together in pairs. Users who wanted to talk to different people had as many telephones as necessary for the purpose. A user who wished to speak, whistled into the transmitter until the other party heard. Soon, however, a bell was added for signalling, and then a switchhook, and telephones took advantage of the exchange principle already employed in telegraph networks. Each telephone was wired to a local telephone exchange, and the exchanges were wired together with trunks. Networks were connected together in a hierarchical manner until they spanned cities, countries, continents and oceans. This was the beginning of the PSTN, though the term was unknown for many decades.[PARAGRAPH:2]Automation introduced pulse dialing between the phone and the exchange, and then among exchanges, followed by more sophisticated address signaling including multi-frequency, culminating in the SS7 network that connected most exchanges by the end of the 20th century.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TELEPHONE_NETWORK_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Town Hall -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWN_HALL</Tag>
		<English>Town Hall</English>
		<French>Hôtel de Ville</French>
		<German>Stadthaus</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWN_HALL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Townclock -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWNCLOCK</Tag>
		<English>Townclock</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Horloge publique</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Turmuhr</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWNCLOCK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A Town Clock or a clock tower is a tower built with one or more (often four) clock faces. The clock tower is usually part of a church or municipal building such as a town hall, but many clock towers are free-standing. [PARAGRAPH:2]The mechanism inside the tower is known as a turret clock. It often marks the hour (and sometimes segments of an hour) by sounding large bells or chimes, sometimes playing simple musical phrases or tunes. [PARAGRAPH:2]Although clock towers are today mostly admired for their aesthetics, they once served an important purpose. Before the middle of the twentieth century, most people did not have watches, and prior to the 18th century even home clocks were rare. The first clocks didn't have faces, but were solely striking clocks, which sounded bells to call the surrounding community to prayer. They were therefore placed in towers so the bells would be audible for a long distance. Clock towers were placed near the centers of towns and were often the tallest structures there. As clock towers became more common, the designers realized that a dial on the outside of the tower would allow the townspeople to read the time whenever they wanted.[PARAGRAPH:2]The use of clock towers dates back to the Middle Ages. The earliest clock tower was constructed by Su Song in Kaifeng, China, and completed in 1088. The first striking clock tower was constructed shortly after in 1154 near the Umayyad Mosque in Damascus, Syria, by the Arab engineer al-Kaysarani. The earliest clock tower in Europe was the Salisbury cathedral clock in England, completed in 1306.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWNCLOCK_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases production in city but the downside is slightly higher maintenance costs.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Trade Union -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRADE_UNION</Tag>
		<English>Trade Union</English>
		<French>Syndicat</French>
		<German>Gewerkschaft</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRADE_UNION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A trade union (or labour union) is an organization of workers who have banded together to achieve common goals in key areas, such as working conditions. The trade union, through its leadership, bargains with the employer on behalf of union members (rank and file members) and negotiates labour contracts (Collective bargaining) with employers. This may include the negotiation of wages, work rules, complaint procedures, rules governing hiring, firing and promotion of workers, benefits, workplace safety and policies. The agreements negotiated by the union leaders are binding on the rank and file members and the employer and in some cases on other non-member workers.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRADE_UNION_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Trade union national wonder increases happiness and healthiness on whole continent.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Training Yard -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRAINING_YARD</Tag>
		<English>Training Yard</English>
		<French>Cour d'Entraînement</French>
		<German>Übungsplatz</German>
		<Italian>Training Yard</Italian>
		<Spanish>Campo de Entrenamiento</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRAINING_YARD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]All men who want to fight need some form of training if they are to be more than just fodder for war. This basic training is performed in a cities training yard where experienced troops will pass on their knowledge to the new fighters in hope that they will at least survive their first battle.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRAINING_YARD_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a Training Yard to increase your fighters experience and hpoefully get them their first promotion</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Treadmill Crane -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TREADMILL_CRANE</Tag>
		<English>Treadmill Crane</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TREADMILL_CRANE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A treadwheel crane (magna rola) is a wooden, human powered, hoisting and lowering device. It was primarily used during Roman times and the Middle Ages in the building of castles and cathedrals. The often heavy charge is lifted as the individual inside the treadwheel crane walks. The rope attached to a pulley is turned onto a spindle by the rotation of the wheel thus allowing the device to hoist or lower the affixed pallet.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TREADMILL_CRANE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases production for Buildings.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Utility Fog -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_UTILITY_FOG</Tag>
		<English>Utility Fog</English>
		<French>Brouillard Utile</French>
		<German>Utility-Nebel</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_UTILITY_FOG_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Utility Fog is a collection of tiny robots together performing a certain function. The idea of nanobotic swarms was detailed as early as in 1964 by Stanislaw Lem in the novel The Invincible, and explored in some recent SciFi novels, such as Prey (2002), written by Michael Crichton. When self-replication is taken as an additional feature of such devices, the possibility of losing control of the swarm is the basis of post-apocalyptic scenarios such as the Grey goo.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_UTILITY_FOG_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[SPACE]Utility Fog increases city's production and defense.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Village Hall -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_VILLAGE_HALL</Tag>
		<English>Village Hall</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Salle des Fêtes</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Gemaindehaus</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_VILLAGE_HALL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CITYBUILDINGS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build Village Halls, Town Halls and City Councils to add free specialist in your cities.</English>
		<French>Construisez Salle des fêtes, Hôtel de Ville, Conseil Municipal,... pour ajouter des spécialistes gratuitement dans vos Villes.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Weavers Hut -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WEAVERS_HUT</Tag>
		<English>Weaver's Hut</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Hutte du Tisserand</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Weberh&#252;tte</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WEAVERS_HUT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Weaving, the art of forming a fabric by interlacing at right angles two or more sets of yarn or other material. It is one of the most ancient fundamental arts, as indicated by archaeological evidence. Discoveries in the early 1990s in the Czech Republic point to an origin in the Paleolithic period some 27,000 years ago. Moreover, the earliest literatures often mention the products of the loom. In primitive cultures weaving was practiced mainly by women.[PARAGRAPH:2]Although weaving sprang up independently in different parts of the world and was early known in Europe, its high development there in the Middle Ages was brought about by Eastern influences operating through Muslim and Byzantine channels of culture. Byzantium became a center of silk weaving in the 6th cent. In the 9th cent. Greece, Italy, and Spain became proficient. In Flanders a high degree of skill was attained by the 10th cent., especially in the weaving of wool. Flemish weavers brought to England by William the Conqueror and later by Queen Elizabeth I gave a great impetus to the craft there, and Lancashire became an important center. Tapestry weaving was brought to a high art in France. In colonial America weaving was a household industry allied with agriculture.[PARAGRAPH:2]The 18th-century weaving and spinning inventions marked the transition from the old era of domestic craftsmanship to the tremendous, organized industry of today. The factory system of machine weaving produces quantities of standardized material for mass consumption; the result is a loss of the distinctive elements of quality and design. Some of the finest silks, velvets, table linens, and carpets are still woven on handlooms.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WEAVERS_HUT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Makes use of "clothing" resources, providing Commerce</English>
		<French>Procure une ressource 'Vêtement', fournissant du commerce</French>
		<German>Erzeugt die Ressource "Kleidung", erzeugt Handel</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- World Bank -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WORLD_BANK</Tag>
		<English>World Bank</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Banque Mondiale</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Weltbank</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WORLD_BANK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The World Bank is one of two major institutions created as a result of the Bretton Woods Conference in 1944. The International Monetary Fund, a related but separate institution, is the second. Delegates from a wide variety of countries attended the Bretton Woods Conference, but the most powerful countries in attendance, the United States and Britain, mainly shaped negotiations.[PARAGRAPH:2]From its conception until 1967 the bank undertook a relatively low level of lending. Fiscal conservatism and careful screening of loan applications was generally accepted practice at the World Bank during this early period. Bank staff attempted to balance the priorities of providing loans for reconstruction and development with the need to instill confidence in the bank as a reliable institution suitable for investment.  Bank president John McCloy selected France to be the first recipient of World Bank aid; two other applications presented at this time from Poland and Chile was rejected. The loan was for $ 987 million, half the amount requested, and came with strict conditions. Staff from the World Bank would monitor the end use of the funds, ensuring that the French government would present a balanced budget, and give priority of debt repayment to the World Bank over other foreign governments. The United States State Department also acted at this time to inform the French Government that Communist elements within the Cabinétte needed to be removed. The French Government complied with this request and removed the Communist elements from the 1947 coalition government. Within hours of this event the loan to France was approved.  The Marshall Plan of 1947 caused lending practices at the bank to be altered, as many European countries received aid that competed directly with World Bank loans. Emphasis was shifted to non-European countries and up until 1968 loans were primarily earmarked for projects that would directly enable a borrower country to repay loans (such projects as ports, highway systems, and power plants).[PARAGRAPH:2]From 1968-1980 the bank focused on poverty alleviation and meeting the basic needs of people in the developing world. During this period the size and number of loans to borrower nations was greatly increased as the spectrum of loan targets expanded from infrastructure into social services and other sectors. These changes can to a large extent be attributed to Robert McNamara who assumed the Presidency in 1968 after being appointed by US president Lyndon B. Johnson.  McNamara imported a technocratic managerial style to the bank that he had employed during periods he had spent serving as United States Secretary of Defense, and President of the Ford Motor Company.  McNamara shifted the focus of bank policy towards measures such as building schools and hospitals, improving literacy rates and conducting large-scale agricultural reform. McNamara created a new system of gathering information from potential borrower nations that enabled the bank to process loan applications at a much faster rate. In order to finance the increased loan volume, McNamara tasked bank treasurer Eugene Rotberg to seek out new sources of capital outside of the northern banks that had previously been the primary sources of bank funding. Rotberg utilized the global bond market to greatly increase the amount of capital available to the bank.  One consequence of the period of poverty alleviation lending was the rapid rise of third world debt. From 1976-1980 third world debt rose at an average annual rate of 20%.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1980 A.W. Clausen replaced Robert McNamara as World Bank president after being nominated by US President Ronald Reagan. Clausen replaced a large number of bank staffers who had been active during the McNamara era and instituted a new ideological focus in the bank. The replacement of Chief Economist Hollis B. Chenery by Anne Krueger in 1982 marked a notable policy shift at the bank. Krueger was known for her criticism of development funding as well as third world governments as rent-seeking states.  Lending for the purposes of servicing third world debt largely marked the period of 1980-1989. Structural adjustment policies aimed at streamlining the economies of developing nations (largely at the expense of health and social services reductions) were also a large part of World Bank policy during this period. UNICEF reported in the late 1980s that the structural adjustment programs of the World Bank were responsible for the "reduced health, nutritional, and educational levels for tens of millions of children in Asia, Latin America, and Africa".[PARAGRAPH:2]From 1989 to present, World Bank policy has shifted greatly, largely in response to criticism from a plurality of groups. Environmental groups and NGOs are often now integrated into the lending practices of the bank in order to mitigate the negative results of the previous era that prompted such harsh criticism.  Bank projects now explicitly embrace a "green" focus.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WORLD_BANK_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]World Bank[COLOR_REVERT] Instant increase in your [ICON_GOLD] reserves, and provides annual interest on your reserves.</English>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Special Building Strings +++ -->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPECIALBUILDING_CLONING_LABORATORY</Tag>
		<English>Cloning Laboratory</English>
		<French>Laboratoire de Clonage</French>
		<German>Klonlabor</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPECIALBUILDING_WORLD_BANK</Tag>
		<English>World Bank</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Banque Mondiale</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Weltbank</German>
	</TEXT>

</Civ4GameText>