<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Game Text - New -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT> <!-- Lepinski Vir -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEPENSKI_VIR</Tag>
		<English>Lepenski Vir</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEPENSKI_VIR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT]Lepenski Vir[COLOR_REVERT] is an important Mesolithic archaeological site located in Serbia in the central Balkan peninsula. It consists of one large settlement with around ten satellite villages. The evidence suggests the first human presence in the locality around 7000 BC with the culture reaching its peak between 5300 BC and 4800 BC. Numerous piscine sculptures and peculiar architecture are testimony to a rich social and religious life led by the inhabitants and the high cultural level of these early Europeans.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]This is clearly evident in the layout of the Lepenski Vir Ia-e settlement. The village is well planned. All houses are built according to one complex geometric pattern. These remains of houses constitute the distinct Lepenski Vir architecture, one of the important achievements of this culture. The main layout of the village is clearly visible. The dead were buried outside the village in an elaborate cemetery. The only exceptions were apparently a few notable elders who were buried behind the fireplaces in houses, according to a religious ritual.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]The complex social structure was dominated by a religious cult which probably served as a binding force for the community and a means of coordination of activity for its members. Numerous sacral objects that were discovered in this layer support this theory. The most remarkable examples are piscine sculptures, unique to the Lepenski Vir culture, which represent one of the first examples of monumental sacral art on European soil.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEPENSKI_VIR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build the [COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT]Lepenski Vir[COLOR_REVERT] to get a free [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Sacrificial Altar[COLOR_REVERT] in every city.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Library -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LIBRARY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Libraries[COLOR_REVERT] boost your cities' research and provide culture. They are required to build [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Universities[COLOR_REVERT], the [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Great Library[COLOR_REVERT] wonder, and the [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]National Epic[COLOR_REVERT] national wonder.</English>
		<French>Les [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]biblioth&#232;ques[COLOR_REVERT] am&#233;liorent la recherche et produisent de la culture. Elles sont n&#233;cessaires pour construire des [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]universit&#233;s[COLOR_REVERT], la [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Grande biblioth&#232;que[COLOR_REVERT], et l'[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Epop&#233;e nationale[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Bibliotheken[COLOR_REVERT] erh&#246;hen den kulturellen Wert einer Stadt und beschleunigen die Forschung sp&#252;rbar. Dar&#252;ber hinaus sind sie die Voraussetzung f&#252;r den Bau von [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Universit&#228;ten[COLOR_REVERT], eines Weltwunders ([COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Gro&#223;e Bibliothek[COLOR_REVERT]) und der Nationalen Wunder [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Nationalepos[COLOR_REVERT].</German>
		<Italian>Le [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]biblioteche[COLOR_REVERT] aumentano la ricerca e la cultura delle citt&#224;. Sono necessarie per la realizzazione di [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]universit&#224;[COLOR_REVERT], della Meraviglia [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Grande Biblioteca[COLOR_REVERT] e delle Meraviglia Nazionali [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Poema Patriottico[COLOR_REVERT].</Italian>
		<Spanish>Las [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Bibliotecas[COLOR_REVERT] impulsan la investigaci&#243;n de las ciudades y proporcionan cultura. Son necesarias para construir [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Universidades[COLOR_REVERT], la maravilla de la [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Gran Biblioteca[COLOR_REVERT] y las maravilla nacionales de la [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Epopeya nacional[COLOR_REVERT].</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- National Slave Auction -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION</Tag>
		<English>National Slave Auction</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The national Slave Auction is a centralized slave sale and distribution center that provides an empire with the means to provide cheap labor to all cities of the empire.  Slaves were moved to areas requiring labor which guaranteed that they would never consume resourses without providing a benefit to their owners.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]National Slave Auction[COLOR_REVERT] provides a free Slave Market in all of your cities and a +1 happiness bonus in the founding city.  It increases it's city's odds of generating a Great Merchant.</English>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION_PYTHON</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_SELECTED_TEXT]The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]National Slave Auction[COLOR_SELECTED_TEXT] increases slavery infrastrucre nationwide[COLOR_REVERT]!</English>
	</TEXT>

	<TEXT> <!-- Slave Market -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET</Tag>
		<English>Slave Market</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Slave Market is the local slave auction block in a city where slaves are displayed prior to sale.  Nearly all ancient civilizations were built on slave labour and slavery existed even in modern times despite attempts to stamp it out.  The slave market was a source of cheap labor and civic pride, as defeated rivals and captured enemies were often displayed for the amusement of the city's citizens prior to begining their labours to build up the very civilizations they opposed.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Slave Market[COLOR_REVERT] provides a 25% production bonus and a +1 happiness bonus in any city it is built in. Allows for the purchase of slaves. Doubles Production for leaders with Organized or Industrius traits.</English>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>