<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Game Text - New -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT> <!-- Brightsmiths Hut -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BRIGHTSMITHS_HUT</Tag>
		<English>Brightsmith's Hut</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BRIGHTSMITHS_HUT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The brightsmith is a metalworker that works with the lighter metals such as gold and silver.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BRIGHTSMITHS_HUT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Makes use of unrefined metals resources, providing Commerce</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Capital Administration -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAPITAL_ADMINISTRATION</Tag>
		<English>Capital Administration</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Administration de la Capitale</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Capital Verwaltung</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAPITAL_ADMINISTRATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- City Council -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CITY_COUNCIL</Tag>
		<English>City Council</English>
		<French>Conseil Municipal</French>
		<German>Stadtrat</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CITY_COUNCIL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT> <!-- Commercial Port -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COMMERCIAL_PORT</Tag>
		<English>Commercial Port</English>
		<French>Port Commercial</French>
		<German>Handelshafen</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COMMERCIAL_PORT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COMMERCIAL_PORT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Commercial Ports increase coastal cities' trade routes and commerce and happiness. They are required to build International Ports.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Construction Firm -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONSTRUCTION_FIRM</Tag>
		<English>Construction Firm</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Entreprise de Construction</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Bauunternehmer</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONSTRUCTION_FIRM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In the fields of architecture and civil engineering, construction is a process that consists of the building or assembling of infrastructure. Far from being a single activity, large scale construction is a feat of multitasking. Normally the job is managed by the project manager and supervised by the construction manager, design engineer, construction engineer or project architect.  For the successful execution of a project, effective planning is essential. Those involved with the design and execution of the infrastructure in question must consider the environmental impact of the job, the successful scheduling, budgeting, site safety, availability of materials, logistics, inconvenience to the public caused by construction delays, preparing tender documents, etc.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONSTRUCTION_FIRM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases Production for Buildings.</English>
		<French>Augmente la vitesse de Construction des Bâtiments.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Container Port -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONTAINER_PORT</Tag>
		<English>Container Port</English>
		<French>Grand Port de Container</French>
		<German>Containerhafen</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONTAINER_PORT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONTAINER_PORT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Container ports significantly increase coastal cities' commerce but at the cost of increased polution.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Fish Market -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISH_MARKET</Tag>
		<English>Fish Market</English>
		<French>Marché aux poissons</French>
		<German>Fischmarkt</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISH_MARKET_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Fish Markets grant a health bonus and allow faster growth. they also increase the commerce gain.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISH_MARKET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Fish Market[COLOR_REVERT] is a marketplace used for marketing fish products. It can be dedicated to wholesale trade between fishermen and fish merchants, or to the sale of seafood to individual consumers, or to both. Retail fish markets, a type of wet market, often sell street food as well.[PARAGRAPH:1]Because seafood is quick to spoil, fish markets are historically most often found in seaside towns. Once ice or other simple cooling  methods became available, some were also established in large inland cities that had good trade routes to the coast.[PARAGRAPH:1]Since refrigeration and rapid transport became available in the 19th and 20th century, fish markets can technically be established at any place. However, because modern trade logistics in general has shifted away from marketplaces and towards retail outlets, such as supermarkets, most seafood worldwide is now sold to consumers through these venues, like most other foodstuffs.[PARAGRAPH:1]Consequently, most major fish markets now mainly deal with wholesale trade, and the existing major fish retail markets continue to operate as much for traditional reasons as for commercial ones. Both types of fish markets are often tourist attractions as well.</English>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT> <!-- Fish Traps -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISHTRAPS</Tag>
		<English>Fish Traps</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Pièges à Poissons</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Fischreusen</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISHTRAPS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Fish are an important part of diets for many cultures, since fish can be easily salted and dried and are rich in protein.  Fish traps allow fish migrating in rivers or coastal areas to be easily caught.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISHTRAPS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The ability to catch fish in rivers and the coastline increases Food</English>
		<French>La possibilité de piéger des poissons augmente la Nourriture</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Fisherman's Hut -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISHERMANS_HUT</Tag>
		<English>Fisherman's Hut</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Cabane du Pêcheur</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Fischerh&#252;tte</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISHERMANS_HUT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB] A fishmonger (fishwife for women practitioners - "wife" in this case used in its archaic meaning of "woman") is someone who sells fish and seafood. In some countries modern supermarkets are replacing fishmongers who operate in shops or markets.  Fishmongers are trained at selecting and purchasing, handling, gutting, boning, filleting, displaying, merchandising and selling their product. In many places fishmongers, like butchers, are a dying breed. With the advent of many modern ways of distributing and packaging food, supermarkets often opt for less expensive alternatives to these trained, highly skilled professionals.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISHERMAN_HUTS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Can be built only in coastal city</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Peut être construit uniquement dans une Ville côtière</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Kann nur in K&#252;stenst&#228;dten gebaut werden</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISHERMAN_HUTS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Fisherman's Hut increases city's food production if city has access to Fish, Crab and Whale resources.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Furrier -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FURRIER</Tag>
		<English>Furrier</English>
		<French>Fourreur</French>
		<German>K&#252;rschner</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FURRIER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Originally, Russia exported a majority in raw furs of the pelts of martens, beavers, wolves, foxes, squirrels and hares. Between the 16th and 18th centuries, Russians tamed Siberia, a region rich in many mammal species, such as Arctic fox, lynx, sable, sea otter and stoat (ermine). In the search for the prized sea otter (pelts first used in China), and, later the northern fur seal, the Russian Empire expanded into North America, notably Alaska. Between the 17th and second half of the 19th century, Russia was the largest supplier of fur in the world. The fur trade played a vital role in the development of Siberia, the Russian Far East and the Russian colonization of the Americas. To this day sable is a regional symbol of Ural Sverdlovsk oblast and Siberian Novosibirsk, Tyumen and Irkutsk oblasts of Russia.  The European discovery of North America, with its vast forests and wild-life, particularly the beaver, led to the continent's becoming a major supplier in the 17th century of fur pelts for the fur-felt hat and fur trimming and garment trades of Europe. Fur was a major source of warmth in clothing, critical prior to the organisation of coal distribution.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FURRIER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Adds gold and commerce with Fur; Resource requirement.</English>
		<French>Ajoute de l'Or et du commerce avec la ressource Fourrure (nécessaire)</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Harbour -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HARBOUR</Tag>
		<English>Harbour</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Port</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Hafen</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Porto:Porti</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Puerto:Puertos</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HARBOUR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Just because a city is built in a coastal region doesn't guarantee that the city is readily accessible by ship. In order for a port city to establish a steady trade, fishing, or other shipping industry, the city must have a harbour. A harbour is a protected body of water that opens into an ocean or lake that shelters ships from waves and high winds. Although some coastal cities are established in areas where a natural harbour exists, most seaports are forced either to improve the existing natural harbour, or to build a man-made harbour to shelter ships and provide channels deep enough to accommodate large vessels.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Le fait de construire une ville dans une r&#233;gion c&#244;ti&#232;re ne lui garantit pas d'&#234;tre facilement accessible par bateau. Pour qu'une cit&#233; portuaire puisse &#233;tablir des industries de commerce, de p&#234;che et de transport maritime de fa&#231;on durable, elle doit avoir un port. Un port est une structure emprisonnant de l'eau mais ouvert sur l'oc&#233;an ou sur un lac et qui abrite les bateaux des vagues et des vents violents. Certaines villes portuaires sont construites dans des ports naturels mais la majorit&#233; des ports maritimes ne le sont pas. Dans ce cas, ces infrastructures permettent d'am&#233;liorer un port naturel existant ou de cr&#233;er un port artificiel pour abriter les navires et offrir des chenaux suffisamment profonds pour accueillir de grands bateaux.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Nur weil eine Stadt an der K&#252;ste liegt, bedeutet das nicht, dass sie f&#252;r Schiffe leicht zug&#228;nglich ist. Vielmehr muss eine solche K&#252;stenstadt einen Hafen unterhalten, damit sie sich aktiv am Seehandel, der Fischereiindustrie und anderen maritimen Unternehmungen beteiligen kann. Ein Hafen ist eine gesch&#252;tzte Wasserfl&#228;che, die sich zum Meer oder einem anderen offenen Gew&#228;sser hin &#246;ffnet und die vor Anker liegenden Schiffe vor Wellen und starken Windb&#246;en sch&#252;tzt. Auch wenn einige K&#252;stenst&#228;dte einen nat&#252;rlichen Hafen besitzen, so sind sie meist doch gezwungen, diesen entweder auszubauen oder zus&#228;tzlich einen k&#252;nstlichen Hafen anzulegen, um die einlaufenden Schiffe beherbergen und auch gro&#223;en Schiffen mit mehr Tiefgang Zugang gew&#228;hren zu k&#246;nnen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Solo perch&#233; una citt&#224; sorge sulla costa, non &#232; detto che sia facilmente accessibile alle navi e alle imbarcazioni. Affinch&#233; una citt&#224; di mare possa intraprendere solide attivit&#224; di commercio, pesca, o altre industrie navali, essa deve avere una baia. Questo &#232; uno specchio d'acqua che d&#224; sul mare o su un lago, protetta in modo da offrire ai natanti un riparo dalle onde e dai venti forti. Anche se molte citt&#224; sono sorte in luoghi gi&#224; dotati di una baia naturale, la maggior parte delle comunit&#224; portuali sono costrette o a migliorare quella esistente o a realizzarne una artificiale per assicurare una sufficiente navigabilit&#224; e accessibilit&#224; anche alle navi di maggiori dimensioni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]El hecho de que una ciudad est&#233; construida en una regi&#243;n costera no garantiza que se pueda acceder a ella por barco. Para que una ciudad portuaria pueda establecer una ruta de comercio estable, pescar o establecer cualquier tipo de industria naval, debe tener un puerto. Un puerto es una masa de agua protegida que se abre hacia el oc&#233;ano o un lago y protege a las naves del oleaje y los vientos. Aunque algunas ciudades costeras se encuentran en zonas en las que existe un puerto natural, la mayor&#237;a de los puertos marinos se ven obligados, bien a mejorar el puerto natural ya existente, bien a construir un puerto artificial para proteger a los barcos y proporcionar canales suficientemente profundos para albergar a buques de gran calado.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HARBOUR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Harbour[COLOR_REVERT] increases that city's income from trade routes. It increases a city's health from access to [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Clam[COLOR_REVERT], [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Crab[COLOR_REVERT], and [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Fish[COLOR_REVERT] resources.</English>
		<French>Les [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]ports[COLOR_REVERT] augmentent les revenus g&#233;n&#233;r&#233;s par les routes commerciales des villes. Ils am&#233;liorent la sant&#233; des citoyens dans les villes qui peuvent p&#234;cher des [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]coquillages[COLOR_REVERT], du [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]crabe[COLOR_REVERT] et du [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]poisson[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>Ein [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Hafen[COLOR_REVERT] erh&#246;ht das Handelseinkommen einer Stadt und erschlie&#223;t die Ressourcen [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Muscheln[COLOR_REVERT], [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Krabben[COLOR_REVERT] und [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Fisch[COLOR_REVERT]. Diese wirken sich wiederum positiv auf die Gesundheit Ihrer Bev&#246;lkerung aus.</German>
		<Italian>Il [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]porto[COLOR_REVERT] aumenta il guadagno della citt&#224; da parte delle rotte commerciali. Inoltre, con l'accesso a [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Molluschi[COLOR_REVERT], [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Crostacei[COLOR_REVERT] e [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Pesci[COLOR_REVERT], aumenta la salute della citt&#224;.</Italian>
		<Spanish>El [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Puerto[COLOR_REVERT] aumenta los ingresos por rutas comerciales de la ciudad. Tambi&#233;n incrementa su salud por acceder a los recursos de las [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Almejas[COLOR_REVERT], los [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Cangrejos[COLOR_REVERT] y el [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Pescado[COLOR_REVERT].</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Jumplane Portal -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JUMPLANE_PORTAL</Tag>
		<English>Jumplane Portal</English>
		<French>Portail de Saut</French>
		<German>Jumplaneportal</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JUMPLANE_PORTAL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Jumplane Portals boost your commerce income - especially from trade routes.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JUMPLANE_PORTAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT> <!-- Lepinski Vir -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEPENSKI_VIR</Tag>
		<English>Lepenski Vir</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEPENSKI_VIR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT]Lepenski Vir[COLOR_REVERT] is an important Mesolithic archaeological site located in Serbia in the central Balkan peninsula. It consists of one large settlement with around ten satellite villages. The evidence suggests the first human presence in the locality around 7000 BC with the culture reaching its peak between 5300 BC and 4800 BC. Numerous piscine sculptures and peculiar architecture are testimony to a rich social and religious life led by the inhabitants and the high cultural level of these early Europeans.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]This is clearly evident in the layout of the Lepenski Vir Ia-e settlement. The village is well planned. All houses are built according to one complex geometric pattern. These remains of houses constitute the distinct Lepenski Vir architecture, one of the important achievements of this culture. The main layout of the village is clearly visible. The dead were buried outside the village in an elaborate cemetery. The only exceptions were apparently a few notable elders who were buried behind the fireplaces in houses, according to a religious ritual.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]The complex social structure was dominated by a religious cult which probably served as a binding force for the community and a means of coordination of activity for its members. Numerous sacral objects that were discovered in this layer support this theory. The most remarkable examples are piscine sculptures, unique to the Lepenski Vir culture, which represent one of the first examples of monumental sacral art on European soil.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEPENSKI_VIR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build the [COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT]Lepenski Vir[COLOR_REVERT] to get a free [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Sacrificial Altar[COLOR_REVERT] in every city.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Library -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LIBRARY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Libraries[COLOR_REVERT] boost your cities' research and provide culture. They are required to build [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Universities[COLOR_REVERT], the [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Great Library[COLOR_REVERT] wonder, and the [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]National Epic[COLOR_REVERT] national wonder.</English>
		<French>Les [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]biblioth&#232;ques[COLOR_REVERT] am&#233;liorent la recherche et produisent de la culture. Elles sont n&#233;cessaires pour construire des [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]universit&#233;s[COLOR_REVERT], la [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Grande biblioth&#232;que[COLOR_REVERT], et l'[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Epop&#233;e nationale[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Bibliotheken[COLOR_REVERT] erh&#246;hen den kulturellen Wert einer Stadt und beschleunigen die Forschung sp&#252;rbar. Dar&#252;ber hinaus sind sie die Voraussetzung f&#252;r den Bau von [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Universit&#228;ten[COLOR_REVERT], eines Weltwunders ([COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Gro&#223;e Bibliothek[COLOR_REVERT]) und der Nationalen Wunder [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Nationalepos[COLOR_REVERT].</German>
		<Italian>Le [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]biblioteche[COLOR_REVERT] aumentano la ricerca e la cultura delle citt&#224;. Sono necessarie per la realizzazione di [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]universit&#224;[COLOR_REVERT], della Meraviglia [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Grande Biblioteca[COLOR_REVERT] e delle Meraviglia Nazionali [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Poema Patriottico[COLOR_REVERT].</Italian>
		<Spanish>Las [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Bibliotecas[COLOR_REVERT] impulsan la investigaci&#243;n de las ciudades y proporcionan cultura. Son necesarias para construir [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Universidades[COLOR_REVERT], la maravilla de la [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Gran Biblioteca[COLOR_REVERT] y las maravilla nacionales de la [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Epopeya nacional[COLOR_REVERT].</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Masons Guild -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MASONS_GUILD</Tag>
		<English>Mason Guild</English>
		<French>Maison des Francs-Maçons</French>
		<German>Maurergilde</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MASONS_GUILD_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Masons Guild[COLOR_REVERT] to increase the production of your city, especially cathedrals.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MASONS_GUILD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Metropolitan Administration -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_METROPOLITAN_ADMINISTRATION</Tag>
		<English>Metropolitan Administration</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Cité Administrative</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Metropolis Verwaltung</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_METROPOLITAN_ADMINISTRATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- National Slave Auction -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION</Tag>
		<English>National Slave Auction</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The national Slave Auction is a centralized slave sale and distribution center that provides an empire with the means to provide cheap labor to all cities of the empire.  Slaves were moved to areas requiring labor which guaranteed that they would never consume resourses without providing a benefit to their owners.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]National Slave Auction[COLOR_REVERT] provides a free Slave Market in all of your cities and a +1 happiness bonus in the founding city.  It increases it's city's odds of generating a Great Merchant.</English>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION_PYTHON</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_SELECTED_TEXT]The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]National Slave Auction[COLOR_SELECTED_TEXT] increases slavery infrastrucre nationwide[COLOR_REVERT]!</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Port -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PORT</Tag>
		<English>Port</English>
		<French>Grand Port</French>
		<German>Seehafen</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PORT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Just because a city is built in a coastal region doesn't guarantee that the city is readily accessible by ship. In order for a port city to establish a steady trade, fishing, or other shipping industry, the city must have a harbor. A harbor is a protected body of water that opens into an ocean or lake that shelters ships from waves and high winds. Although some coastal cities are established in areas where a natural harbor exists, most seaports are forced either to improve the existing natural harbor, or to build a man-made harbor to shelter ships and provide channels deep enough to accommodate large vessels.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Le fait de construire une ville dans une r&#233;gion c&#244;ti&#232;re ne lui garantit pas d'&#234;tre facilement accessible par bateau. Pour qu'une cit&#233; portuaire puisse &#233;tablir des industries de commerce, de p&#234;che et de transport maritime de fa&#231;on durable, elle doit avoir un port. Un port est une structure emprisonnant de l'eau mais ouvert sur l'oc&#233;an ou sur un lac et qui abrite les bateaux des vagues et des vents violents. Certaines villes portuaires sont construites dans des ports naturels mais la majorit&#233; des ports maritimes ne le sont pas. Dans ce cas, ces infrastructures permettent d'am&#233;liorer un port naturel existant ou de cr&#233;er un port artificiel pour abriter les navires et offrir des chenaux suffisamment profonds pour accueillir de grands bateaux.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Nur weil eine Stadt an der K&#252;ste liegt, bedeutet das nicht, dass sie f&#252;r Schiffe leicht zug&#228;nglich ist. Vielmehr muss eine solche K&#252;stenstadt einen Hafen unterhalten, damit sie sich aktiv am Seehandel, der Fischereiindustrie und anderen maritimen Unternehmungen beteiligen kann. Ein Hafen ist eine gesch&#252;tzte Wasserfl&#228;che, die sich zum Meer oder einem anderen offenen Gew&#228;sser hin &#246;ffnet und die vor Anker liegenden Schiffe vor Wellen und starken Windb&#246;en sch&#252;tzt. Auch wenn einige K&#252;stenst&#228;dte einen nat&#252;rlichen Hafen besitzen, so sind sie meist doch gezwungen, diesen entweder auszubauen oder zus&#228;tzlich einen k&#252;nstlichen Hafen anzulegen, um die einlaufenden Schiffe beherbergen und auch gro&#223;en Schiffen mit mehr Tiefgang Zugang gew&#228;hren zu k&#246;nnen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Solo perch&#233; una citt&#224; sorge sulla costa, non &#232; detto che sia facilmente accessibile alle navi e alle imbarcazioni. Affinch&#233; una citt&#224; di mare possa intraprendere solide attivit&#224; di commercio, pesca, o altre industrie navali, essa deve avere una baia. Questo &#232; uno specchio d'acqua che d&#224; sul mare o su un lago, protetta in modo da offrire ai natanti un riparo dalle onde e dai venti forti. Anche se molte citt&#224; sono sorte in luoghi gi&#224; dotati di una baia naturale, la maggior parte delle comunit&#224; portuali sono costrette o a migliorare quella esistente o a realizzarne una artificiale per assicurare una sufficiente navigabilit&#224; e accessibilit&#224; anche alle navi di maggiori dimensioni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]El hecho de que una ciudad est&#233; construida en una regi&#243;n costera no garantiza que se pueda acceder a ella por barco. Para que una ciudad portuaria pueda establecer una ruta de comercio estable, pescar o establecer cualquier tipo de industria naval, debe tener un puerto. Un puerto es una masa de agua protegida que se abre hacia el oc&#233;ano o un lago y protege a las naves del oleaje y los vientos. Aunque algunas ciudades costeras se encuentran en zonas en las que existe un puerto natural, la mayor&#237;a de los puertos marinos se ven obligados, bien a mejorar el puerto natural ya existente, bien a construir un puerto artificial para proteger a los barcos y proporcionar canales suficientemente profundos para albergar a buques de gran calado.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PORT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Port[COLOR_REVERT] increases that city's income from trade routes. It increases a city's health from access to [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Clam[COLOR_REVERT], and [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Crab[COLOR_REVERT] resources.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Poultry Farm -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_POULTRY_FARM</Tag>
		<English>Poultry Farm</English>
		<Spanish>Granja Av&#237;cola</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POULTRY_FARM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Poultry Farm[COLOR_REVERT] rears chickens and other poultry for the purpose of providing food.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_POULTRY_FARM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Poultry Farm[COLOR_REVERT] to increase your cities' growth.</English>
		<Spanish>Construye una [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Granja Av&#237;cola[COLOR_REVERT] para incrementar el crecimiento de tus ciudades.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Ranch -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RANCH</Tag>
		<English>Ranch</English>
		<Spanish>Rancho</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RANCH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Ranch[COLOR_REVERT] is an area of landscape, including various structures, given primarily to the practice of ranching, the practice of raising grazing livestock such as cattle or sheep for meat or wool. The word most often applies to livestock-raising operations in the western United States and Canada, though there are ranches in other areas. People who own or operate a ranch are called stockgrowers or ranchers. Ranching is also a method used to raise less common livestock such as elk, American Bison or even ostrich and emu.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RANCH_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Ranch[COLOR_REVERT] to increase your cities' growth.</English>
		<Spanish>Construye un [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Rancho[COLOR_REVERT] para incrementar el crecimiento de tus ciudades.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Slave Market -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET</Tag>
		<English>Slave Market</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Slave Market is the local slave auction block in a city where slaves are displayed prior to sale.  Nearly all ancient civilizations were built on slave labour and slavery existed even in modern times despite attempts to stamp it out.  The slave market was a source of cheap labor and civic pride, as defeated rivals and captured enemies were often displayed for the amusement of the city's citizens prior to begining their labours to build up the very civilizations they opposed.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Slave Market[COLOR_REVERT] provides a 25% production bonus and a +1 happiness bonus in any city it is built in. Allows for the purchase of slaves. Doubles Production for leaders with Organized or Industrius traits.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Stonemasons Workshop -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STONEMASONS_WORKSHOP</Tag>
		<English>Stonemasons Workshop</English>
		<French>Ateliers de Maçonnerie</French>
		<German>Steimetz</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STONEMASONS_WORKSHOP_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Stonemasons Workshop[COLOR_REVERT] to increase the production of your city.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STONEMASONS_WORKSHOP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Tailor Shop -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAILOR_SHOP</Tag>
		<English>Tailor Shop</English>
		<French>Atelier du Tailleur</French>
		<German>Schneidergesch&#228;ft</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAILOR_SHOP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A tailor is a person who makes, repairs, or alters clothing professionally, especially suits and men's clothing.  Although the term dates to the thirteenth century, tailor took on its modern sense in the late eighteenth century, and now refers to makers of men's and women's suits, coats, trousers, and similar garments, usually of wool, linen, or silk.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAILOR_SHOP_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Makes use of "clothing" resources, providing Commerce and Happiness</English>
		<French>Procure une ressource 'Vêtement', fournissant commerce et bonheur</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Town Hall -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWN_HALL</Tag>
		<English>Town Hall</English>
		<French>Hôtel de Ville</French>
		<German>Stadthaus</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWN_HALL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Treadmill Crane -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TREADMILL_CRANE</Tag>
		<English>Treadmill Crane</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TREADMILL_CRANE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A treadwheel crane (magna rola) is a wooden, human powered, hoisting and lowering device. It was primarily used during Roman times and the Middle Ages in the building of castles and cathedrals. The often heavy charge is lifted as the individual inside the treadwheel crane walks. The rope attached to a pulley is turned onto a spindle by the rotation of the wheel thus allowing the device to hoist or lower the affixed pallet.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TREADMILL_CRANE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases production for Buildings.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Utility Fog -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_UTILITY_FOG</Tag>
		<English>Utility Fog</English>
		<French>Brouillard Utile</French>
		<German>Utility-Nebel</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_UTILITY_FOG_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Utility Fog is a collection of tiny robots together performing a certain function. The idea of nanobotic swarms was detailed as early as in 1964 by Stanislaw Lem in the novel The Invincible, and explored in some recent SciFi novels, such as Prey (2002), written by Michael Crichton. When self-replication is taken as an additional feature of such devices, the possibility of losing control of the swarm is the basis of post-apocalyptic scenarios such as the Grey goo.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_UTILITY_FOG_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[SPACE]Utility Fog increases city's production and defense.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Village Hall -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_VILLAGE_HALL</Tag>
		<English>Village Hall</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Salle des Fêtes</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Gemaindehaus</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_VILLAGE_HALL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CITYBUILDINGS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build Village Halls, Town Halls and City Councils to add free specialist in your cities.</English>
		<French>Construisez Salle des fêtes, Hôtel de Ville, Conseil Municipal,... pour ajouter des spécialistes gratuitement dans vos Villes.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Weavers Hut -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WEAVERS_HUT</Tag>
		<English>Weaver's Hut</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Hutte du Tisserand</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Weberh&#252;tte</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WEAVERS_HUT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Weaving, the art of forming a fabric by interlacing at right angles two or more sets of yarn or other material. It is one of the most ancient fundamental arts, as indicated by archaeological evidence. Discoveries in the early 1990s in the Czech Republic point to an origin in the Paleolithic period some 27,000 years ago. Moreover, the earliest literatures often mention the products of the loom. In primitive cultures weaving was practiced mainly by women.[PARAGRAPH:2]Although weaving sprang up independently in different parts of the world and was early known in Europe, its high development there in the Middle Ages was brought about by Eastern influences operating through Muslim and Byzantine channels of culture. Byzantium became a center of silk weaving in the 6th cent. In the 9th cent. Greece, Italy, and Spain became proficient. In Flanders a high degree of skill was attained by the 10th cent., especially in the weaving of wool. Flemish weavers brought to England by William the Conqueror and later by Queen Elizabeth I gave a great impetus to the craft there, and Lancashire became an important center. Tapestry weaving was brought to a high art in France. In colonial America weaving was a household industry allied with agriculture.[PARAGRAPH:2]The 18th-century weaving and spinning inventions marked the transition from the old era of domestic craftsmanship to the tremendous, organized industry of today. The factory system of machine weaving produces quantities of standardized material for mass consumption; the result is a loss of the distinctive elements of quality and design. Some of the finest silks, velvets, table linens, and carpets are still woven on handlooms.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WEAVERS_HUT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Makes use of "clothing" resources, providing Commerce</English>
		<French>Procure une ressource 'Vêtement', fournissant du commerce</French>
		<German>Erzeugt die Ressource "Kleidung", erzeugt Handel</German>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>